<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-exercise-tips</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1902-08-31/ed-1/seq-25/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>1 The latest fad in the line of
T physical culture Is barrel
rolling. Nowadays both men
and women may be found
who daily make It a duty to
exercise for a certain length
of time with a common, everyday barrel.
Corpulent people may now rejoice, for
this latest acquisition to the catalogue of
health and figure improvement methods
has been proven to do everything claimed
for it.
. Thin, sickly people may also join th*
chorus, for it not only reduces flesh with
fleshy individuals, but makes flesh atd
muscle. Improves the breathing apparatus,
invigorates the action of the heart and
brings about a graceful carriage.
All the properties needed consist of ,a
small barrel or keg. The exercise may
be taken in a bedroom, although out of
doors is better. >\
Barrel-rolling, like all other kinds of
exercise, must be taken In regulated!
doses. The man who goes at It like ha
woulJ to a fire will realize little real bene
fit He will derive the greatest who
makes it a business as well as a pleas
ure, begins on a small scale and works up
to his greatest capacity gradually and
naturally. .
The exercises given in the following are
prepared especially for those who are
earnest erough to have a try with this
new method and who will be really con-
scientious in their work.
For the first exercise the barrel Is laid
on the floor on its rolling surface.' The
body should be so arranged that only the
tips of the fingers and the palms of the
hands touch the floor, the greater weight
of the body ing borne by the keg. The
body should then be propelled forward,
the hands being used for that, purpose.
The legs and arms must be kept as rigid
'as possible, and the feet must not be
moved until the barrel, moving naturally
downward, reaches the knee. Now re
verse the movement, pushing backward
with the hands until the barrel is rolled
up to the arms. This exercise should be
repeated several times. It is the most '
important of all for reducing the weight,
although It tends equally with the fol
lowing, others to develop the arms,
broaden the chest and make the abdom
inal muscles flexible.
The second exercise Is practically the
reverse of the.first. Rest with the back
en the cask this time. Place the arms
downward, and rest the heels on the floor
—the heels only, mind; no other part of
the legs. In order to get the barrel in
motion, move the arms alternately as far
forward as possible. The cask will then
reach the heels, the body being raised
from the floor. As before, reverse this
movement and "bring the cask up to the
small of the back, still taking care to
keep the legs stretched out straight.
"While performing this exercise, keep the
lungs well filled, the stomach drawn in
and the chest expanded. When the keg
is up to the part of the back referred to
lift th* arms from the floor and extend
them along the side of the body.* with
open palms on hip. Keep this position as
long 1 as possible without strain.
The third exercise is a pretty one. It
la performed by lying with the left side
of the body, just above the hip, resting
'on the" barrel. If you wonder why, in the
picture, the right hand is upraised, you
will know as soon as you begin the exer
cise. vlt is to balance the body, for the
feet qnly touch the floor. "With your left
hand pull your body forward as far as
possible until the feet can be raised from
the floor. This is not as easy as it looks,
but a little perseverance will manage it.
Then move back to the former position.
.When this exercise has been fairly well
jnnEtered, repeat it. but by lying on the
richt side of the body and holding the
hft hand in the air. This exercise is
liable \to strain the body if it is perse
vered In with too much zeal, and care
should, therefore, be taken to be conser
vative.
The fourth movement consists of lying
with the back on the cask, the arms, at
first, folded. This, while appearing to be
similar to exercise number two, is quite
. rent, for here the feet only are U3ed
to force the body over the barrel until
the latter has reached the shoulders anl
back of the head, when the arms are then
placed at the side, as in the illustration.
As in the second exercise, do not neglect,
while in ■'his position, to keep the stom
ach drawn in and the chest expanded. No
person with a weak back should prac
tice this movement, for the strain upon
the neck is rather severe, and an acci
dent might be attended with unpleasant
consequences.
The fifth is a fine exercise, easy, grace
ful and at the same time beneficial. Stand
straight up, with the feet together, stom
ach in. chest out, shoulders square, and
head back. Place the small barrel first
upon the toes. Bend down and grasp hold
of it. and bring it, not too quickly, up to
the waist line and thence above the head.
Hold it there for a second or two, being
sure that your figure is perfectly
straight. . - - !V ' :.>.
A good method of regulating the breath
ing apparatus, the functions of which are
rather severely drawn upon in this exer
cise, is to count, one, two, three, four,
etc., at each swing-up of the cask, and
inhale air through the nostrils - only at
the even numbers, two, four, six, and so
on. ■■>:. . ' :
The sixth exercise follows naturally
from the fifth. Raise the cask from the
toes to the chin line, still keeping the
body rigid, though the legs may bo
stretched a trifle apart, to preserve the
equilibrium, and swing the barrel to the
right and the left alternately. Follow
the same rules about breathing as in the
preceding movement.
The next exercise, the seventh, is one
which can be done expertly only by the
man who has Indulged in this form of
• barrel-rolling exercise for some time, but
so many parts of the body are brought
Crumbling Skull of
HE famous "Lansing" skull,
T discovered last February in
Kansas, and recently exam
ined by a learned committee
of scientific men, is pro
nounced by them to have
belonged to a man who lived 35,000 years
ago.
This would malce the "Lansing" skull
the oldest relic of prehistoric man on the
American continent, antedating by some
few thousands of years all the other re
mains of human existence on this side of
the Atlantic, and belonging to the same
geo'.ogical period as the oldest relics of
Europe. ,
Although the skull was discovered some
months ago, It was not until quite re
cently that it was fully and scientifically '
described. It was dug from a iiillside of
the Concannon farm, about three miles
from Lansing, Kas., and within a very
few feet of the channel of the Missouri
river. Two men were making an excava
tion for a cave in which to store apples,
when they came across the fragments of
the ekull, loosely imbedded in the soil and
partly disintegrated.
Prof. S. W. Wiiliston, formerly of thß
Kansas state university, but how of the
choir of paleontology ol the Chicago uni-
into play during It that nothing should
be neglected to bring one's salf to the
pitch of necessary ability. Stretch the
legs so that the feet are apart about
twenty-four inches. Then swing the bar
rel down briskly between the legs and
Tiigh up over the head, bending the back
and allowing the knees to bend slightly
forward as the barrel passes under the
body.
Go slowly about this exercise, for It is,
as has been intimated, no small strain
over the whole of the body, and it is not
one to be performed by the weakling. Yet
the weakling can easily get to it by prac
ticing the previous exercises. It is a
matter only of degree. Keep the lungs
partly filled as you exhale, because it la
neceesary to use the thoracic and ab
dominal muscles, for the Improvement of
which this exercise has been partly de
signed.
The cask ls placed In a novel position
for the eighth exercise—as far a? the
body Is concerned. That Is. one must re
cline upon it stretched lengthwise in the
tame direction as the body. Place th?
hands on the floor In front and let the
toes, the tips of which touch the ground,
support your legs.
Now roll from left to right, or the bar
rel from right to left, according to the
way of looking at It. Refrain from be
coming too enthusiastic at this pastime,
or the barrel will slip away from under
you and you may flatten your face
against the surface of the floor or
ground.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045396/1906-06-24/ed-1/seq-25/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>p&E m no better panacea for ills, real I
supposed, than judicious exercise J
' a the open.
I Growing girk and -women living
to'ns or closely confined in city of
.fctt should endeavor to obtain
in the open air aa possible, and to
wmmer sports during their holidaya
'"Wj anemic, undersized, under-wcigiit-,"ou(5
cornea are the ones that most
' wre'.B mapc healing.
Riificient exercise tho Bvstem becomes
' the Utah Boft and flabby, the skin
Tinkled, the muscles lax and easily
iitS D m1,ow" and one's whole being
d it v"n( anbition on account of the
ffiWj laws.
u . f outdoor exercise ib cultivated
f "npoaiblc to give it up. Even in
bil Birls rcul lar8c hnlla for lcn'
U iT muncles wll not become lax and
itg firmness.
OUTDOOR EXERCISE A HABIT
I rcgUrd exercise in the open light
it tlft & game or croquet or walk a
WJiMl are dcad tire(1- noor thj6s
tilt ' Untii tue' Rtir un a Healthy
1 educes vigor and energy by cor-
ka 0r narrow-chested, others have
.-MVt r Slr l P Incasurcinent is deficient
W'tat defects, too, but never
m ; ' 7 be cured, and a splendid mimcular
- -e'
i
development induced by exercise bet fitted ior
individual requirements.
And when the caves begin to turn in tnc au
E artificial beautifies arc no more. Ihe
fcSfhy Sow on check, the sparkle of her eye,
he natural sheen of her locks, her broadened
ehea lar arms and limb, arc the souvenir
of her healthy, natural life in the open.
H around exercise is capital; no one will din
put c that, but it is possible that certain parts
of your anatomy require further development,
thai may be pained by certain forms of exercise
that bring muscles into play. .
For example, swimming develops the rniiFclc
of the chest, arms, limbs, and abdomen, but its
greatest benefit lies in its powcrB of increasing
the circulation through reactionary causes. Row
ing, also brings into active condition both nius-J
cle aud blood.
Tennis is a diversion more likely to bo within
reach of the average city bred girl than any
other, lln's will develop tho muscles of her
arms, particularly the forearm, to a surprising
extent. -But here let nic whisper a note of warn
ing; play with both hands, or the one that wicldi
the racquet will cause the left arm to have th
appearance of being lop-sided.
When a girl is ambidextrous she can keep tho
development of both t-ides equal. And though
it may be tedious and uninteresting for a good
player to start all over again by playing villi tbu
left hand, it is worth all the trouble in the end.
In golf both hauda are used, and the mighty
swings not only stretch the musclcn of the arms,
but the chest and back as well. Add to this tho
benefit of walking over tho links. .
Horseback riding is a most excellent form of
exercise, advised by doctors and physical cultu
rists alike.
It brings into play all the muscles, Fends the
blood thundering through the veins aud assured
ly gives a woman self-confidence, self-control as
Hi'do issues. A couple of months' riding will do,
more -to' develop the bust than a year of massaging-
Your bones will ache and your muscles vnll be
eore,' but cheer up. Any kind of exercise taken
when you are uuaccustdmcd to it will produce
imilar results.
The benefits of walking arc well known. This,
the most common form of exercise, is recommend
ed for fleshy people who wish to part with their
superfluous flesh, but the lean kind need not
worry- When walking is not too strenuously a
plied it is a most excellent all around exercise,
made doubly beneficial when the practice of cor
rect breathing becomes a part of your regime.
Remember that your exercise in the fresh air j ,
will have but little value unless you. take deep 'j ..
vitalizing breaths', filling your lungs to their ca- ' !i
pacity. ! '
BENEFITS OF DEEP BREATHING ' I i
Throw your shoulders back, your chest out, I ' a
j'our abdomen in, your feet close together, so. f ' ,1)
-There you have the proper poise of the body. J j
Keep it, not for a couple of minutes or an hour, j 4
but make it a habit, then it becomes second na- J -jij
turc. Your lungs have an opportunity of being jj ' ? j
filled, your organs are not crowded or cramped, f jj I
your back becomes broad and shapely, your head j j Y'U
assumes a becoming angle and your personality j J fl
nssumca a -new grace and dignity. I iVU
Have all your garments made comfortably loose. V L
No binding of the waist, armholcs or neckband. j j 5
Go without corsets if your figure will permit it, 1 , i
or compromise on the little ribbon girdles. Don't j , u
check your muscles, but give them full play to ! 1a
spread and increase in bulk. ( , j ! fl
Remember to make hay while the sun shines. , V
AIARJORIE. , ft</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1906-11-25/ed-1/seq-34/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXERCISES TO KEEP THE FEET WARM
M"^^ ANY women in winter suffer habitually
from cold feet.
■pets This is not a vulgar slangism, if you
luaßsl I please, but an undesirable physical
condition, known also to men.
Nine times out of ten women so af
flicted hold sedentary positions, where there is
little chance for exercise, and as the average wo
man is too tired at night to walk a dozen squares
after dinner, she goes to bed with cold extremi
ties.
All the inner Roles, woolen hosiery nnd pee
per sprinkled in the bottom of trie shoes will not
 an atom of good, permanently, merely offering
temporary relief.
The only way to effect its cure is to Ect right
down to the seat of the trouble, to improper cir
culation, the bane of ho many women's troubles.
Besides the acute annoyance of having cold feet
this condition indicates that you ore not in good
health, that your constitution has become weak
ened, that your heart is none too strong and that
in consequence tlm circulation is languid.
And what some women would consider the
"unkindest cut of all," i* that a clear, unblem
ished complexion is absolutely impossible with a
sluggish circulation.
The Carriage and Pose of the Hands
MARTINI
B IIK person w*ho carries his hands in front i
of (hi body, or, iiictly speaking, a
V«v;i,i little to the 1. 1,' often flourishing them
fejSjaw) about m though warding oil thiugi
that might come in coutact with them,
"shown in Fig. 8. Hurli a pSfSOD is suspicious j
and critical; he sizes you up from the crown o(
your head to the tip of youi toes; in other words, |
ht take* your measure, lie notices every little
item as regards the setting of ■ room; often has
ths temerity to draw Hni curtains that ar«
placed to shield or hide displeatting ohjeeta. lie
or .lie is searching for information, and we are
efWu want to call them "nosey."
Nothing that fifty doctors can give you will so
materially help you as the following exercises,
which draw tlie blood to the feet and stir up an
all around good circulation.
If you are a chilly, bloodless creature ilon't
pamper yourself and keep close to the fireside.
No mutter how cold the day, j;o out and take an
airing, and walk, walk, miles if you can. Breatne
deeply as you go, holding your breath until you
count 25, then slowly exhale. Throw your
shoulders bad-, chest out, abdomen in; there you
have the correct position. Learn to make cor
rect breathing habitual.
Sleep in a well ventilated room. There is noth
ing worse for your health than a stuffy, ill-venti
lated room in which to sleep. Eat only whole
Another type is tlm individual who approaches
you with fingers twisting about a handkerchief,
the moustache, lapel of coat, a button or more
frequently with the watch chain. (Fig. '■•). In
this we learn that our subject is nervous, and in
a moment may Ity into I state of excitement.
Such a pewou i» nervouh to a great degree, and
difficulty U) ' M" ■riencril in controlling tile emo
tions, since that calm, placid and even temper is
wanting.
In Fig. 10 we see an individual who claspa the
hands in front in a seemingly firm and atoady
manner aa though one hand were resting upon the
other. Those who carrj their hands in this
fashion u» they approach you or when appearing
in public,' where it is more often noticed, mdii
I! ■ R \l.n SI \!>\\ SITPI.I
some food and be sure to include such necessary
things in your diet us fresh fruits, olive oil with
your meals and after them, with grt^s juice whe ■
taken as a tonic, and distilled water.
EXERCISE I.
Place lice's together, toes apart, take a deep
breath. Then raiie heels from the floor as high
us you can. standing on tiptoe. Repeat £he ac
tion witlioir taking hold of any object; and so
continue as long as possible, without making
your muscles too tired,
Do it ten times if you can. Of course, it will
make the muscles of your limbs tired, but it soon
wears off. Increase the nuiuber of times at every
exercise and you will soon get up to 25. .">
i in* manner that they are calm, cool aud
' stlf po»Jtl*"il. and thoroughly believe in their own
i abilities. They carry an air of being perfectly
! couvuraant Wltfa their subject, they dislike hurry,
I Hurry and scurry and will interrupt you when
talking tea ltd ThjM people are rarely ahead
of time in their engagements; they possess the
coinage of their convictions and speak tht'ir nuudn
frankly ; eonsequenth arc often disliked for so do
ing.
In Kig. 1 1 we see the bully. He passe* yon with
his fist* tightly clenched, his elbows bent and a
swagger to all movement, lie loves to chew
plug ami talk light. He Is ths bruisM i Umm is
uven • tougli ring in his intonation. He is often
found dressed in an alleged uniform and wearing
I sure to take deep, full breaths while doing the
exercise.
EXERCISE 11.
Standing in the same position put your weight
on the heels and raise toes. Repeat, breathing
deeply.
EXERCISE 111.
Women who are afflicted with any organic dis
ease, especially heart trouble, should only take
up the following exercise under the supervision j
of a physical culture teacher or doctor.
Take correct position, heels together, toes'
apart, hands on hips. Take a full deep breath.
Now you arc required to do a funny little stunt-
Stnrt on a run, but stand just wnere you ore. J
it big tin badge on hi* burly breast— the type
which disguises hia actual business of "bouncer"
under the title of special "officer." v
To such a person ai in shown i/i Kig. 11 it is
eiceedingly necessary iliut you be firm in what
you suy, for his hragt-n effrontery is as a rule only
backed up with heated atmosphere.
In I'ig. 12 we see a person who rub* his hands
as if cold; au action often noted in the miner of
a im lodraum who wants the best security for hi»
loan and large intercat for the favor. Further,
thia is mining, slippery, hypocritical and
untruthful, aud one whom it 1» impossible to
trust.
| Jn Hg, 18 we see a person who comes towards
lienil you kners far forward, then put left foot
out in front, then right. Repeat exercise without
allowing the herl.« to reneh the floor. Hold the
breath for a second, expel. Continue the motion
Until you fen] tired, rest, and resume it.
EXERCISK IV.
Place both hands over the head, locking the
thumbs together. Take a deep breath, rsieiug
your chest hign, and walk about yoxir room on
tiptoe; hold the breath for a few neconds, eipel,
take another, hold, expel; and bo walk about the
apartment until you are quite tired. Be sure to
keep your arms stretched high above your head.
When it '« possible to do thia exercise during
the day besides morning and night, so much the
better.
EXERCISE V.
Lie on the floor or on a very hard couch; for
in this exercise there must be no yielding under
the body. Take a deep inhalation through the
nose, raising the abdomen as you do so. Then
still holding the breath, force the chest upwards,
letting the abdomen down. Repeat movements,
and exhale through your nose while the chest is
raised. Practice until capable of doing move
ments five times without letting your breath out,
abdomen nnd chest up alternately.
EXERCISE VI.
Here ia another good exercise taken ■'- recum
bent position, lie on the floor, take a deep
breath, raißO the abdomen and feet without bend
ing tbe knees. When they are nearly perpendic
ular, bend knees and move limbs as though mov
you with a lofty bearing, the left hand usually
carried at the tide, fingerb gently cloiing, while
the right hand is carried across the abdomen, the
palm side generally facing upward. This ielU ot
a haughty, stiff and proud nuture, highly inflated
with hii o«a importance. I might add an un
limited amount of self-importance, and either
■tarei or "jumps" at you when addrta»ed jn a fa
miliar term. In order to travel harmoniously
with such a one you must fully* agree'with aim
as to his plan* and idea*. '
1l Fig. 14 wt »ec a person Whose liamls hang
limp and loggy, often heavy, ■ thick and fat in
thape, ait though they had nearly reached life's
journey. With thia aubject all. is heavy, dense,
tag Ihe pedals of n bicycle. Be careful to turn
tile toes up and down an you mnke the revolu
tions. Continue for a minute then rent, Bnd con
tinue agnin, taking full inhalation* while exer
cising.
EXERCISK VH.
Stand erect, take a deep breath. Bend knee of
right limb and try to touch shoulder with it. D<>
thin ten times, breathing, holding breath, and ex
pelling; then take up exercise with left limb.
There is considerable work attached to these
exercises and some may be considered vigorous;
but they will certainly do the work for you if
faithfully followed.
For invalids and elderly people T should advise
having the feet and ankles rubbed and kneaded
with the bare hand, another's hnnds are bent;
they will impart new strength. Press the hands
against the iect ju»t as hard as the patient can
stand, do this for fifteen minutes a short time
before retiring. Just after a hot mustard bath
is good. A good cold cream bein^ used occasion
ally in place of the bare harirlc</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-07-28/ed-1/seq-38/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXERCISE FOR GIRLS
T* I IIERK is no disputing the fact that
girls need exercise as much as boys,
— . and the day has long gone by when
I a frail, delicate, white-faced girl
was regarded as being a model of
femininity.
Girls are no longer afraid of being strong
and ruddy They are beginning to thoroughly
understand that good health is not the pre
rogative of one sex, and that good health can
only Be preserved by exercise.
It is true that all girls cannot exercise as
they should. Some are so situated that ev
ery hour from sunrise to sunset has its duties,
each one confining; others inherit ailments
that prevent walking or running, and a few
perhaps are restrained by false ideas oi
dtcorum from developing their frames by ex
ercise. But the majority remain in a state
of ill health simply because they will not ex
ercise, or do not know how to set about it.
Perhaps many do not know what exercise
really is. A carriage ride is not exercise,
E flUemorable Cruise
CONTINUED FROM PAGE FOCU
island-a mere willow-fringed pih of rocks
scarcely over ten feet in diameter and not
more than fifty feet from the verge of the
fall. But I was saved, and the sudden reliol
Of mind and body was so great that I almost
swooned. The light of moon and stars seem
ed all at once to go out, and 1 sank down
upon the rocks, content only to breathe, be
reft of all power to think or feel.
Of course, the faintness soon passed, and
once more, as I opened my eyes and sat up,
the torture of thinking began.
I could not forget poor Holly, and the de
spairing look in his eyes as he went down
forever haunted m: all through that lonely
night.
What my thoughts and feelings were as 1
sat there, hour after hour, iv my dread isola
tion, would be difficult to tell in words. 1 er
haps I may safely leave them to the readers
imagination. ,
One paramount fear kept me sleepless ana
alert. It was the dread that father mignt
undertake to follow me on a raft, and, less
fortunate than I. miss the island and be car
ried over the fall.
Long before the day dawned the strain ot
this anxiety had become nearly insupportable,
and the incessant roaring of the mad waters
seemed to have started an echo in my brain
that was driving me wild.
How I welcomed the first faint streak of
gray light in the east, though the dawn was
ushered in by a cold breeze blowing up
stream that chilled me in my wet clothing
through and through; but daylight, I thought,
must surely bring me relief in some shape.
So, with chattering teeth, I sat motionless,
with' my eyes fixed on th^ western bank of
the stream, watching and waiting. I knew
the noise of the waters would prevent me
hearing a voice if I were hailed, hence I must
trust to my eyes to discern my rescuers.
I had sat thus for perhaps an hour after
the first peep of day, and the sky in the east
was beginning to take on a tinge of palest
pink, when I was startled by the striking of
some hard substance on the rock beside me.
Turning quickly, I beheld, lyins within two
feet of me, an Indian arrow, tipped with a
spear and winged with bright feathers.
Springing to my feet, I faced about to scan
the opposite shore, and there, standing close
Bits of Nonsense
A joke is never good until it is cracked,
and not always then.
—This life is but a dreary dream,
With troubles and misfits;
And the largest, ripest cherries
Always have the biggest pits.
"Why is it, Emma, you play that piano
selection in such odd time?"
"That's on account -of the measure, papa."
"Oh, you're playing it by measure! I didn't
know but what you might be giving it to us
by the pound."
"What arc you reading, my dear?" asked
a member of a literary society of her daugh
"The autobiagraphy of Thomas Jefferson,
ma." .
"Who wrote it?
—"Why do they call these blackberries?"
asked the small boy of the grocer.
"Because they are black, was the prompt
Then why do they call these other black
ones raspberries?" „
"Because — because — You move on! What
are you lianging around here for, anyhow?"
—The sun glared down in his fiercest style,
The people looked glummer and glummer. '
"Well, no," he remarked, with a leering
smile,
"I will not go away for the summer.
Ig the man with a shady character any
..w.i..r than other folks?
BOYS AND GIRLS MAGAZINE SECTION
neither is housework nor any exacting labor,
no matter how hard it may be. II that were
bo, the blacksmith would be the most long
lived of men; but statistics prove otherwise.
Gymnastics are not always exercise in the
true sense. No pennnncnt good can come of
¦winging clubs or dumb bells in a close
room, unless followed by a brisk walk and
a bath. Croquet is exercise, and lawn tennis
is best of all. But. neither •of these games
is beneficial if played for fashion's sake.
The girl who gets herself up in a "stun
ning" costume and plays for the effect on
the spectators, might as . well be reading a
novel in the parlor. Loose clothing, com
mon sense shoes and an ardent desire to win
tin 1 game, are the requirements for exercise.
Mowing is another capita] exercise for girls,
if they can overcome their natural timidity;
and swimming is better sitll. It is not gen
erally known that girls swim more gracefully
than boys and learn quicker. Both these ex
ercises have an additional value in the fact
'that they may some time preserve life.
Pitching quoits is beneficial exercise, and
trains the eye and hand. • Badminton, a vari
ation of the old game of battledore and shut
tle-cock, is a game which forces all the
muscles of the legs and arms into action,
on the edge of the precipitous embankment,
were three Indians' — big, muscular fellows,
looking down at me in very evident wonder
and curiosity.
As soon as they saw that I perceived them
they began gesticulating and making .signs to
me in an excited way.
The spectacle tent a despairing chill to my
heart. Of course, they were hostiles, 1 (old
myself, for had they not tried to shoot me in
the most cowardly- way, before ] saw them?
I stood stock still and gazed at them.
Presently they drew off together, as if in
consultation, then one of them ran off, out of
sight, only to return in a little while, bearing
a coil of rawhide rope.
To one end of the ropo they tied an oblong
stone weighing three or four pounds. One of
the Indians thjn swung it several times
around his head, and, with a whiz throiMjli
the air, it shot over me and fell in the water
on the opposite side of the island, thus leav
ing a line stretched taut from shore to island.
His next move was to slacken the lin3 and
proceed to fasten the end of it to a tree on
the bank, and while thus occupied, he and his
companions united in making tiigns to me to
do likewise with my end of the rope.
I very soon understood their meaning, and
comprehended something of Uieir plan to gain
possession of me; but, with a child's inbred
terror of the red men of the plains, I felt
that such a rescue would be scarcely prefera
ble to death. So I folded my arms and shook
my head in refusal.
They did not seem to rightly interpret my
attitude and evidently thought they had not
succeeded in making their meaning clear to
me, and their gesticulations became each mo
ment more excited and vehement.
Finally, growing tired of this game of cross
purposes I thought of a way to make them
aware of my sentiment, and, though quakiug
with fear of possible results, I proceeded to
put the plan in execution.
In my pocket I carried a knife— not a lady's
penknife, but a Btout, bone-handled "Barlow,"
such as boys affected a quarter of a century
ago. I drew it forth, and, bending down, de
liberately cut the rope, strand by strand,
while the Indians watched my movements in
a puzzled way. But when 1 caught up the
severed rope and tossed it out into the stream,
their demeanor underwent a sudden and start
ling change, and I saw that my ac,t had en
raged them.
Seizing their bows, thsy began shooting ar
NON-COMMITTAL.
Stranger—" Was you looking for anything?"
Boy— "Ye9."
Stranger— What was.youjooking fovt r
Boy (cauliQutly)—" For what 1 105t.",,
nml puts the players into a glow of pleasura
ble excitement.
Where good roads abound, cycling is an
exercise timt is beneficial, if not carried to
excess. No girl should attempt to ride more
than twenty miles a day: to ride more is re
ducing exercise to work. It is injurious to
try to pee how far or fast you can go in a
given time. Take it moderately and you will
?ever tire of your wheel.
Lastly comes walking, and I think that is
the ben( exercise of all. •It is the simplest
of all exercises, yet there are some rules to
be observed if you would get the greatest
bnefit. The best time to walk is before nine
in the morning or after five in the after
noon. Begin with a mile walk every morn
ing or evening and increase the length until
you can cover ten miles a day?
Walk in the country if possible; if that is
impracticable, choose wide streets, those nneci
with trees preferred. Mind how you walk.
Square your shoulders, expand your chest,
and hold your head high. Keep the mouth
closed when not talking, and breathe through
the nose. Step out easily and firmly, letting
the ball of the foot strike the ground first.
Vary the location of the walk each day if
possible, and exercise the ere and mind as
rows at me. This was the result I had appre
hended, and as the ugly missiles fell around
me, I sprang to the side of the island farthest
from my assailants and dropped into a little
chasm I had previously noticed between two
Kicks, quite close to the spot at which I had
first crawled ashore.
I had hoped to be able to conceal myself
from their view; but, to my dismay, I found
that the aperture was not deep enough, md,
crouch as I might, mv h;ad still protruded
above the surface of the rocks, a conspicuous
target for arrows.
Casting a despairing glance around for some
means of protecing that highly-valued portion
of 'my anatomy, my eyes fell on the old cedar
bucket, htill dangling from the sharp, dead
snag on which it had so opportunely impaled
its-elf.
It was scarcely. three feet from the edge of
the island, and, acting upon what I have ever
insisted upon regarding as an inspiration, I
arose, leaned, far over, resting my weight on
the projecting snag, and dislodged the pail.
Then, springing back into the chasm, I
crouched low and drew the inverted bucket
(\er my head, holding it firmly in place by
the bail.
Up to that moment I had heard no sound
from the Indians, though, during their ani
mated pantomime, I thought I saw their lips
moving and imagined they were trying to
make their voices heard; but nature's counter
tone had rendered the effort futile. Now,
however, shrill and distinct above the roar of
the fall, arose a prolonged yell of strident
laughter, proving, I think, that there is in
the savage breast a sense o.f humor before
which even his anger melts away.
Imprisoned in my wooden helmet, I had no
loophole of observation, and when some min
utes had gone by without further sound or
d?monstration from the enemy, I began to
grow- restless in my cramped position, and,
lifting the bucket a little to peep out, I dis
covered, with surprise and relief, that the
Indians had disappeared.
Aft:>r waiting and watching a while longer,
seeing no sign of them, I finally crept from
my hiding place, and seating myself on the
faithful bucket, with my back toward the fall,
I prepared to divide my attention as impar
tially as possible between the two shores of
the stream, dreading lest either my foes or
my friends should appear and be unseen by
me.
By that time ths sun had risen above the
well as the body. Never let the walk become
a drudgery.
When you return home take a Rponge bath,
a vigorous rubbing, a cool gown, a glass of
milk and a nap. If you do not feel healthy,
happy and wise after a month of this exer
cise, you may be sure that yoii have some
chronic disease.
In summing up, remember that all exer
cise, to be beneficial, must be taken in the
open air. You may amuse yourself over a
billiard table or a game of cards, or you may
have a lovely time in a ball room, but you
cannpt develop your form or add an ounce to
your weight unless you breathe fresh air.
The simplest exercise in the open air will do
you more good than the most elaborate gym
naßtics"in a closed room.
You must also bear \p mind that exercise
must be continuous to be beneficial. Once
you get yourself in good condition, you must
keep there by constant exercise.
Do not look upon this as a task: with in
creaaing strength the exercise will be a posi
tive pleasure, which you will not think of
shirking. You will be proud of your ability,
arid your ambition will grow with your
achievements. Try it for one year, and see
if I am not a true prophet.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1911-12-31/ed-1/seq-21/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Open Air Exercise to Give the Arms Strength and Grace.
T
WIS ft the third of a tcrie$ of practical lenson on health
and grace especially prepared for thia newtpaptr . by
Ui$ Christain Hitler, F. C. ., the famout Englith health
expert.
By F. Christian Miller, F. C. I.
WE EngllKh have an expres
sive little word of three
letters to describe that
state In which we are entirely well.
It la "fit." When we are "fit" we
are equal to anything that may hap
pen. 'Flt" la a cross-cut word to
adequate. .
When we. aie "At" we have an
eaay, comfortable, natural bearing.
' We have an alert mlrrd. Our spirits
are buoyant and that ' buoyancy
speaks in every movement and ges
ture, and particularly in the expres
sion of our faces.
; Now to be lit, what? First we
should begin the day well. A good
: beginning, the right beginning and
', the only beginning, is to take' two
. baths, an inward and an , outward
I one. I am always "fit," and this I
ascribe ln large-part to my lnv
. rlablo habit of the morning inward .
' bath. Aj eoon as I rise in the
I morning I-drink two glaues of
water. Cool, not ice water. If Jce
water Is brought to my-room I ro
1 move the lee before drinking It.
Water should not be too rapidly
drunk. Hotter quaff or sip it than
vulgarly toss it down at a gulp.
The inward bath should always be
followed by a douche. In England
this term means what I have heard
Americana call rplashlng. We take
our plunge bath, the cool or cold
tub, but do not (step out of It imme
diately after as you do here. In
stead, we sit or stand in the tub and
throw handfuls of water over our
neck, shoulders, back and breast.
Then, tingling from the shock of
the cold water, ive step from the
tub and, wrapping ourselves in a
huge bath towel, that is like a sheet
except that it is made of rough
towelling, we thoroughly dry our
uelves. Then we get. into our not too
tlg'ht clothing. It has been said,
and very reasonably, that our cloth
ing should be at least four sizes too
large so that the air can circulate
freely between the clothing and the
skin. The air skin needs ventila
tion. It gets none when we wear
our clothing hermetically tight The
lungs are willing slaves yet they
cannot do all the work of purifying
the blood. If the third lung, the
skin, neglects its duty the body bo
comes snaemlc. It In in nstnge of
starvation, the starvation for fresh
air.
To be "fit"- we must have fresh
air and plenty of It , We cannot
get too much of it, so we must get
as much a we can. Particularly
here where you live in too hot and
steam heated rooms you should fly
for your life to the outer air. And
you should reduce the temperature
of your rooms. .American women
ask me the secret of the fine com
plexions of the Hnglloh women. I
answer, "fresh air and cool rooms."
I believe that the temperature of a
living room should never be above
sixty. In a sleeping chamber it
may well drop ten or twenty degrees
below. I . sleep In a bedroom at
fifty degrees, sometimes forty.
There is much to be said in favor
of sleeping out of doors, if you grad
ually accustom yourself to it Bum
mer i the time to begin, so that the
body will not be too greatly shocked
by the change of surroundings. The
habit of xlinlng on the veranda or
balcony of your home as long as tho
weather will permit is excellent. If
I lived In New York where there are
few yards and many roofs, I should
plcnick a great deal on the roofs,
eating many a simple meal above the
roar of the city streets. This could
be frequently done for six or seven
months of the year, I should say.
And at any time of the year I should
be inclined to go often to the roof
for my deep breathing exercises, for
the air, while colder there, is per
haps 60 per cent purer.
Every woman should allow herself
at least two hours a day out of doors,
one hour in the morning and one in
the afternoon. Or if her circum
stances will only permit one hour a
day, let it be divided into two equal
parts, one In the morning and one
in the afternoon. Try to get your
exercise period Into the sunlit
hours. Walk briskly during the
hours out of doors. Or play briskly
at whatever you are doing. I ap
prove of all out-of-door sports for
women, except hockey. . That Is too
violent
Drink Two Glasses of
Water on 'Rising
Take Two Hours
irv 1 . XI T e f
rresn Jtir uauy
and Lift
Imaginary Pianos
s
Pulling Cork Contracts the Abdoman.
Remember that the weight of the
body must be equally divided be
tween two legs. Don't make the
right leg do the work of both right
and left The legs should be help
meets, not shirks. Hold your body
wo that the weight settles upon the
balls of the feet Keep your knees
straight and walk with a long, free
stride from the hips. Throw the
weight upon the bones and you will
not tire. It is only the muscles that
grow tired.
An indoor exercise that will help
to keep you ''flt" Is the imaginary
motion of lifting a piano, and the
other of drawing a cork from a bot
tle. Hold the bottle between your
knees and pull and pull at the
tightly driven cork. Both of these
contract the muscles of the abdo
men.whlch In most women are flac
cid and fall, giving them a balloony
appearance. Another exercise for
this purpose is to hold the knee
firmly by both hands, drawing It up
on a level with the waist Stand
thus for as long as you can. Then
shift to the other foot and repeat
exercise. This, like the two fore
going exercises, make tho mus
cles of the abdomen firm; form
lng a natural corset and giving
a naturally straight front Also
they reduce the hips.
walking and the exercises I
have described, combined with
deep breathing and the baths I
have mentioned, and plenty of
rest every woman knows how
long she must sleep to awaken
refreshed will keep her beauti
fully "fit"</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-10-25/ed-1/seq-22/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The First Word You can't,
stretch your abdomen hy overeat
ing and expect to remain slender.
An Erighsh, friend of mine said
to me the .other day7 "I wonder
why so many American women
over thirty are stout?"
"Because they eat so much and y
exercise so little," I told her4 j
"Most American men try to let '
their wives and daughters worfc -
as little as possible in the world." j js
"Their wives and daughters '
show it !" he exclaimed.-
How shall I reduce my flesh?</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-07-13/ed-2/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TO BE BEAUTIFUL, PUNCH THE BAG, SAYS THIS -
ATHLETIC STAR
San Francisco, Cal. Grace Patter
son, a lover of outdoor sports, is be
coming an euthusiast over bag
punching. "" --
"I have discovered," said Miss Pat
terson, "that punching the bag is not
only a healthful and enjoyable exer
cise but that it tends to a muscular
uiy -
Miss Grace Patterson.
development that enhances ' a wo
man's beauty. Women with shallow
chests and undeveloped arms could
improve their looks greatly by means
of this exercise. Every woman loves
a round, full neck and a plump,"
smooth chest with the bones well cov--ered
and the hollows filled in witli
hard, firm flesh.
The punching bag will accomplish
this for the most frail person in the
world if she will only exercise con
sistently, being careful not to overdo
it It rounds the arms, giving' those
alluring dimples at the elbows, along
with a good shoulder deevlopment.
Miss Patterson entertains a num
ber of her girl friends in the base
ment of her home and by her re
markable exhibition of skill is win
ning many fair devotees to the sport
of bag punching. In ruffneck sweat
er and 4-ounce gloves she attacks the
bag with a vim that makes its clatter
against the platform sound like volley-firing
in a Mexican battle.
"I wear 4-ounce gloves," she says,
"to protect my hands. Striking with
lighter gloves would, in time, enlarge
the hands, and this, for a lady, you
know, would never do." </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-09-01/ed-1/seq-27/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HERE SHE IS ONE OF NEW PERFECT WOMEN
I
vr-mmlk
'-KSWfK-.
Are you one of the NEW perfect
women? What do you measure -up'
oto the new dimensions of perfect
womanhood?
Here are the feet and inches which
'denote feminine perfection; also
pounds:
r Height 5 feet 4 inches.
Weight 134 pounds.
. . Length of arm 64 inches.
, Chest circumference 32 inches.
., Waist 30 inches.
, Now the question is, how near do
you come to this? The measure
jnents were outlined by the National
Conference For Race Betterment
Wie hi stssaiun m ouii r rauuiscu.
Uss Adele Coffee of this city is one
the first to prove herself a candi-
e for the new-woman perfection.
measurements vary but slightly
those outlined at the confer
ee.
vmTtf nmvrca if vnn Hrm't moaaura nn
SlsSeic 3 a remey. always Trovii;is;
ry6u start with about the right height
r If your chest doesn't measure up to
xzm
'WH
standard, exercise, deep breathing
and gymnastics will do the work.
If your arms are not long enough
the athletic instructor at the "gym"
will tell you how to lengthen them.
If your waist isn't as big as it ought
to be, strengthen and enlarge the
muscles of the abdomen with right
exercise; or if it is too large, the
same process will reduce it
So if you are not as near perfect
as possible, it's no one's fault but
your own.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-09-28/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BETTERS THAN MEDICINE! 1915 BEAUTY
SHOWS. STRETCHING EXERCISE FOR HEALTH
Exercise is "better than medicine. If
one would keep healthy. Better still
exercise brings beauty and grace. It's
the. best sort of tonic to keep the fig
ure from "sagging" or "settling" r
the dread of all women who care
about their appearance.
Exercise that gives the spine and
the abdominal muscles something to
do are best and America's famous
1915 beauty, Kay Laurell, of "Zieg
feld's Follies," is pictured in the ac
companying illustration in one posi
tion of a good stretching exercise.
To do this exercise lay- flat on the
back, and then keepingthe knees stiff
raise the legs to the position shown
in the Illustration. Hold for a count
of five, then lower and relax. Then
-repeat five times taking deep "stom
ach" breaths with the exercise.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87055779/1921-04-13/ed-1/seq-14/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The "One .
Hundred
Per Cent.
Perfect"
Measurements
of Miss
Marie Kuhn.
C1.V i'ou imagine what a shock it mutt haw
Leen to the experts engaged in searching
far a "100 per cent, perfect high school
jirl" to find on who attributed her splendid
figure to houseicork? The Life Extension Insti
tute was looking for a perfect type of school girL
Its experts made a search through the biggestin
stituticv.3 cf secondary education in New York
city. They most carefully applied tape and stethe
tcope to every student who was of athletic lean
ing the lasket ball girl, the hockey girl, the ten
nis girl But they did not find her. Always, when
they were about to shout "eurckal" a calf was to
large, an ankle too "beefy," a waist too stout.
So they turned their efforts to the classroorv,
among girh whoso exercise was largely compul
sory, the girls including even the pedantio among
their number.
And the girl they sought was fownd!
To the astonishment of the delighted "perfect
form" seekers when asked what her principal
form, cf exercise was she eaid:
"Mixing dough, baking, dusting and washing
dishes."
In other words, she was a "home girl who be
, lieved in "helping mother."
Her name is .Van's A. Kuhn, On this pag
' she tells hoic she unconsciously developed the
really 'wonderful physical attributes concerning
" which she is so charmingly modest.
Every American girl should read her narra
tive, particularly the girl who is habituated to
Ccdging housework as irksome, boresome end
ruinous cf white hand and good looks. It may
tei this type of girl to thinking and washing
dishes end it may bring abcut a change of horn
condition that will be beneficial to the girl, help
' ful to the tired but uncomplaining mother and
ccnd:icne to perfect peace in the family circlet
By Marid A. Kuhn
WHEN' I meet a pirl who is pale and dell
cate looking I feel sorry for her. I try
to imagine how I would feel if I looked
(ike that, but, of course, I could not look like that
try well because I have never teen ill.
But I believe that every fcirl who is not strong
rould improve her health and a;.pcarance wonder
fully by merely doing as I do .nd living the way
X live. Mixing dough, cooking cake, dusting and
II : Ä TT U I - I
Help
Shoulder 391rh
Chb'321nche3
---- Bosk 36 inches
Her
-"Waist 27 irxte
Real
at
- Hips 39 inch
-Wrist 6incJ)-
Thh20iinches
Calf 14 in c
Miss Marie
A. Kuhn, tho
"Perfect"
School Girl.
, Ankle' 8 inches
washing dishes are means of obtaining excellent
exercise, just as salubrious as the workout m a
"grym." rienty of the kitchen work and swim
miner is as pood a repimen as I cm recommend.
Every summer I live out of doors. That is to
fay, I spend every day in the open, rain or shine.
I have done this since 1 wa3 a little pirl. so when
I swam the Hudson river, a mile and a half each
Mother With the
work, " Declares Marie Kuhn,
the Perfect Girl Who Attributes
Graceful Form 'to
e Exercise an
Hard
Home.
way, a few years ago, while my friends and fam
ily fretted on shore, it seemed to me to be only
the most natural thin? in the world. To me thero
was nothing remarkable in it. Our summer home
runs down to a, creel: and this runs out into the
Hudson. Every day my two younger sisters ar.d
I so swimming in the creek, and sometimes in the
ludson.
Swimminp is wonderful exercise for a pirl. I
began to swim when only 15 years old. I cannot
remember anyone teaching mo to swim. I thirk
I just learned it naturally, which i3 the best way
after all. Mother bought us a canoe. When wo
tired of Fwimming we do love to paddle Kaater
skill creek.
Basket ball, croquet and tennis are good fun
and exercise, but the very best outdoor exercise
'Mixing
Douh Is
Excellent
Exercise,"
Says the
'Perfect
Girl."
C '
5 t-
' --Vr
1
x
-
fvV.'
;
.t
Newtraper Feature Venire.
I l i v. '-' V .
AUlj BäSlIAöW wyr-z kj- yrzL
Home
. pf
xO. ; . r.v::- .:;.. :"
of all 13 swimming, because it
develops all the muscles, and
makes one exercise one's
brain at the same time.
Now, I shouldn't say that
housework and swimming
alone arr. responsible for my
good health. My summers in
the country include work in
' the field besides. My sisters
and I take caro of the garden,
pick apples and rake hay, and
keep the lawn in good shape.
After we finish with the
housework, we work for a
couple of hours every morn
ing in the garden or on tho
lawn. We have our dinner
at noon, and then, after the
dishes are put away, if we
have any more out-door work
to do, we finish it, and tnen
we are ready to amuse ourselves.
It is only people who are not used to exercise
who do not like farm work because it makes them
tired.
If one is used to using one's muscles in swim
ming or in playing tennis or basket ball, ono
doesn't get tired so easily working in the garden.
Hoeing and rakin and weeding are all good ex
ercise, and it's lota of fun to watch the things
prow. We love it, and so we don't mind it.
Two or three time a week, after supper, wo
walk to tiie village, about a mile away, and some
times besides going there for the mail, we attend
a dance. But mother never permits us to stay up
after 10 o'clock.
Up with the Chickens
I know city glrl3 who haven't been reared as
we were, who could rot do so many things in a
day. They said it made them too tired. But when
one'is used to it, it makes all the difference in the
world.
All the year round we get up at C o cIock, with
the exception of Sundays, when we have an extra
hour cf rest. I know many people complain of
getting up so early, but that is another thing that
doesn't bother one much if one has grown up to iL
I see now that mother was wiso in the way
sh? brought us up, because we are all strong and
we'll.
In the country one doe3 not have to bother
about "dressing up." And it is so much mow
fun not to have to do it. We wear bathing suits.
"Mother Bought Us a Canoe. When We
Tire of Swimming We Do Love to Paddle."
; -j -. v. ' Is- : . -7' v.
.iu- . . ' , ,..'-.'.-.'- i
fc' o- . - " -f ' -.1.. v-'.-r -.'- ;
i -''.Or .... , '. -.1 -, ' . ..
Three of the
"Gym" Exercises
Which Miss Kuhn
Takes When School
Is Open and
the Kitchen Is
Not Available,
fcr instance, of knitted wool
Woolen bathing
wool absorbs the
suits
are best, because the
moiiture mora quickly, and lying in the sun after
a good swim, the circulation is kept up by the heat
from the wool which drys very quickly. We wear
little rubber bathing caps, and sometimes no
stockings at all.
When we are gardening we wear overalls,
which arc much the bert for that kind of work,
and of course we wear large straw hats to keep
the sun rut of our eyts and usually we wear
Encakers and heavy stocking.-3, to protect our feet
end legs from briars and bushes.
Shank's Marc Her Vehicle
During the winter, while going to school, I get
plenty of exercise in the kitchen, in the school
gymnasium, by attending some dances and skat
ing, and of course walking a lot every day. I
think I average Irom four to six miles every day.
My sisters and I never think of taking a car to
do shopping or any other errands we havo to do.
We always walk. It is much more pleasant than
being packed in vile smelling subway trains and
unclean germ-laden trolicy card.
Naturally, a girl docs not get as pleasant ex
ercise during tho season in town that sho would
get in tlv country in summer, but it i3 most Im
portant that every girl should have some kind of
vigorous exercise the year round, particularly In
the open, air.
Boor circulation will make a girl pale and
delicate looking. Lack cf fresh air will make her
lose her appetite. Vigorous exeicise in the open
will stimulate her circulition and give her an ap
petite for good, wholesome food instead of for
tweet tilings and tea and toast. My mother has
alvny.--. been most particular about having U3 eat
pood, wcil-co'.kp.i food, three times a day, with
very few ;veet things.
Ho-.vevcr, I cat a rather light breakfast
never coffee or tea I don't care for either. For
breakfast, I drink milk, and eat some fruit and
perhaps ;;n epp or two. Tr.en I carry my lunch
sc loo:, ann eat a hearty dinner in the evening,
i the country we always have our dinner at noori
id I ihlr.k this is mu?h the better thing to do,
it in to.vn with the long distance to school, it ii
in ir.v c
and
but
:mpo53ii).c.
One thing we do the year round is to sleep
with windows wide open, no matter what the tem
perature may he. Fr?3h air is one of the most
important things to remember if one wishes to
have good health. I never Fit in a closed room if
I can help it. If one is in good health, if one's'
circulation is unimpaired, one doe3 not feel tha
need of such a great amount of steam heat. I
have Leen in homes when the heat was sufficient
to give one a Turkish bath. People who live in
tnat temperature can never be well and strong.
Any nrl. even f eVn io oiii, . i V
r. e v r
come food.
Even if a girl is employed during the day, ahe
can v.-nh: from her werk in the evening, or Bha
can take a walk, or spend an hour or two skatinr
or dancing after the evening meal. She will sleep
til the better for this exercise, and feel much
more rested tho next day. .She should never ahirk
the kitchen.
People who wake up tired are either gufTer
lng from poor circulation or lack of enough frtih
air in their room during the night.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1957-07-30/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>From middle age on fewer
calorie* are required but spe
cial attention should be given
to the qaulity of your food.
The essential, protective foods
are your enthusiastic allies.
More moderate servings, and
well-balanced menus will do
much to prolong the youthful
portion of your life. Simple
foods, prepared with a mini
mum loss of vitamin and min
eral content and appropriate
exercise will give both you
and your figure a lift. You
cannot “get away” with over
indulgence as you could years
ago.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83032307/1903-07-23/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>Exercise for Health.
Many women assert that they get all
the exercise they need in going about
their household duties. Tnat is a great
mistake. A few sets of muscles are
called into activity and the mind at
the same time is fully occupied. For
physical exercise to be helpful, the
mind should be at rest. A walk of
twenty minutes in the open air is most
beneficial, and deep breathing should
oe practiced while walking. A good
plan is to inhale slowly while taking
seven steps and then exhale during
seven more steps.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92067096/1910-10-07/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045366/1904-09-19/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>DR. COOKE'S
HYGIENIC EXERCISE
FOR WOMEN
Muscular exercise is indispensable to
good health but the amount of it that
is required varies with age, habits, em
ploment and constitution. Most women
who are free from organic disease are
greatly benefited by properly directed
exercise. Few muscles are exercised by
those in daily office work, and the
others remain comparatively idle. Ex
ercise under the direction of' a physician
who is a specialist in therapeutic phy
sical culture acts as a restorative both" to
the wearied muscles and to the ex
hausted nervous Bystem of women fa
tigued, or whose systems are run down.
Invalids may profit by such exercise,
and remarkable cures have been directly
attributed to hygienic exercise. No
other method of known treatment is so
effectual as systematic hygienic exercise
under a skillful instructor. In these
days of deficient breathing and excess
ive lung disease, especial attention
should be directed to the strengthening
of the muscles of the chest and abdo
men, increasing the chest measurement
and lung power strengthening the
heart's action, stimulating the circula
tion, not onlv righting the wrongs with
the system but really preventing dis
ease, by putting the system in a condi
tion to ward it off.
Ladies' Evening Classes.
Monday evening, Sept. 26, Dr.
Cooke will form an evening class ior
ladies in hygienic exercise at his private
institute, sixth floor Kasota building.
This class will meet for work every
Monday and Thursday evening for exer
cise, from 7:30 to 9:30. These classes
are very popular and they are rapidly
filled up by lady clerks, bookkeepers,
stenographers, saleswomen and others
whose daily work is so confining and
deleterious to the general health. Aside
from class work, there are those who re
quires special, individual exercise to di
minish or increase the weight, or to meet
some particular requirements, or neces
sity. Those desiring to enter for class
or special evening work should call upon,
or phone Dr. Cooke, 611 Kasota
building, for appointment to arrange for
suitable costume.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86058226/1919-09-13/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015104/1892-02-24/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88067090/1887-09-10/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>The health of women tliat work in
Die fields is generally excellent—and
why? Because of their exercise in
pure, outdoor air. O, that I could im
press on my countrywomen in all the
conditions of life the necessity of mod
erate exercise in the open air! It will
give women clearer thoughts, firmer
principles, more patience, self-reliance
and stability of character. It will give
vigor and freedom to botli mind and
body. Especially would we recom
mend this panacea to the considera
tion of young mothers. Since the
hydropathic system has become fash
ionable we think more attention has
boon paid to the general health of the
body. A prudent diet, outdoor oxer
cise, relaxation and freedom from the
use of strong medicine are tending to
restore strength and vigor to many
shattered constitutions.
lho early entrance into society of
most American girls has iis had effect.
The night is devoted to fashionable
gayeties and the day to
accords with the fast and go-aheada
tive character of our people. The dis
sipated, unsettled state of mind it en
genders, the intense love
meat, the fondness <
certainly disadvaut:
American women
ami live too secluded.
Tlii?
rest.
of ex ci te
if admiration, are
eons.
marry loo early
Many are
scarcely out of school before they' have
settled down as
•ivos and house
keepers. The cares of a
devolving on them before they have
the strength and
family are
nerve to perform
them. One reason tliat our female an
ce-tors lasted longer and had bettor
health was that their minds were not
so much taxed nor the nerves so hi'-h
ly strung. They had tin: full use"of
powers. Their physical health
better, their
a
constitutions
a
a
with I
nervous prostration and general I
failure of iioalil; oi American peopij. j
tlw*ir
wa?
Stronger. Those who had much mental
activity generally Imd sufficient phys
ical exertion
Englishwomen
marry later, and have by nature bet
ter constitutions.
to counterbalance it.
wall; and ride more,
Tho Civil war had much to d
the
Tbs suspense mod anxiety attending It
by the absence and danger of rela
tives, the death in battle and hospital
of soldiers whose wives anti female
relatives were dependent upon
them, the struggle to ran
livelihood by such women. who
were untrained ami unaccustomed to
work, the poverty resulting therefrom,
the loss of property, and the terrible,
soul-harrowing scenes to which many
were subjected produced a severe fail
ure of health in the past and present
generations. It made the Nation par
tially ono of reckless, broken-spirited
men stud of prematurely old, sad anil
invalid women.
, , . ,, ... ,
A lady of foreign birth told me she
thought t marvelous that Americans
have such good forms when they grow
so rapidly, but attributed it to their
restlessness which prevented their
being long in one position, so that any
defect was not likely to become fixed.
Much of the ill health of shop girls 1*
brought on by their standing so long
and constantly.
a
Fashion is so arbitrary Unit often in
miil-wmter the clothing of a lady does
not shield her chest. The searching
blasts of winter are not guarded
against. Most American women in
easy circumstances are. like hot-house
plants, chilled by the fresh, bracing
ui r that is intended to strengthen and
invigorate. Their slightest exposure
to cold or dampness is sure to be fol
lowed bv catarrh. What travclor that
observes the silk hose and single-soled
slioes still worn by some American
women in the rigors of winter.
or the sacrifice to appear
ance ( of comfort in their
clothing, can form a favorable opin*
ion of their judgment and taste, or
be surprised that so many are annual
ty carried off by tliat lingering and in
sidious disease—consumption? Dress
mg so as to injure the health is sui
cidal. 15 c find ns a ge neral thing
that women live longer in Southern
climates. Especially is it so after the
changes incident to middle life are
passed. ... ...
The peculiarities of our institutions,
tiie nature of the people, the mode ol
government, and other circumstances,
have conduced to develop earlier in
life, more fully and more rapidly, the
capabilities of women than in ativ
other country.
Iree air, outdoor exercise, sufficient
light, wholesome food, and frequent
bathing are the best preventives of,
disease. Girls growing up and just
reaching womanhood particularly ;
need them. Light and fresh air, in ■
some case-, prove not only preserva
lives of health, but a restorative to
tlioso out ot licalth. Dark room? and
solitude tend to produce mental as
well as bodily disease.
Someone has said: "Ifcwhoisnot
a physician at thirty is a fool—a phy
sician to his mind as to his body, ac
quainted with his own moral constitu
tion—its disease
diet, its conduct,''— Philadelphia Pres.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86086481/1900-10-28/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92070146/1937-05-10/ed-1/seq-19/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>SWIMMING AN
EXERCISE OF
IMPORTANCE
By ALICE KENYON
Swimming is an art superior to
all others for the promotion and
preservation of health. Why? Be
cause swimming is becoming known
as the best exercise for all pur
poses. It is one of the few sports
which exercises every part of the
body with moderation, yet im
poses no severe strain on any
single muscle. It is 4.he only sport
in which we engage while in a
prone position, for which our bodies
were designed. As a result, all of
the organs of the human body as
sume their correct position while
swimming, thus allowing them to
function naturally.
Knowledge of swimming is es
sential for the protection of the
individual. It has been estimated
that 90 per cent of the deaths oc
curring each year from drowning
could be eliminated if every one
would learn to swim a mere fifty
feet. For the protection of life and
promotion of health and happiness
everyone should learn to swim.
No matter what your physical
make-up, you can be greatly bene
fited by participating in an invig
orating, healthful exercise. The
majority of people require a sport
that is not strenuous but which
develops their physical structure
evenly and beautifully. Swimming,
the universal sport, fulfills every
requirement for healthful and
beautifying recreation.
Active swimmers are developed
proportionately, every muscle has
been built up gradually and uni
formly. The chest is deepened and
the lungs strengthened, thus aid
ing in the clarification of the
blood stream, which is fundamen
tal for a clean, clear complexion
and a bright, alert expression.
Co-ordination, the secret of a
lithe, graceful carriage, is out
standingly apparent in those who
are active swimmers. There is no
sport, especially for women, that
gives more healthful exercise.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90060762/1919-04-03/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-roller-skating-craze</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86089977/1905-04-01/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Rovival of Rollor Skating
Forty or fifty roller skating
rinks have been built and opened
to the public in New England
New Jersey and other states with 1
in the year All are well patron
ized and their promoters believe
that this sport neglected for 20
years will again become popular
In the late 70s and early 80s roll
er skating almost attained the dig
nity of a national amusement No
person was too oldior too young
to use the rinks The hockey
games endurance races and exhi
bitions of fancy skating arranged
bv rink owners attracted big aud
iences for four or five years be
fore the popular appetite was sat
isfied
Then and almost in a moment
roller skating fell into disfavor
Only children clung to it and on
them it has never lost its hold
This sudden loss of popularity
was due simply to the fact that
the pastime was worked to death
for although a good many harsh
charges were made by solemn
moralists against it these never
could have killed it Now it is re
turning as a novelty with another
gene ration of pleasurcscekers to
appeal to but it is improbable
that it will ever regain the glory
it once had The outofdoors
cult has made great progress since
1885 and roller skating is an in
door game</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1905-11-12/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>YOUM ST. LOUIS ON KOLLEE SKATES ENJOYS FAD SO INTENSELY THAT
DANCING AND OTHEE FOEMS OF WINTEE AMUSEMENT AEE NEGLECTED
An Expert in the Art of Gliding on the Little Wheeled Shoes Gives Some Valuable Pointers to Tyros Desirous of Becoming Adept Too Enthusiastic Followers
of the Pastime Compelled by Rules to Take Needed Rest.
CrfA5 FRANKS.
Ar , jIjv VW KbMHdV-.ft?aif?. .- r noil film If- .iiiNSmjK 1
. , WSSLUCfUE CAMPBELL
the roller-Vaunt f.id )n
upo- brlnrlns a Krrat
Fr ii HrwOclvn bridle- to fir Go den
tlate J the hre of the Ore it 1-lke. J
to s- !.i .f thr MIss.;ippt. It rVrry
l"ii w v rn them I, .i h-itl litrip1 enough j
it if r slick nouicti. 'oclfty folk anj
ollf - a tak 11 to whils
N t fiMwr-tlm! hl tht itu;;xrt.
t -iant motor r. although automo
Mii ro r:i!l popular, riot the li.cv.-Ir-
! i arc I'ltis stn.-o out of il.t. nor tin
"bnu ro'iim' n'jr llut3-l to u inatprtal
in I toj n )t rart f th liarn.an nnit
mj, or. In other. orJ. wheel in the
tiwil Non of thetx-.
Tlip litttr h-s tint nuk up thr ma.'or
tart 4-r t' roller U: ni- th ihlni
ta-. 1 ij Too comi'ry haj can" m.il
utrr ro lrr fi.utr. and S' lul 1 In thr
t ror t rank of th Jrotr" to thl latr.t
rjlilcn of an oM fad
TIk ir'ai ho uc-c-,J la thr :mplr
and uralthful pii'im of rl.rr i-kitins
trn rar ai nould Rnd thr nr katr
ai' ditTTent frvci thr old articl' I.U'il
rr k-tr.. tr . li""i IcjtoaJ of ooJn
onr rnj !.! tn-arii.S' Inslrad of pin
xxir rciar tlr infjirn rolKr ikatr
luu r r-rifort!nc and favtnatln;:
O un f.t5 Vatr on l no lonr a
vulrr ph ir in to ftnart Wnt Kad r
Catwnnr tn onr roller Katr. en
St Ij1 hit
t-n-. ITOfe-
flonal. who had brconr rjprrt with th
rollrr. Thry wrr rnsaK'd at b'c talarj
tu h-lp 'mart thr motrment " Datrs with
th hlch-prlcrl performrr r- canrrlrd !
afirr two fk. for thr rrnidrnta of thr
V. Knd rrr a!rrad trampllnc upon
nr .mothrr in th'lr rffcrt to co throact
rr cur. iraainc to ir.r niny r.oot.
WHiAt a thr o-r of costly ttrattlon j
hri all thit tbr popV ftntrd wa an j
i -pro r'ur.lty to i.atT Tft bump nl hrl i
kno-ki t'; fall to t brcir.r.rr Jtdn t '
friiMrn anv of tr-r rol!rr-ttlnt novlc.
horn havr boom o profl
t that trrv arr now cl?tr.l I
Ji qujtr thr pror-r thiu No fad tfct has j ha,dr,j, .
xr comr to St. Lo-x ia cauxht on a j ,..,;,. ln twr ,
haa thl onr j , ,n, fojjn.-i , bt.
So lnttnn la thr tn'.rrt In rojlrr .at- ri-AT TO CAPACITT
nt tJ " inc parti" that naturally j -rt.,r, ar. t0 rlr,k, ,n St 1riul, thl.
CO wtth It. that tr automotl" h almort r.a Arv nxj.1.. ,bo:t : Vatrr It 1
tconi rc3dary It lil iur;ty tak an , r4r. tdrr.1 whan ltrr of thr rlnka
obacurr pUe- a f wwki Utrr. when th- 4ee0 , -rl,y to .jirj,ctr j crjn:r.1
Jrt toB'i and th case ln thr thT ia ,., CTo! trccmr at tlrr. tkat a r
rnotaetrr drops In th vflnlty of tr ' t,J34Cjr 4anounCrr t-i blur urlfom- wnrid
fralr. rotnt. It wtU thn b too cofcd . A c(c m -j,. j, . ju. , ., ,ura t J
to "auto. " waUr thr "ra-hratrd skatlns j ordr thr mm or tr-t wernn. aa IN
rlnka will b- at th p4nc: of thrir .j. ta v.-r rrcm t:vr arrna and clro
!
I th nni
XriuViar ar rouiai i ti,t:r
Iory ! proSt.
Tnciuvand ef St
r.htly th lrt-sr miser tn thrr
!raa3 rUKs. whc ar rcd to rip?
tty whtr.r tt'raln er hiaN a thr M
tcc would ay
Tt rirsr-aU' fcatsrr of It? lr.nTa
Uon 1 thr suns.- tn wafcrfc th tcp .otch
:racst na taken to thr rirt. Out on IV
Bajv.rr avenue ee caa r autcasobi.ea
liatt! up fcr a bXv'a Itr.C " aiot a
raT IMrate kat-.C r-r?le a.- b
comic tr;3tit, and St ta ejta to that
a uc waen the aatcrcotllr part! cu?t
It a !ta areclnr wten. after a ioeg ?
w ti et-usty redr. wtth lt acnpa
imett of rvputy Sheriff asd ht!t; If
halt tta't sada t the rtsk aed aa hor
r two (ttvn to tie rrCrr idi-att-v.
A atwa-iB. aka fctlped. to introduc
rr ptrtru!ar "T tS
:r-rro:
Ftftren nslnut w-lU ?-
HOW TO LEARN ROLLER SKATING.
,
In
allowrd the
wersrn. 6en aftrrn mlr;utr arr allotro
to the rat then Sftrrn ta'r.utra ar civets
to tto want to kate In plr In
th! war the earful rrsacajretsent farcw
ra trpon tfc. who rsav b too n
thu.iatr it thlr loyalty to the port.
and Incidentally h rlrra rrryycnr
chase to kte Is oro ecrcfert
to rraon that I n to thr V riled
rmpt tan evrry yrar ali .. yoorB
nn." l that I don't dancr Tier rr o i
nvasy at te V r that t:ter ceer lack
for rcsM rompr It t different at tk
rak hower Evrrjer. or. h 2 , .a cr:3al fall here and therr brine th
.n to akate and tN trouble J that c3jr treak la what U In all other rpecls
t eerer ksow ten tn quit It fcaa tb ) aa rea picture
aA (Sect tiat roZaws lha rH iaa I Ttm akatcrm so r ta alnlea and d3-
II V AX IIXI'KHT.
' ' ' '" 'earn th art of roller knt-. should, hut r..i fnrr.
tnot 1'jn'i- J- t rollrr knf Th! Is renti:tl.
Af?rr pur. h..!c a pair of flu'e... thr tt.drnt houl 1 fa to a katlr.)t rink
and. after paying hi tdmlsslon. hou'.l Irmi.tli.itrly rMIre to the uriinc
roarai. he-- t- will met a number of ri.unc mn. who will make him fr.l
koi by triic him of thr nrifvo. thry had liTini: tl:- earlv t:iscs of
their rollrr--S..itjni; eduratlon Aftr ' rri-i: th'r tcr!-- thr itu.rnt will
th'nk of brok-n nrrke. arm and suddi i d-ath. Lut h ,houId b fr.arl.-j and
tva-1) to !. catnr If ned be
A -tulTt cm. If hr d!rr. Co on thr rioor r.ra-ins enly thr roller knte
ai.d tu. ordiran raiment, but It l advisable to arrRuatd 3 bit l.v wrapping
j-erral ard- of autorr.ob!l tire around thr waiit and chv. Th adju-t-nent
of an automatic euMon t jlv ron!derrd a cxxl sugcstlon. a th
tudrnt trae not lon- want to lt down. But he may ImoUnMrily it down
whrn hr IrAUt rjrftl I.
No or.r car teach th- tud'nt how to ka on roirr katr. but It I well to
hmr an intruetor for two potent rron One '. that tlsr intructor act
a ort of a pirltual aid Ar.othrr rr.iaor. u th-t thr sntruetor n-ed the
monrj-
Oncr on thr fl.xir. thr tudr.t hnuld re etTth!nc to thr kat !-t
thrm do th wcrk After hr ha fall-n to thr -nor which -UU occur oon aftrr
hr h,. madr hi, nrn e-rld-. hr nhould rir ,:owly anj look around to if
anyon .aw hin fall Kwryonr w-sll har .rn him fall, to br ure. and thr
student houkt not feel chagrined In ordrr to -hrrk thr temper thr f:dent
Jhould rprat oer and oer ataln th. word Kverj bejy work, but father'
The tudent will diorr. aftrr h ha falkn the f.r-t tine, that .lerr.
mlnatlon ha arl'en within him Hr will mrntally reolv- to learn thr nm( or
d'- He will the- mak- arother trtdr. and fall ar.Ia After arislr. and ;:-
line ivuanc ar win rnaar anotr.rr tnIr and fall arain Uy thl tlmr ,. :l
reel aeccitoc.r.j :o itmtt ie wjh airo rrri ,ore. doubtte. but hr hould not
let thl deter Mra Kep r!(ht at It. Kockefeiler ays that hard knocks never '
hurt any mat and he cujh: to know A '
I all No fer of ridicule, however They
have ail b. en In the early stage of the
roller s-rirnce Urmelvea
The ?t !ul, promoter of the skating
rclcr.cr are thinking yeriousty of perleet
lr.c Romr sort of a pnrumatlc protector for
the :afety of brlnnera Jwicli a p-i.tfetor
would nrcesatl!' louk like an e"cagerjtd
t itnpjr of a crlillrcn oiirit If adoptel It
' would undiubte'ly trove a ourcr of profit
J t. f-.e k.itirc rink, for a man r'KRed out
' In thr b sinner" rra-alls would no doubt
. br thr funnlet thin? ever en flti th!"
earth and vrvn.i n ul 1 want to i hits
It 1 e.t!tntril that til l-i than J."1"
I perroni paitltpatr in the new fad In St
4) I Iul -ry night. The matlneaa are pro-
j tr. almost a popular the nlrht -
j ion Student of Hotrrr Hall, thr .r
a , e,t Park Arilcw and l.r Intll - r.rr
ROLLER SKATING AN AID TO HEALTH
ANO BEAUTY, DECLARE DEVOTEES ?
A I dodsi-c thr theater nowaday and lnte.l '
( meander down to the rwa". ti.ere to in-
Ire f trie iat- aou t ,t aenaiionti
Aid rrrreat'vr ;or'j
tnr c if tnax aii
about to.ler kat
Thr r.tnirtr I
I
:i
Why wn tt i T
KTon la talklr. j
havlnr hl harvest, i ?
t ... .-.- .. ...n. .. I. AHa '.
a f XOO. JCfl an ioere mr i-ji.u ikj nun i J
i learn to dsn'r of tl.e.r own a.Tord, bt.t 1
trf'- r teacher. Jut o are there thse t .
Ia a. w. ..a liamatt ala rrt enlla aaUtaawl
! n't , " - "!'.-- " iwiici aaaw-l-- k
t. ... i -Aan--A -v art.,.., attaisM finer I
who en t themlr on roller akat
un'.e ther t omror.r to !lOW thejt hOT
to do It Roller kal!n. Ilkr everything
I ! in th' world. I !wrnd by hrd
J I kr-oek The Inrtnwtor can't keep one
apintiii aid to th beinner and aa b
nee.! th- mor.ey no one blames him.
Sorr.e of the meat prominent oety folk
i I i..'rnir of the nrf of roJIr latins .i 'h
lta!;t r, 1 1'r.uij They .iv thl, with ari'iii eoletinitv Th v itieiri It
I.Ol.'et ,katmg ei tiex -rrv lr (.f III' 1mhI tliry ny. ami better
till. It m C'r Kintl) Tlielr no! Mir Ml.UTirr of hurt bill! or tniril In allal-
ln o tie rtllcr,. nor I thrr .in il.itK'r of Hie lii'rjliig th.it one meeta In
fiutbuii
llo'l. ' rkatlns M.rj .Tj-. l.rl a- the Siitli i.f healtl to the clierk of tti
)omig lmly It iulrken the lilnml nml rimke onr frl "brund new "
llidle' Valine inaketr i, in nr.n-rful While the feet mm onl to be arriitnl
arv 'r tiller katlng tl'r k:ieh lr,m the tlilta; Iti HiH Inntnn.-e. i.evettlielei.
ep rtE trairialn that akntliiK rnIarillj' on the u,II r tenrlie one how to
walk afttr the skate have let taken off
While tl.c danrha'I jromoter look upon the ki'lur link manager aa hi
ar-l. enetnv thr fact l fi.it roller rk.itlna; tn.tke bfter din.er of thoar who
Ir.irn the former art In i.tliir word. kntltig on t tilti tearh onr how lo
ue hi fet
Holl"T "k.itlng taken In niMerat nuantllle. I helpful atnl healthful TI'H
eoui.da like ih Ijiitruase of the tnedlrlne dvertlerm nte Mil It I ttue that
the roller rr-ike the oM fel oun and the youna; tel great
I.lnr all farinatlng jmtlme roller "katlnr nn be mnle 'too much of
good thing ' ICniwIr.g when to fjult la un art to be acquired, ami riereaarlly
ui on would enjoy fully all thr benefit and pleaatite of the Ort
aa
r.ew fml I an aid In
aa44a
I tn st I.oMi are getting up early In th
mortiss to take private Instruction In
the eentlemanly and lady-llke art of roller
dec t know whn J ou've g-5t enough ' J much more arr.tlment and lnplritl9n In .katlng Other have ped the early
Standing octIJ cc of tfcr st. Loite J th roller katr giHr than la th two- Ug of the game and ar no full-
katlns rink thr eoucd of the gliding
rcller frota Ithla remind ore cf thr
rumbUcg of great wate-jfatL Co ir.lie
ard one ee a thousand katera aaillag
two-
tp It i l..i tlrram-. aLv Tc-r 1 t f'ls1 PUei?nt.
... . . ,,.... Skating rink trtU ar th rjle torn.
ia.- wuir. ioo. .-so fuuijej saaiing ' v
rink should t ralnua an orcheitra. The
melody alto help to lean th vbock
over th floor act ce of ttera ersir.R ta j wh,- .omeone U1U head over heel and
exert a air.gl riue The .later iut , i, or!j,a to craxnbl to tt -aide Ilr.e
roll alosg In the even tencr of hi way. ;ar utr
The crowd may roll around for an hour
without a ml ha p. Then of a eudden there
will t-e an awful crab. followed by peal
of laughter, it u aoaneona faUI&c that
rhere are n ght partlea and matin par-
tie The profit of the rink manager
are of great conamueac1. however, and he
can't give up ola apace ln th early vers
ing o all cf th pr.vate gatfcermga are
s'beduted to open at 11 p. m Aa a rule
tny last until J a. tn Th early part of
the everlrg l given to the theater or to
a tour ta the motor can. and wvtwt gen
erally It la the Utter.
There ta ooe naaa In ft. taoat who leaka
upon roller katea aa th rlt'ten of New
Orlean look upon the fever-tnfretlng
moaou.tn He i the owner .ml proprietor
of th Ht IjI iltnr hall Th kalr
hav ilnMi made h'm non t He l
nearly uut of hiilne. Danca ar Infr
quett Everyone who 1 moving hi feet
th-e dar 1 d-lng o on ball bearing
Isatead of dancing parti' It I kllng
pertle. Not ha Tins the power cf Injunc
tion, the dance. hall man ha about re
algr.ed h!mlf lo h'a fate, and only hope
that he may be able ome day to own a
akattnc rtr.k
In the roeatlme th wife promoter of the
rlnka im Browing fat in th dollar,
roll tn. for It et money to get on I he
rink, erefl if nn dent hjow how tt
akate. and lh popularity of th fad It
ever Itvrreaalng Inatead ef b'ng on tk
w ane. 1
Another feature I moon lo be Introduced
that will lend materially to lh luccea of
the tyort. Tk fad ef roller akallac laa't
confine,) tu mer katlng Other Ihlnga
ran l don on th tntrnirtlk floor Home
one hriv-ovri that about every known
lame can be aicompllihed on th toiler a
Poto la on of the moat popular It ta very
like thr polo trnt U played en horae
beck only In iead of being on a horae.
the purer I rr wheel. The roller aelo
plaer 1 thrown a lot more llmea than the
man on horwhock. and the (port. It la
e.d, I ito thrilling aa football, and
lmot a, flangrrnua The roller aoJe
player wear a gull that reeemblea the
gear of a North fole egplorer, only the
guoda ar firmr and heavier. Thr la
bakrt bill ami Indoor t'nnla; too. aaaj
ihe ar to 1- Introduced aa aaon aa the
enthuila. tire of polo.
No on I of the opinion that roller that
Ing ha come to alay. but there lea atreaT
belief that the Ht. Uule eagaewmaut f
lb muni fail playing an Indefinite g
gagetnent. and It to a pretty aafg hat tkM
it anil laat all mm.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025121/1906-02-13/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A Roller Skating Rink
Will Open March
Third,
It has been a long time coming,
many have thought, but it has arrived.
At least the preliminaries havo been
arranged for inaugurating tho "roller
skating craze" in Honolulu,
The Honolulu Skating Ilink Com
pany hag been organized bv a number
of young men. of whom Clifford Kim
ball is the business representative. A
skating boom has been in tho air for
somo timo and this ontcrpriso is its
culmination,
Having taken the Union Feed Co.'s
old warehouse at (jucen and Edinburgh
streets for u rink, tho company
will open it to the public on Saturday
evening, March 3. Lumber is already
on tho ground for tho skating floor. A
supply of skates is on tho wny. They
are or steel with ball bearings in fact
the type of skate in uso on the Coast
and in the roller skating rinks of New
York and Boston. On tho inauka siilo
of the building tho walls are to be
opened up for admitting the cool
breezes. This will make for comfort
in tho exhilarating sport. A lean-to on
tho Waikiki sido will bo fitted up. as a
ftr.injlaf nnrl. aiu uvMrtfofn.. fliAvn a
"Slsofjto be' a jiodnwator booth on the
premises, but ,no spirituous, malt or a
vinous liquor will bo sold. Arc lights
will bo -installed, which will make the
rink always brilliant.
Of course an admission feo will be
charged, as well as a skating feo. The
riuk will be run on a first-class basis,
in ehnrgo of a competent man. It is
believed by the promoters that tho
time for starling bucu a place of amusement
is opportune. For a long period
there has been' a dearth of popular entertainment
other than theatricals and
field Bports.
To tho younger generation of Honolulu
folks up to twenty-five years of
age skating will ba an absolute novelty,
for it is twenty years since tho
previous voguo of that amusement
here. And thero Is undoubtedly a
larger population of tlnW hankering
after that class of diversion, combining"
exorcise with rollicking fun, In Honolulu
now than then.
The craze will bo a pastimo, moreover,
for ninny onlookers of tho large
class who take enjoyment from seeing
others making joyful. At suitable intervals
there will bo masked or fancy
dress carnivals held for tho jollification
of tho town. In the former craze
theso wero highly successful features,
No doubt Bandmaster Bcrgcr will meet
me craze iiuiiwiiy aim uo prepared wmi ijn
special stunts of music for gala</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1906-02-25/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>st of the World, fashionable and
otherwise. CfcJK \u25a0
What greater proof can there be of
the lure of the roller skate when in this
territory, already famous for its skates,
the denizens take to the new kind!
Billy, the laundryman. came to the res
"Some green hand in his establishment
made an awful mlxup and bits of the
Van Slcklen wearing apparel were dis
tributed throughout the community wher©
they would do the most good. The dilapi
dated condition of moat of the articles re
joiced the hearts of the recipients. Bord
well drew a dress shirt and a union suit
which he says he would have been
ashamed to send to a rummage sale.
"Every piece was plainly marked "Van</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1906-04-22/ed-1/seq-36/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CHINESE DIPLOMATS JOKE
TOOK 11111 THREE WEEKS HUTHE
HE HAD HIS FVXAmiiml
Amused the Folk From the Other Legations
Hall at the Holler Rink Jut OnoeThen
Then Ho Set to Work to Learn theGame
Game Made Them Open Their EyesWASHINGTON
WASHINGTON April 21 Persons whobelieve
believe that Chinamen have no sense of funare
are invited to pay attention to this storyWashington
1 Washington has had the roller skatingbug
bug for the past three or four montlmIt
Itis a revival of the roller skating craze ofa
a couple of decades ago ConventionHall
Hall which has been turned into a rollerrink
rink late one of the biggest floor spacesInthe
in the United States and the flooris lackedwith
with skaters of all degrees at each of thethree
three dolly skating stances Many of thetofflest
tomcat people in town men and womenand
and porno of them middle aged personawhorollerskatedbeforemout
who rollerskoud beforemost of the presentgeneration Igenemtlon
generation of roller skaters came into beinggyrate
gyrate around on tho floor of this Washington I
ton rinkThe
The diplomatic hunchIlA Waslilngtonlans
tonlans offhandedly call the legation poopie iplE
pie patronize tho rink during the morningfpssion
session from 10 to 12 noon None of theAmbassadors
Ambassadors or Ministers Plenipotentiarylias
lias yet been seen actually skating but tlwattaches
attaches and the women folk of the legations
tions have fallen for tills sport with a thudand
and they cavort around on tho wheels wljilotho
tho Ambassadors and Ministers look onfrom
from tho berioliosAbout
About a month ago one of the leadingsecretaries
secretaries of the Chinese Embassy accompanied
companied a crowd of the legation peopleto
to the rink at a morning session He is ashort
short rather fat Mongolian with an eversmiling
smiling visage He took a seat with thestaid
staid lookerson and watched the antics ofIhe
the beginners with great apparent amusement
ment A number of the young attaches ofother
other legations begged him to put a pair ofskates
skates on and have a try at the Americansport
sport He shook his head over these suggestions
gestions for a long time but finally heyielded
yieldedWhen
When tho other legation people saw theChinaman
Chinaman being led out on to the floor byone
one of the instructors they all stood byfor
for fun They had the fun The Chinaman
man on skates was a Joke The secretaryexhibited
exhibited all of tho Chinamans natural lookof
of agility as to foot and log work He wabbled
bled like a rundown top and his legs refusedutterly
utterly to support him even when he triedto
to stand perfectly upright and still buthe
he was game and hegavo tho thing a dozentrials
trials Ho fell down every time on severaloccasions
occasions dragging his obviously chagrined
grined and tore instructor with him ThoChinaman
Chinaman fell on every part and portion ofhis
his anatomyHis
His flowing green silk garments wore oftho
tho color of oily mop rags when he finallyhad
had the skates mood from his feet butthroughout
throughout the whole performance thepleasant
pleasant engaging smile never left the
hiCOOKJRt7CZAsSM4NYOlZCHC
eeWlfffG
COOKJrff czwss jywwopraE xesv WWTTO SE CHEW wziMffG CARS iffo
live to make the school a SUCCORS Therewasnt
wasnt any doubt of this in a few weeksThe
The school started with 200 pupils of nilages
ages and wound up the term with 2000Next
Next year it is expected the number willswell
swell to more than 2000Even
Even thorn who wanted to see the experiment
periment made were hardly prepared forsome
some of the things that happened Onenight
night soon after the school was started awhite
white haired colored man came along andput
put his name on the rolls Ho said he wanor
or All they askod him was what classbewanted
wanted to joinI
I want to write my name Bald the oldman
man Im kind of late but Id just liketo
to see how it looksGeorge
George Braxtonthat was his namestraightway
straightway became a member of the firstprimary
primary class Ho has been going everynight
nightWhen
When the closing exercises were heldrecently
recently he was kept busy writing his nameand
and a lot of other words for a circle of admiring
miring friends He was the oldest pupilin
i
Iin that or any other class but there weremany
many whi > had passed 40 Some of thesewere
were colored women who went out scrubbing
bing all day or bent over the ironing boarduntil
until 0 oclock They were there learningto
to read and write tooThere
There were carpenters janitors andwaiters
waiters men who worked hard all dayThey
They sat side by side with colored boys andgirls
girls in their toerwHundreds
Hundreds came however not to loamto
to read or write but to learn how to make
a livelihood They werent asked how muchthoy
they know They were just told to enterwhatever
whatever class they wonted to
Chinamans face If Chinamen ever arehard
hard losers they rarely or never show itThe
The legation people had a great lot of funover
over the clumsy Chinese secretarys thumping
ing falls They pretended to sympathizewith
with him keenly but their winks and grimaces
maces when he wasnt lookin g indicated howmuch
much enjoyment they wore having Whenhe
he had the skates taken off the ChineseSecretary
Secretary of Embassy resumed his benchseat
seat and benevolently watched the restof
of them skate for the remainder of themorning
morning stanceThe
The Chinese secretary appeared at therink
rink at 0 oclock on the following morningsought
sought the proprietor of the rink introduced
duced himself and announced that he wasgoing
going to learn how to roller skate Hewanted
wanted to loam while there was nobodyelse
else on the floor he said and was willingto
to pay for private instruction during theoff
off hours He arranged for private instruction
struction in the art of roller skating from
8 to 10 in the morning 12 to 2 in the afternoon
noon and 5 to 7 in the evening at whichperiods
periods the rink la closed to the publloThe
The proprietor of the rink detailed one ofthe
the Instructors to attend the Chinese pecretary
tary during these hoursWhentbeChlnaman
When the Chinaman turnodup at the rinkon
on the following morning he wore an American
ican sack suit Instead of his Chinese officialrobes
robes He had regular skating shoes onhU
his feet and ho had n pair of brand hewroller
roller skates the finest purchasable formoney
money slung over his arm The wholeImmense
Immense rink floor space belonged to theChinaman
Chinaman and his instructor and they wentat
at It The Chinaman practised roller skating
ing for six hours that day six hours thenext
next day six the day after that and everyday
day for three weeks Ho was as prompt OHthe
the town clock and there wasnt n minuteof
of the entire time that his smile didnt lookto
to be ineradicableOn
On Wednesday morning last the Chinesesecretary
secretary invited his chief the ChineseAmbassador
Ambassador and all of the members otthe
the Chinese official suite to accompany
him to the roller rink for the morningsession
session Whether the secretary let hischief
chief and the others of the legation staffin
in on what was going to come off doesntappear Iappear
appear but the Ambassador from theFlowery
Flowery Kingdom and every member ofhis
his entourage down to the lowliest oopyUtof
of official documents went with the secretaryto
to the rinkAn
An unusually largo diplomatic bunchIncluding
Including a couple ot Ambassadors thirdto
to look on had already assembled at therink Ihands
rink when the Chinese party arrived AHhands
hands gave the Chinamen a great reoebtion
ties and a crowd of the young attachesecretary
or olber legattons got around the Chinesesecretary
secretary and pleaded with him tq put theskates
skates on once more and try the thingagain
again The secretary demurred quite alittle
little but finally ho yielded again thintime
time with more apparent rejuotanco thanwhen
when be had put the skates on the firsttime
time He retired to his Instructors cubby
hole of a room put on his skating shoesand
and his fine pair of roller skates and thenappeared
appeared at the gate to the floor leaning
heavily on the arm of his instructor hisknees
robo knees seeming to snake beneath hiflowuK I
1
I Y
Dressmaking was the most popular Theschool
school started with one dressmaking classand
and finished with six On the night theschool
school closed choruses of exclamationscome
came from these classrooms The coloredpopulation
population of the district had turned outto
to inspect what had been accomplishedand
and gasped at what they saw There werecreations
creations in blue in red in lavender dresseswith
with lace and without lace princess gownsand
and gowns for the ballroom And thecreators
creators stood around giggling at the exclamations
clamations of their friends Some of thepupils
pupils were middle aged women who didwashing
washing lii the daytime but their Joy wasthe
the joy of childrenNext
Next to dressmaking came the millineryclasses
classes In point of popularity There werefive
five of these There were classes for beginners
ginners and advanced classes The crowdsof
of colored visitors that surged throughthese
these rooms saw hats of every kind andshade
shadeSixth
Sixth avenue has nothing to equal someof
of them and Sixth avenue has been ablazewith
with them ever since the school clowdfpr
for thq pupils were allowed to take themhomo
homo iorthofr own adornment or to sellthem
them if they wished The city furnishedall
all the materials and taught the pupils howto
to make tho hat from the frame to the lastpiece
piece of ribbon on itIf
If the joy of those who had turned outthese
these confections so dear to the race thatloves
loves color in Us gaudier forms was great itwas
was nothing to that of the pupils in thecooking
cooking school City Superintendent Maxwell
well happened to visit the cooking class ofthe
the new school soon after it was startedTo
To his surprise he found a lot of able bodied
A titter of acute enjoyment went up
from the crowd of Jogationpeoplo ou thifloor
floor when they saw tho Chinaman witlthe
the skates on again They huddled at oniond
end of the rink to give the Chinaman althe
the room hed neeThey had no intention
tlon of Allowing him to knock them dowiin
in sprawling around anti anyhow thejwanted
wanted to get together so as to erijpy the
fun momThe
The instructor gave the man running
the big orchestrion a signal and the orchestrion
chestrion struck into a swinging Woldteufelwaltz
waltzThen
Then the Chinese secretary and theinstructor
instructor holding each other by the handsand
and facing each other at arms lengthshot
shot into the middle of the floor and beganto
to execute an extremely graceful rollerskating
skating waltz The jaws of the watching
legation people fell and they were struckdumb
dumb at the sight The Chinaman and hisinstructor
instructor waltzed gayly about the immensefloor
floor pace for a few minutes reversing atwill
will and doing all the other position exchanging
changing stunts of the roller waltz w enl
with a mighty shove the instructor puahedtho
tho calm looking secretary into the middleuat
or the floor The legation people huddledtogotherto
togotherto watch he run tlintdlrlnt eventuate
wotchJhe
uate were amaze to note that tho Chinaman
man was spinning all that long distance towhile
tho centro or the sUppery floor on one I5katejWhllo
while he held the other foot up under theshelter
shelter of his robeReaching
Reaching the middle of the floor theChinaman
Chinaman brought the other foot to theground
ground and started to skate curlicues oncult
the toe wheels only ot his skatesas dlmcult
cult a feat as any roller skater ever triesin
Ho got away with It In great shape Thenhe
he dashed forward on one skate wheclddIn
in midcareer still on one skate and propelled
pelled himself backward in a huge circleon
on the one skate winding up by doing amost
most perfect split on the heel wheelsunly
only of his skates All the time the exhlmself
pre slon on llla face was just such a one as
he might have worn with cqualaJmropriate
nllSll while engaged In plokJng wild flowers
Then as a final stunt the CDlnamnn raised
himself to the toe wheels of his skates
began to revolve tfowly to the right and Ineight
eight seconds he was spinning around onthose
those toe wheels like an Indian whip topmaking
making so many revolutions to ihomlnutethat
that Ills features couldnt be dlstjngubuiedglanced
The Chinese Ambassador sitting up on a
high tier bench looked smlllrig and bdppywhile
while the members or his oTclal suiteglanced
glanced at one another and made low
toned gurgling remarksThe
The legation people huddled at the farend
end of the rink and looked chapfallen butwhen
when their nretiomozemont was over theyshowed
showed that they were fair by surrounding
the Chinese secretary and overwhelming
him with congratulationsThe
The Joke Is on us they all told himrather
rather superfluouslyuFor
For the remainder of the morning session
the Chinese secretary skated around thegreat
great rink arena with the prettiest girts of
the legation crowd and taught them how
to do the more simple rolloring stunts
The Chinese secretary hasnt sold a word
to any of the legation people as to how hlgroyereal
reversal of form came about and mostfirst
or thom believe that he fooled them the
first time by pretending not to know how toskate
skate professing to hold It Impossible
for anylKxly to achieve the Chinamansrollerskating
roller skating proficiency In the space of amonth
month They dont know anything about
the Chinamans six bourn of determined
practice a day for a month and they say
that he must have learned roller skating
In Ban Francisco where he WM stationed
before coming here but the facts ore as
bore given</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87093407/1906-09-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LATEST FAD IS THE
ROLLER SKATE TWO STEP
aBATTLE 18 JUST AS SUSY
LEARNING NEW FORMS OF
AMUSEMENT AS ANY CITY—
, THREE RINKS OPERATING
J*TjE- ci t g|g|g|||-TJi|^|-gTgßSMaal*. ll'TaT'l t f laWjasSß 'I"
AND ONE MORE ASSURED.
tVdier skating baa ttrttck the Pa.
• in' itwat and struck It hard, tlred
easSy working out from the -•' it
teaoaaw... It* si) through th* south. !
rrn.stat.-« t 9 i-,iiir,.ntta and then
ssaili il northward. The fad atrurfc
i l**rtsar rebounded t* the iburb
st lawns. entered Washington at
Vaisjonver, atruck Aberdeen a
blow, and ended It* apectacular
■MM In thla city.
lb Seattle tie growth of this I*l
-e«t firm >.r amoaement la dtatlnctly
evident. At first th* younger gen
eration began etrapplng the roilera
on their feet and skating around Ihe
hails mn4 rooma of their bomea.
The* law epi.nlit cement gaßtWalha
and asphalt driveway* fern - tb*
new open-air res* of sport. A rink
was ft.rmally opened and now Heal.,
tie boaata of three flourishing roller
Mia* Maud Coffin Shewing Differ
ent Positions of th* Two-Step.
I
skating amusement place*, and ■
fen Hi I* bring constructed nnd will
he open lo the public by the it I.llls
Of HI. month.
Th* Two-Stop Now
And now the rotlrr-iknte twu.step
hi* "arrived" nnd tt.i. nrw fad I*
raging. Just plain roller skating.
despite lis delirious risk* and i. as.
lUUrntlng danger In life and limb.
It being relegated. To h* up with
the times ..lid in with the »«tin on*
inns' In nt this new Whirl o*l wheels,
lh* |tt> at. tnaddett, wildest Inven
tion of the roller sksllng rrnre.
To ii. -i this new method nf
courting death la the ambition of
all th* tyros, and the bill, he, -pen*"
af ell the link* along th* ...as! si.
crowded with those eager to con
quer 'I,a new d.tme on skates.
Bump*, bruise* and broken headt
count for nothing, and should an tar,
CARMEN REFUSE
tli II 01 II h KBII 1 IT
TO ARBITRATE
I if NnSafl I BlffV I &a
****************
* ' DANK CLEARINGS. *
* Kr, I 1. I'Hlt 1i.32i.0nil *
* h.'.i 1, m0i1,....., 7ll.til.it *
a' ■ *
* Incrrase over i:uin> *
* dale last )*ar...l to:,r.3J II *
• «
..........a*.**.
"I'M.MOT SHOT"
SAID PRESIDENT
OYSTER. HAY. Rent. I.— Wild
minora that President It.ataen It
whs shot, believed to hsve been
rtsrled by curb brokers, sent news
pa|H r mi to Hagamore Hill, raua
tng Ihe country folk! lO Mill. thai
a crura country run was In progress
Tho icoclied, the prealJant'a house
brealhlra* and were Informed by
Ihe president personally that he
had not hern shot. DII "■« 'he
forenoon Mir president -ii.'.. lo Iha
vlllsgt. Thete am no Incident to
give ihe smallest foundation for
such a rumor.
FIRST TO ADOPT
NEW SPELLING
WAHIIINITON. D. C f*ept. Ir—
Th. Army and Navy Itrglster, aeml.
.•ffi. I il, th* fiisi Journal In this city
1., adopt the irfnrtned spelling.
•ays:
It should be adopted throout the
country, tha the purtata do bate
spasms." "■■ -'
perchance, get sllcrd off by an un
tamed wheal a hill ..1..- 1* prune upon
lb* floor of Ihe pen. It I* of no Im-
I portance—a mere Incident to the
main leeue.
Otily Stan**.
At home. In the batementa *nd on
the kitchen ft-., re. th* skater* are
at the task. emittltrig alt' th*
* hitting Illtl* wheel*, trying to
bring them Into lb* pretty but diffl.
cult toot rin.Hie of the roller skate
""deui-tempa." In I'orlland and la.s
Ar.aelea already there *re number*
of expert tao-slep skaters among
the female lel.tsts, the girls, st
a rule, being quicker lo master any
new til. on wheels tbsn the mas
culine element of th* rinks. Now
8. .ill!, wilt time h. , artist*.
Mia* Maud Coffin of Portland,
who posed for hr accompanying
pli lures, la an espert at the deux
temp*, and ha* undertaken to •bow
her i... fortunate staters, through
the ratneru. Just bOW it it dune,
iter* are her direction*:
This It the Way.
"Fir*!, own your own tkatrs, for
no '».. pair of skate* are alike, and
constant changing Interferes with
progress. If you are a rank ama
teur, -. ii n to stand up on your
ek.it.-s iti the kitchen at home, even
li. t"i. venturing Into the slaughter.
p*n, nnd always .-in. Mb to keep
your knee ell h*llt ■■ If the funda
mental rule. Don't undrilake the
two-step until you have mustered
Ihe gild ami Ihe swap </text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1906-11-25/ed-1/seq-35/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>T— ""IHE athletic Winter Girl is bubbling over
with the buoyancy of her spirits.
mjgWfl What's the answer? Guess.
KSECq Another hygienic and beauty-wooing
diversion has been added to her list of
indoor winter sports, — roller skating;
before which throngs of enthusiasts willingly bow.
And mcthiukn that morning tennis and croquet
clubs, which were so fashionable last winter, will
now go a-begging.
This whirling through the air is a most invigo
rating form of exercise, keeping the body in a
good, steady motion (that is, after you have gone
through the preliminary stages of proper balan
cing, when your physical and mental forces some
times woefully desert you).
The exercise brings all the muscles of the body
into play, stretching those the average woman
seldom employs, besides stimulating the blood
into healthy, vitalizing action.
Not one woman in ten takes the proper amount
of exercise; yet she wonders why she easily tire*,
why her complexion is dull and colorless and her
circulation poor and languid. Here's her beauty
balm, packed down and running over.
The benefits of ukating are materially increased
when the fair whirler will make up her mind to
take deep, full breaths, such a* can only be ac
complished when the shoulders are thrown back
and client out, in place of the atingy, little in
halations that utterly ignore the upper portions
of the lungs.
ROLLER SKATING ABROAD.
Heir, then, is au ideal exercise, that will keep
you in good physical trim until the outing season
intervenes. Let me conclude thin overture set
ting forth the manifold benefits of roller skating
by saying that Madame Heavyweight and her
oliiu, aimeinir little sister will i-.ich deiive physi
cal battarOMDt particularly suited to their indi
vidual woe».
We Americans are faddists at best with regard
to our pleasures.
T.OS ANGELES HERALD SUNDAY SUPPLEMENT
We take hold of a new diversion, run it to
death in six months, shelve it and take up an
other. With the present advent of roller skating,
however, it is likely that it will make good for
a considerably longer time.
In foreign capitals, London, Paris, Vienna and
Berlin, roller skating is regarded quite as essen
tial an amusement as theatres and music halls,
and here the rinks are never closed except in
midsummer.
The costuming is usually elaborate, often fanci>
ful, and the scene as a whole, a very picturesque
and interesting spectacle.
.mere is a wide difference between the charac
teristic types of the skaters of the two countries;
the sturdy, blonde-haired (Jerinun fruulein, and
the dninty Parisian, with her perfect coiffure and
chic toilette, are good example* of whut 1 mean.
Fancy dress costumes, bal masques, as Paris
calls them, are frequent occurrences, and many
of these are given, both in private rinks, rented
especially for the occasion, and in the large pub
lic rinks. All manner of fancy skating is intro
duced, and in some cases national dances are
given on roller skates.
In London, while the King, Queen Alexandra
and Princes* Victoria do not actually indulge in
the merry sport, they often occupy a private
box on gali occasions, and saem to thoroughly en
joy the merry spectacle.
Pauline Chase, the original Pink Pajama Uirl,
hat recently introduced a very novel skate dance
in Ixindon that is making a great hit.
But how boon, here in America, are we going
to introduce our foreign cousin*' idea of a carni
val on roller skates? Here's a chance for a wide
awake manager!
<;\KH ACCORDING TO HOUR OK lUY
The Americau girl, as ever, has adopted l>rue
i,,il and becoming attire for this indoor *p«rt
that i.i in perfect taste for the- hour of day or
uight.
For the morning sessions the fair skater is very
simply gowned in a rather severe tailored suit,
with morning skirt of plaited linen or dainty ba
liste, or fine French flannel, both styles being
frequently hand embroidered.
In place of the separate* waist, which is more
practical and comfortable on account of its light
weight, a waist is worn to match the skirt, mak
ing a three-piece suit. The waist may be of the
same material, or of silk trimmed with the cloth,
r more fashionable combination this winter. The
flannel waist referred to is not unpleasantly
heavy, as it is the same quality used for outing
wear in the summer.
White or cream serge skirt worn with lingerie
waist make* v pretty and attractive costume. The
skirt and waist, too, may be kept in the locker
or in care of the wardrobe woman and left there
for a small sum each week.
Roller skating seems to have captivated soci
ety people. Especially in the morning do the
girls make the largest showing, since there is
less to do on the social program, and a string of
automobile* and carriage* is always along the
curb at thia hour of the day.
GAY COSTUMES FOR AFTERNOON AND
EVENING.
Quite a stunning array of gown* is seen in the
afternoon, many of which are typical matinee
toilette*; short skirts, of course. A number of
dressy bodices are worn, white or those in pale
shades, harmonizing with the skirt*. A mlk or
ahiffon blouse will top off a skirt of plain cloth
or figured cloth. Many fetching plaid suits are
worn, and in place of the small turban hats,
larger one* are worn in the afternoon, laden with
flowers, grape* and feather*. The surplice and
fumpar with tfuimpes of lingerie, silk or
shiffon! •'!.■ Mry attractive.
Prime** and piiBMM corselet gowns aie worn
for afternoon and evening, developed in a quan
tity of fashionable materials.
At night the scene presented is brilliant; white,<
pale and brilliant colors are worn, and the gown
ing is often quite elaborate. A favorite style for
evening wear is a silk or velvet Dutch dress
(which is a princess, cut with low neck and
shoulder straps), worn over a frivolous little
guimpe of some sort, chiffon, lace or silk.
A striking model of this description was worn
the other evening; a wine-colored dress, panne
velvet, "with self-colored chiffon guimpe, trimmed
with bands of passementerie and silver buttons
and a large cream felt hat with wine-red plumes
shaded to pink.
Another was of black corduroy, princess corse
let (low) with bretelles of black velvet and baby
Irish crochet waist over pale blue chiffon. The
hat was a "magpie" model, narrow brim of cha
mois-colored felt and crush crown of pale blue vel
vet caught at the side with small black plumes
and rhinestone buckle.
I describe these costumes to show you how
the fittingly well-dressed women choose their rai
ment for hours of the day.
CONFIDENTIAL VIEWS ON THE SIDE.
Since Paris has taken up the no-corset notion, 1 1
see girls experimenting with the fad during the
morning, and undoubtedly the unrestrained exer
cise will do them much good, but the same girls
have small waist* in the evening. Feminine vani
ty is a stronger force than self-preservation.
Girl* who have long, narrow feet should choose
shoes with wide, extended soles, otherwise the
skates will not stay on, and when they slip off
the soles a very nasty fall is sure to follow. For
a 3tt-A shoe, a number 8 pair of skate* is re
* Short »kift| should be worn, those that touch
or nearly 10, are too long aud are likely to throw
you. U y° u have a pair ot bloomers, us
this doe* aw »y wilh e*t«'a skirU, save the | O i,g
„,!,., which makes your effort in skating mv.li
easier aud you fuel several pounds lighter on your
feet.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058246/1906-12-22/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Roller Skating.
The roller skating craze that has
caught every ottior city and town In
the country has Logan thoroughly
within Its grasp. During the past few
weeks the local rink has been crowded
each evening and throughout the day
many beginners may be found taking
instruction. Roller skating Is most
exhilarating and no sensation quite
equals that of gliding through spaco
swiftly on skates. The late roller
combinations makes skating easy even
for novices, and many In this city aic
now Indulging In the pastime as
healthful recreation.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1907-01-27/ed-1/seq-37/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Washington Is In thes the thethroes
t tblda 0 0throes
s throes of a fad which whichbids a lirh lirhbids
W bids fair to outrival outrivalthe
1 e <
f the b4cyel fad of ten tenT tenyears J Jyears
T years igo p Then It Itwas Itwas Itwas
was two wheels to toride toride
io
ride en n Now No with the advent of theroper the thero theroer
ro roer roper er skate It ta eight el < < ht wheels wheelst wMelaaU
t all began with a few tn children childrenhating rhUdrentlng ebildrenskating
hating tlng up ti at aM 4 down the sidewalks sidewalksearly aidewalkSearly Wewalksearlytist
early earlytist Mat fall Finally 1111 high school schoollads 8hoollads schoollads
lads and laaetes tea tried H and found it itHost 1tt108t itMost
t108t Host inviting Then the older broth brothera
4 l era and staler faactnaied by b the theport theII a asport
II sport port took their turn at It and now nowit nowIt t
it has actually actuall come co to the point pointwhere pointwhere r rtaere <
where taere the children cblld of a II larger Jar er growth growthshamelessly Xr growthshantelesety wth p paban1EIEHly
shamelessly declare in accounting for fortheir fortheir iJ iJtheir
their participation in the fan that iliatthe thatthe
4 I the family lamll physician recommended reeotgx + ended It ItSome ItSome II
Some id tde Idea a of the popularity of roller rollerskating rollrkatlrg rollerskating
skating in Washington tan be gained gainedfrom ai ri4 s sS sfrom
from the fact that during durin tb the Ctiriat Ctiriatmas l Chrietmae rilt riltmlUil
S
mae holidays over 1W9 Jii OOI palm of akatps akatpswere akat akatw s swere
were w re Mid The roller akathtg abattn tlnx 6 rink at atConvention atCURYentlon > t J
Convention Mall has a dally attend attendance IlttEndanCf attendante ¬
ante of from 9 9iIIf to 1NU1 lM I people jmopleThere PttOPIfThue peopleThere <
There are ttw cities dta in th the world worldtli worldthat orld k +
tli that t offer the t poaribiHti that Wash Waahingto ash r rInlftM h e eIngt9a
ingto doe doer for roller aiwUng Ubl The ThejnileK TheHell ThenIIes
jnileK nIIes Hell and mites of smooth m oth olean 4 an as asphalt asphalt ¬
phalt afford an outdoor rink rt k that can cannot cannot ¬ gra1 gra1phalt J Jnot
not be surpassed ItU rpU Tbte fact lit at last lastbeing lastJwtng lasthetng <
being appreciated appreciatedhundreds IUI to shwn II by the thehundreds tV tVbundrecls
hundreds of akaters who 00 each pleasant pleasantevening plea ant 44 44evening t teenl
evening eenl < < whirl hlrt glkle 1I1k > e and pirouette up upanJ upand t ° t
and 8 n down the level streets or engage engage1r fna fnaawr
1r 1 Iteree awr batth battles > s of n roll skate sknteTliere te 00 00T1ure nThere >
There was as a tlwe UIo1 when hen Ice abating abatingwax IIktlnlIUI rkatingw
w wax IUI the th princlpa 1 winter Inter sport of ofWaahington8 ofaahllIlon
11 Waahington8 aahllIlon youtg people But for forthe torthe forthe
the past few Ie year there ha has not been beenmore beenmore beenmore
more than several weeks of o this thisshealthful thishealthful 1 1healthful >
healthful outdoor exercise A good goodsubstitute goodsubstitute goodsubstitute 1
substitute has ha at laat been b en found In Inthe 1nthe inthe
the present popular diversion diversionTitere dlver dtverslonThere lun lun111ere
There ta no question as to the bene benefits hen hennts hcnefits ¬
fits derived from this form of exercise exerciseSome exerciseSome t tL
L ° Some doctors are recommending roller rollerskating rotterakatfng i iskating
skating to many of their patients patientsNervous pattentsKervous patientsNervous Ii
Nervous trouble of all kinds rheuma rheumatism rheumaUsm ¬
4 tism and colds contracted from overheated over overheated oerheat8d ¬
heated heat8d houses hous are among the diseases dlseaaeeta diseasesfor diseasestor
ta for which the physicians ystcJaas advise thetoiler the theroller theroller
roller skat skate And whisper hlI r it gent enriv enrivlest nIJ nIJ1Mt 1 1beat
lest the streets be blockaded with withskaters withx k kekattira
x + skaters roU roller r skating ia the tbebe beet t anti antifat antlfJlt antifat <
fat remedy Jfm dy + n the world w rld One hour oa oaa o oa > d
a pair of roller skates Is worth more morethan morea I Jc Jcthan
than all the nostrums oa the market marketfor marketfor
a for the reduction of superfluous tissue tissueKor thlllueFor tissueFor II
For a number of years ears it bus been beenthe beenthe iI
the custom for the th CarinthUn and the theWashington theJ theneehlfRton
J Washington boat cebs ch hbs > bs to give an an an anaual ani
+ ti i hunt Dual dance in Coi Comstlo4 > ttin Hall This Thise Thillf2 Villeyear
f2 year > e r a rkate rkt wl1 w1l VI be heb h llelli In I l placo placoof lato latoof Ie Ieot
of tbe 11 be usual IIn darce darceIt dance ute uteIt
4 It wilt UI lwerawtjsinx be a aiWMttbmg r new to to see lan lancers IAnerll tansere ¬
< sere erll and Cf qua4 tu drUl s being la + lag danced da on onroJler onS
S roller skates BkutesV IIkliLt There kere e la no doubt doubtthl1t doubtthl1tf doubtthl1tCqatlnued that thati t tr5n</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1912-11-24/ed-1/seq-16/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>As one sees children gliding along on
roller skates, coasting down hill and
gaining greater speed as they go, there
is always the Impression that it Is a
dangerous bit of sport. Then one re
members that little folk are bound to
take their chanees and that at the worst
the only consequences of a tumble or
two may be a few bumps and bruises.
But the figures recently given out by
the National Highways Protective So
ciety startle one Into believing that there
Is ample ground for the Impression, and
that the sport Is Just as dangerous as
it looks.
In the ten months of this year In
Greater -New York VK young lives were
sacrificed to the craze for roller skating.
Sometimes the trouble came at the
handa of automobiles or heavy trucks.
and sometimes the boys and girls, going
faster and faster on their down-nm-
coast, fell and that ended It all. For
they gain great speed as they get under
way, and when an accident comes the
blow is pretty heavy, and the little folk
pay the price of their venturesome plea'
sure.
Worth While to Take Care.
Probably those figures are not ap
proached in any other city in the world.
Europe cannot equal them anywhere,
and surely our smaller cities and towns
do not pay so oeariy tor tne cnuaisn
pastime. But it Is worth wnile for
fathers and mothers everywhere to take
care when their little folk Indulge their
fancy for the sport; and if they do not
bar out the level spots they can stand
guard over the graves
A day or so ago when three little tots
were seen speeding and coasting about
on skates that fairly skipped over the
giound. some passersby were heard to
remark that there would be some broken
heads or shattered bones before many
days went by If that racing kept up
much longer. The only reply was "Non
sense," and as no direful reports have
been heard presumably all has gone well
with the loung racers, but tnose ios
deaths In one great cit. Just from roller
skating, make one realize that "Non
sense" Is not all that should be said
Whatever else those figures may em
phasize, there Is the one great crying
need thrt they bring to light the need
of the children for playgrounds where
they can gather together and play to
their hearts' content. Just as nolslli or
as quietly as they like
Infnlr to Children.
Few, very few of our cities, are fair
to the children. They warn them that
they must not do this and they cannot
do that, they must not play ball for fear
of broken windows and they must not
play with roller skates for fear of
broken heads Rightly enough they are
scolded and threatened when they run
ill iruiiL vi ma iu nco j ti uvo vi, .uc .
drivers and run the rlek of something
worse They are told the 're a nuisance
with their shouting, they run staid
pedestrians down with their blcicles,
they give them a shock with their skat
ing, and the street Is no place for their
I i.o. do not. In sufficient numbers, pro
vide big open spaces where there Is no-
tody to "call them down,' and do not
make up for half the "don'ts" that are
uttered. I
Even once in a while we are eon-j
fronted with some great demand that)
we are told is a public necesslti vo
must have this for the sake of the city's
fair name we need that to show that I
we are progressive, and there is some
thing else that Is a common comfort,
and of course that cannot go by the
board
The city wants them, the clt needs
them, and money Is appropriated and
space devoted to the Improvements that
will make the city grow
But the children They want more
playgrounds and the need them too.
for the sake of growing big and strong
and wholesome like the blossoms that
have light, air, and room a plent
The bigger and more crowded the citl.
the greater the need for playgrounds,
but It Is only In the great open country
that there Is no pla -problem at all It
was In a little village this summer that
a party of city folk saw scores of chil
dren playing about In the streets. That.
of Itself, was nothing, for they alwais
will play there But the strangers look
ed about them for the traditional "vil
lage green ' looked for front lards, back
yards, too. and they did not wonder that
the boys and girls flocked out to the
sfreets there was nowhere else to go
The rich folk, the well-to-do folk, the
comfortable even where, do not alwais
think very much about pla) grounds.
Their boys and girls can play In the
open, and can keep off the busy streets,
but of those 10b children killed while
roller skating, most of them skated and
played In the thick of traffic because they
had no play space of their own and no
big place where they could go.
Children do not have to skate, do not
have to romp and shout or play on the
city streets, but nature made them want
and need to, and cities should give them
the space.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84027718/1908-04-02/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>How long the roller skating craze will
continue. .
If there'll be more homo butter for
sale in Canaan and Falls Village, now
that the Mutual Milk aud Cream Com
pany has gone out of business in the
latter place.
The Roller Skate Craze.
The following paragraph from the
Torrington Register will serve in a meas
ure, to show what proportions tho roller
skating fad has assumed: "So general is
the roller skate "craze" throuhout the
country that in spite of hard times the
Union Hardware Co., of Torrington, is
rushed in that department as never be
fore in its history. For the past week
the concern has been running five night
a week overtime, or until 9 o'clock, and
then it cannot keep up with its orders."</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058396/1914-01-10/ed-1/seq-18/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>Tangoing on roller skates Is th
I latest craze to strike America,
i Fresh from Parle, where they be
gan tangoing on rollers a year ago.
It has been received with open arms,
by American society, for it began to
look as though w would have a dull
winter without anything new in the
dancing line.
I ij For several seasons society has
been kept on the move learning the
latest Inventions from Argentine Re
- public and from the Apache dis-
trlcts of Paris. "We grabbed the tur-
j key trt right off the bat and then
I learned tho bunny hug, the tango,
the maxlxe and castle walk with as
J much rapidity as we could. We
whirled along from step to step,
I I astounding more sober folk aDd even
. ' astounding ourselves a little.
j Just a few years ago who would
I HI have dreamed there would be so
' many new daring dances Introduced
I I Into our best society?
H This year started a little dull. Ev-
B erythlng was getting old. Americau
I I hostesses who entertain on a large
I . 1 scale, found themselves facing the
I H height of the social whirl without
I I anything new to do. Then somebody
H came back from Paris and told of
j;!' '!, the wonderful things they were do-
. A lng there. Men of wealth were
iv '( building "Salle de Patinages'' In
i their houses There they could roller
. V J skate and tango as they rolled.
'y- A America was saved. It was only a
few weeks ago since the first tangn
ii ,,'(! roller skating tea was given in New
'Vi,'! York, but in every city of the eoun-
'i'! tvf there are those who are eagerly
2fv following their example. We don't
i-J have Salle de Patinagcs to roller
I tango In. Salle de Pallnages Is a
roller rink In the hnme. It is vastly
gHtP larger than the private ball rooms
r-iJ of the wealthy, so the roller rinks
5fj re being built In basements.
XS Women eager to give their roller
tango parties first are renting tango
JSS rinks and staging the event there.
Tango rollers are this year's hope
sgsfjj of the newly rich They wish to en-
pjgR ter sc-clety, and about the only way
HS to break in is to give something no-
HpH body ever gave before. As soon as
BBpfrsi the Christmas festivities were over
aEfig.' these new rich folks began to plan
fijjj their bombardment of society's
BSroi strong doors. Invitations havo al-
Bffl5i ready been hurled at the topnotch-
ers of tho social realm to see If they
joSSI will not attend the newest of the
Efcflyl new things. It Is still too early to
pgjl, tell how these Invitations will be re-
EEsB ceived.
BH ROIJ.FR rinks
H9 FULL OF TANGOES.
BBS But while the fates of the aspir-
nH; ants for social preferment are eager-
Ng ly waiting the outcome of their ven-
HH tureg, the common folks hare not
IHg hesitated. Go to the roller rinks
WM arid see There they are doing the
hesitation waltz, tho maxlxe, the
HH castle walk and the unadulterated
jH Argentine tango.
Bj Round and round tho floor they
fil go, risking their necks as they exe.
cute the difficult steps while sliding
and rolling. Roller ekatlng In Itself
H' la a difficult feat. Put tango rolling
fl Is something to be proud of. It Ib a
wonderful accomplishment to dash
through the crowd while the orch
tra grinds out the music, tangoing
Hi all the way and still come through
the fracas uninjured.
The learners have gone so far as
to engage teachers to teach them
the newest whirls. Women have
been brought over from Paris
American women who have studied
HI In Paris are giving lessons In the
newest art.
To be the most graceful tangoer
en the floor Is something worth
while, for it is certain to make one
the center of all ces It Is certain
to win applause and favor.
Miss Sybil Henderson, a roller
tango expert, one of the exponents
of the latest frill, insists it makes
one more graceful to tango on roll
ers.
"When you can go over a floor on
roller skates, tangoing as you go.
without bumping into anyone, it is
bound to result In more graceful
carriage." she says. "And for exer
cise, there is nothing to equal it It
Is a wonderful thing for fat women,
for it will reduce the flesh as noth
ing else can.
"If you are looking for excite
ment there is nothing to romparo
with tangoing on rollers. Oh, it is
grand to go whirling round and
round the rink as fast as you can
go. doing nil the difficult steps of
the latest dances. You can do any
of them on rollers. Some steps are
more diffirult than others, but all
are an aid to beauty and all are
exciting to learn. Just try It and
see."
The roller skate craze has struck
Amerlra at arlous times. But
never before have society folk gone
in for it as they have this year. It
is a pleasure for those who don't
mind getting mixed with the com
mon herd Roller rinks were con
sidered too big for the homes of
the rich entertainers, so they con
tented themselves with such small
diversions as whist and dancing.
Roller skating has also invaded
the business world. Speed in get
tine: over a certain stretch of floor
in a business house In carrying par
cels has a distinct advantage.
CHICAGO POSTOFFICE
HAS ROLLER MEN.
Roller skates were added to the
equipment of the Chicago Postof
flco in an attempt at accelerating
the speed of employes in handling
the huge amounts of mail which
will pass through the office.
F. W. Klein and R H. Klokowskl,
two clerks employed In the parcel
post division, were the first to try
the experiment. Their duties force
them to make frequent trips from
one end of the 300-foot basement to
tho other, and It was found that the
roller skates enabled them to make
the trip In less than one-half the
time consumed in walking. Eight
other clerk will don the skates.
In addition to the office employes,
William Soelgmar, a carrier on
Route No. 1. was first to carry a
sack on each shoulder from the
Central Powtoffiee to tho Twenty
second Street Substation, skating
tho entire distance. According to
Postmaster Campbell other mall
carriers will be (equipped with
skates if the experiment, which was
suggested by Fred Holy, foreman of
clerks, is a success.
Roller skates were Invented in
New York as a substitute for Ice
skates for Indoor skating. Deotees
of the sport of skating were trou
bled because the Ice would thaw in
SON, in several poses,
tangoing on roller skates
with a partner.
has to learn over again when skat
ing on rollers.
Ico skating probably originated
In the Scandinavian Peninsula.
From there it was introduced into
England and Germany. in Den
mark it became the means of trans
porting material to market In the
winter. In North America trap
pers learned to use skates when
they were near rivers. Great speed
can be attained on skates. In "Wis
consin in the early lumber camp
days men used to skate from the
camps to tho postofnees to get tho
mall.
Skating in all forms is really a
modern development It reached
Its highest development first in
Norway. It was introduced in Eng
land in 1666 and rapidly spread
over the Island and to America.
ICE SKATERS CAN
MAKE GREAT SPEED.
There are several skaters who
can go a mile in about three min
utes. Any number of skaters can
do a mile In four or five minutes.
Unlike running, skating long dis
tances do not Induce such great
exhaustion.
In skating on ice the feet are
plaoed nt right angles to each
other. The toes are turned out
and the body Is bent slightly for
ward. Then away the skater goes
over the ice raising his feet alter
nately acquiring irreater speed with
every stroke. Beginners In skat
ing either on re or rollers have
the habit of looking at their feet.
That is tho cause of more bumps
than anything else. Tho skater
must look straight ahead and let
his feet take care of themselves.
Tho arm opposite to the striking
leg is swung forward and back
ward as tho skater swings along.
When one wishes to stop suddenly
he digs the heels In the Ice and
arches backward.
When skating on lco wonderful
figures can bo mado. These figures
are a series of circles, spirals, arcs,
serpentines, letters and numerals!
By combining them remarkable
results can be obtained. There
really are oniy four different strokes
used in figure skating. Thev are tho
inside forward, tho outside forwar 1.
the Inside backward and tho out
side backward. That is. the skae
is turned either on Its outside or
inside edge as the skater maks
his way. The variations of theae
four strokes are endless. By a
sudflen turning from one style of
stroke to another, skaters can spell
out names on the Ice.
Many different kinds of skates
have been produced. In Canada
whero skating Is an all-winter sport
there are several skate factories
which turn out skates of all sorts.
Skating In Eastern Canada has been
discouraged in recent years by real
estate men. Formerly there was
an annual Ice carnival at Montreal.
This has been done away with to
a large extent by real estate men
who did not wish it to be advertised
that Canada had cold winters. The
Ice carnivals of Montreal were won
derful events. Long preparation for
them was made.
The ice carnival there was what
the' Mardl Gras was to New Or
leans and similar carnivals were to
other cities of tho country. Crowds
used to go there every winter to
take part in the festivities,
SKATING CLUB
STARTED IX 1830.
In England tho London Skating
Club was organized In 1830. It Is
still In existence and has a large
membership of aristocratic men of
London. In England there are
largo numbers of skating clubs and
there is keen competition in tour
naments all over the Island.
Small rinks for skating have been
established in tho British Isles. Ice
skating rink9 are maintained there
In the summer by building great
refrigeration plants.
Roller skating, however, Is popu
lar in England. It has gained great
popularity tn- tho last few years.
In America roller skating has In
creased in popularity since it was k
first introduced in New York with
the invention of the roller skate.
There have been waves of in
creasing popularity at different
stages. At first the sport was con
sidered too strenuous because It
took more energy to skate on roll
ers than on ice. Roller skates havo
been improved greatly since that
time and run much more easily now
than they used to run.
In skating on rollers the skater
uses a sliding movement in place
of the old-time stroke of the toe
skater.
The Ingenious brains of the Pa
risians' were needed to invent the
tango on rollers. The tango orig
inally came from Argentine Repub-
lc, they say. In Paris they grabbed
it and made it more wild than ever.
When it came to America It soon
found favor with the youth of the
and and spread across the con
tinent as fast as telegraph could de
scribe the antlct, one must go
through In order to tango
Then camo the tango on rollers,
u la a dangerous pastime. Even
n?3 earnest devotees of tho
wild dance admit that. But that
adds zest to the game. It is su
premely beautiful to be able to 4
glide around and around the room
aomg one graceful turn after anoth-
t-r. Rolling skates make the per
former more vigorous than ever. '
The performance has not been
classified. It is & dance and it Is
a sport. When one starts with the
new sport away they go gently at
irst. Then when their blood is
warmed by the excitement of the
yvholo thing, they begin to swing
faster with the music. Round and
round the rink they go. wilder and
Z 7,Crwthey becom a the time,
until the spectators are awed with
the performance.
Often whllo the dancers are at
the height of their movement
there is a spill. One or the other
topples and falls, dragging his part
ner down with him. If the floor Is
clear, there Is no harm done other
tnan the bruises from the fall on
the hard floor. But In the rinks
Tvhero most of thla tangoing on
skates is done, there usually Is a
crowd. When one goes down, sev
eral fall.
But, what of it? That adds to
the excitement and the fun-</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92051126/1905-11-21/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>ROLLER SKATE CRAZE
Sumptuous Revival of fbe
Old Time Indoor
Diversion.
“Well,” gaid one of the old-timers,
“I see the roller skating' craze Is be
ginning to have sumptuous revival here.
About 18S0 was when we had the first
craze here, and It spread throughout
New England like the news that Sum
ter had been fired upon. Everybody
had a. skate on then, and, come to
1 think of it, some of them haven’t tatom
I their rollers off yet. ‘Twilight Skate
Tonight’ used to be the sign that was
| displayed outside of the rinks from
i New Haven to Gardiner, He. Every
j body who wanted exercise went in for
j this amusement. Occasionally private
i parties were wont to engage rinks for
1 the entire evening, no one being pres
j ent but a select crowd of their friends
! "Roller skating hadn't been in very
j long before polo leagues were organ
ized, and upon the glassy floors some
Cast contests took place. The man
agers of the teams put fancy prices
upon their players, just like the base
ball managers do now, and there was
also something doing.
"People got tired of roller polo for
awhile and It died out. Ten years or j
so ago it was revived and lasted for a;
considerable! time. Jimmy Canavan,
the half back, and Billy Aufort were
some of those interested."</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92051397/1907-12-28/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	  	<rel>0</rel>
	  	<text></text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015675/1906-12-16/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>WHOLE COUNTRY
HAS THE FEVER
Roller Skating Craze Expert
encing Its Greatest Revi
val this Winter,
FIVE RINKS ARE BUILT
EVERY EVIDENCE THAT THE
CRAZE HAS GREATER STABILI
TY NOW THAN ORIGINALLY
THE POLO PROSPECTS.
Richmond, according to M. C. Hen-
ly, is not the only city In the United
States where the roller skating craze
has again returned to favor. Mr.
Henley said last night that the de'
mand for skates had been greater this
year than at' any time since the
eighties, when people skated on side
walks, in barns, and almos went so
far as to try it In their own homes. At
the Ilenler skate factory on North
16th street,' a largo force of men Is
now engaged turning out the rollers
and the demand Is greatest for ball
bearing skates. The cheap ones do
not go anymore.
Fine Rinks are Built.
Roller skating now has its greatest
popularity In Pennsylvania, while
other parts of the East are also tak-
ing It up. California and Texas are
getting the fever in a most noticeable
manner. Mr. Henley says that not
withstanding that the skating craze fs
not as general as it w-s twenty-Are
years ago, it has the signs of greater
stability.- Splendid rinks are being
built tin most cities that now hare th
fever, thua Indicating that the mai
agers are satisfied that the form ct
recreation is likely to stay for son
time. . . I
Mr. Henley started In' the skatf
business In 1880 and he has seen thi
"skating disease" in prosperity anl
hard times. It is an amusement i"
which will always be popular wit f
the middle class of people," said Mrj f
Henley last night. "The country has
had a rest from indoor skating for sev 1 I
era! years and it would not surprise l
me to sea them take it up again with
even as mucn iervor as twenty-nve
years ago."</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86090439/1907-02-24/ed-1/seq-20/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>THE roller skating craze w hich I
"struck" this country a years
ago did not die out. but. con- t
trarily, caused hundreds of • n
athletic people to give the spott lasting .
attention. Today the pastime seems; a
even more popular than it was ten. fif- s
teen or twenty years ago. when almost
every one owned and used a pair of the t
wheeled shoes. i
In several cities roller skate races r
have become regular features of each c
week’s sport. Championships and rec-
Srds are coveted as jealously as in run
ning, swimming and ice skating. In
New York city alone five rinks are ,
flourishing.
<
Popular Outdoor Sport. f
In many cities and towns where In
loor rinks are not available the sport i
has to be followed, of course, on the t
rtreets and sidewalks Children play a]i
striking variety of games on roller । |
ikates in addition to using them for
pleasure trips and for going on errands ■
— 11 ’■ ।
DAN J. KELLY, WORLD’S FAST
EST SPRINTER.
Dan J. Kelly, who will race at the
Jamestown (Va.) exposition games, Is
the world’s greatest sprinter. He is
a member of the Multnomah Athletic
club of Oregon and of the team of the
University of Oregon. He holds th
world's records of 9 3-5 seconds for the
100 yards and 21 1-6 seconds fur the
SIU yards.
•
Several song hits enliven the even
■ ing. One is "I've a Very Nasty Tem
i per," which Estelle Wentworth sang
very engagingly. Another is "Have
You Ever Heard It Told That Way Be
। fore?"
• Joseph Miron in an Indian song and I
• as an Indian medicine man was all to
। the wampum.
d
Harrigan Revives “Old Lavender,”
1 ’ Somebody, and I suspect it was Wal
' ter N. Lawrence, has picket up Edward
i‘ Harrigan and given him a hypodermic
1 installment o$ the virus of life. Any
t j way. Harrigan has been coaxed into re-
I vising "Old Lavender” again, and he
The Roller Skating Craze Here and Abroad—fight Talk
Roller skates can, in fact? be put tot
so many uses that it would ia>t surprise J
the writer to see postmen And police
men equipped with them some day to I
expedite them ip their labors. Anyway. |
a great deal of time could thus be
saved.
England, too. has been overrun again
by the roller skaters. These attractive
implements should not. according to
many, have been neglected on account
of the advent of the safety bicycle.
London Has the Craze.
In the city of London so many are
now using roller skates that the public
authorities have had to step in and pass
official resolutions to provide for the
accommodation of these persons.
The London city council has origi
nated the practice of setting aside cer
tain parts of walks, streets and parks
for a period of several hours each day I
for the use of roller skaters.
A part of Southwark park, for tn-1
stance, is reserved for six hours ea' h I
morning for roller skaters, and Fins- I
bury park is in part restricted for them ■
in the same manner.
—
Example For American Cities.
This London innovation gives a valu- !
able suggestion for American town au- I
thorities that are at a loss to provide
facilities for roller skaters. The Lon
don Scheme could be followed advan I
tageously to all concerned. The roller
skaters would be given improved facili
ties for their favorite amusement, and
so they would surely vote to keep in
office the authorities that so benefited |
them.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88056165/1907-03-08/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>Who Said Roller Skates?
The roller skating craze has at
last struck Cottonwood and we are
informed that Stuart Severns and
"Dad" Rooke have rented the up
per floor of the Wolbert hall and
will turn it into a skating rink just
as soon as their supply of skates,
already ordered, can get here.
Grangeville is at present running
two skating rinks and Kamiah and
Stites are each boasting one of the
novelties, so it is believed one will
pay well in Cottonwood besides
furnishing plenty of amusement for
our citizens, both young and old.
Roller skating is said to be a very
fascinating diversion, both for the
skaters and those who derive
amusement from watching the.
many and various attitudes the
"human form divine" can assume
besides the one the Almighty in
tended for it. We predict a heavy
patronage for the new enterprise.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88076086/1910-05-27/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>ROYALTY GETS SKATE CRAZE
King and Queen of Italy Watoh
8katers Perform Quadrille at
the Qulrlnal.
Rome.—The roller skating craze la
in full swing, and recently at the Quirt
nal, In the presence of the king and
queen, Queen Margherita, Princess
Militza and Princess Vera of Montene
gro, a quadrille was performed by
about thirty young people In the large
Sala del Corazzieri. The effect was
charming, as all the young ladles wore
white, with becoming caps edged with
fur. and the men wore the same caps,
with colored sashes worn decoratlon
wise.
Among the performers were Princess
Helen of Servia, Donna Maria Giulia
Moncada, Donna Mariettina Pignatelli,
Signorina Annarella Grazioli, Donna
Vittoria Ruspoli, Don Michelangelo
Caetani, Conte Borsarelli, £arong de
Felice, Conte Suardi and Marchese
C'appelli.
The royal party witnessed the quad
rille, which took place to the strains
of "The Washington Post," from a
raised daiaB at the end of the hall. It
went off without the slightest hitch
under the direction of Marchese Gior
gio Gugllelml. Afterward skating be
came general and, with a brief inter
val devoted to tea, went on gayly until
past seven o'clock.
Among those present, either skaters
or spectators, were Principessa dl
Teano, Contessa Morosinl and her
daughter Donna Morosina Morosinl,
Principessa del Vlvaro, Contessa
Bruschi, Principessa dl Frasso and her
daughter, Donna Sofia Dentice, Princi
pessa dl Sonnlno, Contessa Serristori,
who brought her little boy and girl,
and Principessa di Trabia, whose three
daughters and her son were all on
wheels.
Principe Ludovico Chigi has broken
his leg while indulging in the favorite
pastime. While having a skating les
son in Principessa di Scaletta's villa
he fell heavily, snapping his shinbone
just above the ankle. He was con
veyed home with difficulty in an auto
mobile and will be laid up for some
time.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88076086/1910-03-18/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>Roller-skating Craze.
London.—During the last year this
city has been the center of a roller
skating craze which has developedi
throughout the United Kingdom. The1
enormous amount of $10,000,000, repre
senting 270 companies. Is the amount!
of money invested in this form of rec-i
nation for the last year. The fasci
nation of rlnking Is growing in Scot
land and orders have been given for
the building of many rinks there as
trill as in all parte of the kingdom.</text>
	  </result>
	  <result>
	  	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025020/1907-12-04/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	  	<rel>1</rel>
	  	<text>The roller skating craze has struck Muskogee.</text>
	  </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ping-pong-craze</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1900-12-23/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TABLE TENNIS.
HI'LKS OF TLAY FOR THE NKW INIM>OR
GAME. AI^SO CALLED POMPOM."
Table tennis is the name of a new game which
was introduced in England a short time ago.
and has already become one of the most popu
lar of indoor amusements. It is the came
of lawn tennis in miniature, played on an or
dinary dining table. The net is a tiny one, made
of gauxe stretched between two uprights, which
rest on a bar laid across the table. The balls
are made of the thinnest kind of pyroxyline ma
terial, and are consequently very light. The
racquet has a slender handle and a blade with
a frame about one-half inch thick, which Is cov
ered on both sides with thin drumhead Material.
The play and counting are practically the satn<?
as in lawn tennis, but, according to the rules,
'•the player serving must not put his racquet
over the table nor have it above his wrist." That
is, he must serve underhand and never over
hand, but after service he may hit the ball as he
likes, but he most not volley.
The contact of the light ball with the drum
head racquet produces a pleasant sound, and
because of this sound th(» game received the
name "pompom."
Among the rules for playing the game are the
following:
No faults are allowed: if a fault is served.
that is, the ball does not go over the net or goes
off the table without touching the opposite side
to the server, a |M>int is counted to the non
server.
If the net is touched by the l»all. and the ball
goes over, and otherwise the service is correct,
it is a let. and counU nothing to either side.
If a volley is taken a point is counted against
the person volleying.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1902-01-05/ed-1/seq-26/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE FIRST PING-PONG TOURNAMENT IN LONDON.
It wum held at thy Royal Aquarium In December. 
AN ABSORBING HEW INDOOR GAITS
WHICH HAS ATTAINED GREAT
POPULARITY IN LONDON;
The three men who occupied the studio flat
were having their quiet end-afternoon srnoks
together. There was the artist, w hose hair haj
turned gray after long years of painting an*
black and white doings; the youth who, fcesi
from art school, was just making a start, and
the man of business, who was the saving clause
of the combination. He put up the money wh»3
black and whites would not sell and the youths
checks from home were delayed In the mails.
"I wish people would find something new wia
which to entertain us, ' said the man of buij.
ness, in a bored tone.
"New Year is coming," chirped the youth, aa
obvious statement, setir.g that Christmas «xj
just one day past. "Perhaps Santa Claus tLpgti
off' the dear girls to a new game."
There*! nothing new under the sun. Billy*
said the •Id artist. "If taert was I'd draw it jj
■ hurry."
Then there came a knock on the door, and a
messenger appeared with a dainty note. Billy
grasped it hastily. Billy was in love.
"It's addressed to all of us," he said, with di*.
appointment.
"All the more reason you should hurry up aaj
lead it,"' commanded the man of business.
"It's from Harriet," he murmured, as he read
it to himself.
"Head out loud, uli>.t"" commanded one of the
older men.
" "Won't you ccme up to-morrow night and
play ping-pong." " read Billy. "Now, what is
ping-pong?"
"Search me?" remarked the one who was nut
artistic, except when it came to making money.
"Sounds Chinese," said the artist.
"I've heard of 'pom-pom,' " remarked BiUy.
"That's a sort of big gun which makes a funny
noise." Billy had ence had the idea of beeoininj
a military man. "But ping-pon^r— that's a new
one on me."
"Some new style of bridge. I suppose." mut
tered the artist. "It's not for me. I've sacri
ficed enough on that altar."
"Well. I'm going up to play ping-pong," an
nounced the youth. "I don't care what it is, tit
name's new. Better come along. Jack. You
were growling a minute ago about there being
nothing new, and here you are."
Dilly went to Harriet's and played ping-pong,
and when he had not retumeO by midnight th«
other fellows knew that he was enjoying it. H«
would not tell them what the new game was
when he finally put in an appearance, but ad
vised them to find out for themselves.
An indoor edition of tennis is ping-pong, til*
name coming from the curious sound which tie
parchment rackets give forth when they striis
the little balls. It is played on the dining room
taMe, across the centre of which a low net is
stretched. Th> rules are almost the same as
in tennis, and the points are counted tennis
fashion. There is even mure chance for skilful
handling of the ball than In outduor game*
and there are tricks innumerable which add
interest and variety. Skilful players can ii??
up the volleying process until interest reaches
fever pitch. It is almost as exciting for tie
spectators as for the players, which U core
than can be said of tennis.
It is an absorbing game, as the EngHsh S«l
tell you. It his been played i:i London ilisisj
romis for the last two or three years; but ha
never been strictly in vogue until this winter
The ollieers of the British army carried pir.g
peng sets to South Africa with t'.u-m. and have .
set up their tab) on tho wldt when the Ecea
let them remain Ln camp long enough.
Why the game has not taken hold in tiia '•
country is something which Americans who live
In London cannot understand. They have writ
ten home about the beauties and delisht3 o! v
ping-pong. They laud it to the skies for tie
exercise it affords to busy c.tn who have o
work in offices all day. and to women who **
occupied with a round of teas a^d recepucsi
PING-PONG.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86071197/1902-03-02/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Everybody as Is Anybody Plays Ping
Pong Directions for Playing
Jlf you would be the proper thing
With progress keep along
Do you ping pong
Shakespeare
4amtnai G4 S
b then I rede ye learn to pips
And also learn to poug
VVell well well go and pine pongl
Xhe only reason that ping pong Is not
ntentloned In Shakespeare Is probably
wjug to tho fact that the game was jot
Invented In Shakiispeares time Toor
lng pong li lawn tenuis little brother
f
Bi Is the latest little International baby
Sthjt has found Its way Into the lap of so
fclety If you belonged to the hoi pollol
faiijl wero quartered n Londons White
Sfchjpel or New Yorks tendetloln and
fnappeiicd to be a champon ping pouger
utho doors of tho most eNCluslve society of
Jboth cities would swing open to aduit yon
Fqr ping pong Is strictly the thing and
Jytha Hkllleil player U at present It
Being little It Is played Indoors and
ujbecausjc of the moving about which It
Permits It Is rapidly superseding euchro
< hlgh Uvb and bridge whist as a means of
jrepreatlon and entcitalnmcnt In the games
rjut mentioned one must sit In one position
throughout the tedious cveuing llng pong
isKillfferent In ping pong one must t > tlr
constantly
tiding pong Is usually played on a dining
jtable with a specially piepured celluloid
ball Instead of the India rubber one iw
Jnglawn teunls It requires some little
praetIco before the proper strength Is at
jitalped with which to strike tho ball but
tea minutes or so Is suflielont as a rule
rtoinabIc the plajcrs to keep the ball within
fch space of the table top The ping pong
foil does not fly easllv
mA dining tablo about seven feet to nine
feet long by half the width without a
idoth is thp best place to play the giie
toj and when the room Is lighted from
febtvo tho table by a chandelier tho tnbf
M uld be moved a little to the sldo of tha
lrm
PWThe height of the net can be varied from
Jcp inches to Ave Inches the lower It Is
stftpa more difficult the strokes can be made
ito return
iKThe racquets are Tellum covered bats of
I
Thc Home of the Patrician
Patrician
Shoes for Women
350
kn Eloquent Tribute
Is on the lips of every woman yho
has worn the Patrician They
are a 20thcentury product in every
particular of style workmanship
and service and their fitting quali
ties are little short of marvelous
atrician
SHOES
re made from the choicest and
nost fashionable Icatiers hey aie
modeled by artists and aie put to
feci her by expert craftsmen Ex
cept onal facilities and an imme se
Jotiput enable us to sell the
Patrician at
ISole Acency
the kind that used to be known as battle
dores
Warming tho battledores slightly before
tho tiro will lmptovo their elasticity but
caic must be taken not to overheat them
When wlogs are used wlb the net these
should bo died up on the posts so that
they project out beyond the edge Of the
table aaid thus prevent n ball being re
turned tound the sides of the posts Instead
of over the net
1 The game Is for two players They
shall stand one at each end of the tabic
The plajer who lirst delivers tho ball shal
i > e called tho server and the other the
sttikorout
2 At the end of tie first game tho
strlkorout shall become tho server and the
sirvei shall become the strikerout una
so on alternately
a The service shall bo strictly under
hand und delivered from beyond tha end
of the table
4 The ball served must drop anywhere
ou the table top beyond the net and Is then
In play If It drops Into the net or off the
tabie It counts to the striker out There is
no second son lie as In lawn tennis
0 In fretting It Is a let If the ball touch
the net lu parsing over
0 If the ball in play htrllscg any obiect
above or around the table beloro it bounces
on tho table top Itself net or post except
ed It counts against the player
7 The berver wins a stioku If the strlker
out fulls to return the service or return
the service or ball In play off the table
b The strikerout wins n stroke If the
server bcrve a fault or falls to return the
ball In play or return the ball In play so
that It falls off the table
0 No volleyllng Is allowed hut as long
as the ball touches the table top It Is In
play aud can be taken at half volley
10 On either player winning his rtrst
stroke the score is called 15 for that
plajer on either player winning his sec
ond stroke the score Is called SO for that
player on either plajer winning his third
stroke the score is called 40 for that play
er and tha toiuth stroke won by either
player Is scoied game for that player ex
es pt as below
11 If both players have w n three
stiokes 40 all the score Is called deuce
snd the next stroke won by either player is
scored advantage to thit player If tho
same player wl the nest stroke he win
the game If hi loses the next stroke the
store is again called deuce and so on
until either player wins the two strokes lm
mediately following the score of deuce
when the game is scored for that player
12 The player who flist wins six games
wins a set
13 The game may nlso be scored by
points twentytwo up The players lu this
cn e change the service aucr every tive
points scoied like overs at cricket
The apparatus of the game costs about
260 i
A pingpong dance In which the women
wear pingpong patches and powdeted hair
Is the latest development of the present
mania Tho women carrying white balls
with a red number on each and each gen
tleman a scarlet ball with a corresponding
fluro in white walk down the ball room
and meet at a silken net Batting begins
Af soon as each dancer secures the ball the
numbers are called out pairing oft begins
and the couples glide down the room hand
in hand in minuet style The latest rival
of pingpong bv the wnv Is table bowls
which has Just been exhibited at the Alex
andra palace</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1902-04-06/ed-1/seq-23/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>From present indications society will
no longer be divided upon the lines of
birth, l)i ceding or wealth, but the quail-
Jiciition for membership in the innermost
circle will )m- ability to play "ping pong,"
that fascinating parlor game that has
recently come over the seas to us from
aristocratic London.
Age. sex. color or previous condition
inaki no difference with the devotees of
the game and in England duchesses have
been known to struggle for the honor of
having a champion ping pong player from
some suburb at their receptions. Success
ful authors, artists and actors are no
longer being: lionized and made to roar
for the benefit of society. Their place ,s
but secondary now to the man who can
make the highest score with the bellum
covered racquet* and the celluloid balls.
The craze has but just struck the West,
although in New York, and. in fact, in
all of the Eastern cities, it is raging al
most as widely as it does in England.
The dealers say they are unable to keep
up with the demand for the game and
that thousands of sets have been sold,
v.ith the demand still increasing. "Pins
pong" parties are taking the place of
bridge whist and cinch contests and even
of bowline tournaments. No longer does
the Western swain sit contentedly in the
parlor with the girl of his heart, discuss
ing the weather undisturbed by the other
members of the family. Now the parlor
is in use. Father and mother and the
neighbors are "serving" and "returning"'
and calling love 15, love 30, deuce ad
vantage, etc.
i'iiiK pong is Bimply modified tennis
played upon a ta-ble in the houft« instead
of a court in the open air and is, in fact,
table tennis. Bui when the little celluloid
ball strikes the hard surface of a table
the contact prodapes a sound best
d< scribed by the word "ping" and as it
bounds against the viium racquet the
Bound "pong," a full note lower, issues.
Some person with a quick ear and a
quicker imagination translated these
sounds and the gamfe was christened with
the catchy name "ping pong," a name
tnat has helped to call attention to it.
The balls are very light, much like blown
birds' iggs to the touch, and there is no
possibility of their breaking or of injur
ing anything they may strike except, of i
course, fragile bric-a-brac. The racquets !
are light rattan affairs, covered with |
vellum. In this respect they differ from j
those used in ordinary tennis, although |
ih>- dealers are showing some specially
constructed ones strung with catgut, as j
are tennis racquets. They were ordered
by ]>ing pong players' who are also tenn:s
experts and who believe they can play
In tter with the strung racquets than with
the vellunf-covered ones. Any table
about the height of a billiard table and
jn the neighborhood o. nine feet long by
five feet wide will do for the game. Many
use dining tables. To be correct one
should have a table, the surface of which
has been painted dark green, or covered
With biliard cloth, it makes no difference
in the game whether it is played with or
Without a cloth upon the table. Without
a cloth the balls will, of course, bounce
higher. The game is played by two or
Jour persons, usually by two. For the
at in which thfe are two players,
and this is the game in high favor, each
player stands art one end of the table.
The one first delivering the ball is called
the "serve;;" t):.- other person is th-e
".■strikeout." At the end of the iirst game
the "strikeout"-becomes the "server' and'
00 on alternately to the end of the sets.
As soon as theball is served and drops
nnywlK re on the table top beyond the t.et
it is 'play." if it drops Into the net-or
off the table it counts to the "strike out."
I i re is no second service as in lawn ten
jus. On either player winning the first
strike, the score is called fifteen for that
fourth stroke won by either player is sac
ond "game," unless both players have
yon three strikes, "forty all," whsn the
scon- is called deuce, and the next stroke
v.on by either player is scored "advan
tage" to that player.
[f the same player wins the next stroke
the game Is his: If he loses the next
eiroke the score is again deuce, and so i
on until either player wins the two
Strokes imediately following the score
player; on either player winning his or
her second stroke, the score for that play
er is thiity. On either player winning- the |
third stroke, the score is forty, and the
of deuce, and the "game" is scored for
that player. The player who lirst wins
six games wins the set. In tourna
ments usually three sets are played by
each competitor against each other one.
The rules for playing are similar to
those in lawn teunis, except that no over
hnnd service is allowed. There are no
urts marked as in lawn tennis, the
~\i of the table forming the court, so
that the ball striking any part of the ta
ble is in play. The strokes, apart from
the service, are divided into two main
lasses—the half volley and all other
Etrokee. The half volley is when the bull
immediately after striking the
table. The player hits where he thinks
the ball will be, not at the ball itself,
and it is, therefore, almost impossible
to actually hit is half voiieyin^. Ji is the
ball which hits the racket, and not the
racket that hits the ball. This ia en
tirely defensive play. To attack, the
ball must be struck after it has reached
the top of the bound, or even later, for on
ly then has the player complete control of
the ball. When the ball bounds high it
may be smashed straight on the table,
but if your opponent gets back so as to
make the return, twist your wrist BO that
the ball is hit at right angles to the
flight or even somewhat underneath; it
will drop close to the net and come
straight up or even bounce back over the
net. An effective stroke in reply to a
hard (irive is that called the "crouch
smash." As the ball cornea toward you,
crouch down and hit It at the edge of the
table. This is a good return for a hard
service, but it is most difficult to ac
complish. All these strokes can be done
■backhanded— -in fact, some are such
easier, as, owing to the wrist having
more play in the proper direction, a (,-rtat
er twist can be imparted to the ball.
In addition a ball falling on the right
hand side»f the table can be driven with
the back of the hand in any d-esircu di
rection. This stroke should only Le used
when pressed by a hird ball.
It will be gathered from th<^ strokes
described that play can be made both
back and forehand. This gives many
more opportunities for deceiving an op
ponent. Variety is the secret of success.
Nev< r let your opponent anticipate your
intention. When driven to swing, after
hitting the ball, do not stop and turn
back, but continue the swing the same
way, bo as to make a complete circle.
The player i an get square with the table
much quicker by doing this. Ping pong
sets may be had to suit any fancy or any</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016357/1902-05-03/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>P1NGPONO IS A CRAZE GRAZEHAS CRAZEHAS CRAZEHAS
HAS INVADED ALL SORTS OF PLACES PLACESFROM PLACESI PLACESFROM
FROM CLUBS TO HOTELS HOTELSOne HOTELSOne HOTELSOne
I
One Factory U I Timilnjr TlIrnln Out n Tl TIu Tlrogand TlrogandSets < unand unandScti jflnll jflnllSet
Sets Set n l DnyTho Lay > nj Tho 1ainlon l 1assinn lon For fie Sport StiortHas SOItIInOrown SportIIas
Has IInOrown Grown Up Siicldtnlj 6llItltenlllo Ilc urcsrj ureerue ureerueLnnJunlo uroalueLanguage ue ueLanguage >
Language For Carne Term TermIn TennIn TermsIn
In the past few days persons walk walking walkIng walkIng ¬
ing through the quiet uptown streets streetshave streetshave streetshave
have remarked about the number of ofhouses ofhouses ofhouses
houses through whose open windows windowscame windowscame windowscame
came the staccato pins pln 1 pong pongl ot the thexylonite thexylonlte thexylonlte
xylonlte table tennis ball Accordlug Accord AccordIng According
Ing to the stories which aro told by bydealers bytJealers bydealers
dealers In sporting goods thousandsotsets thousands thousandsof
of otsets sets of this game hare ha e been sold to tofamilies totam tofamilies
families tam Illes in the city and the demand demandappears tJemantJappears demandappears
appears to be increasing One taco factory tacotory fuetory ¬
tory at Ohlcopee Falls alone is turn turnlug turn turning turnIng ¬
ing out 1000 sets dolly and Is far t l be behind bebind behind ¬
hind Its orders Pingpong Ptng poug outfits arc arcgoing arcgoing aregoing
going iu numbers now to suburban suburbangolf sulmrbangolf suburbangolf
golf clubs It shows what a bold the thesport thesport thesport
sport has taken on Its devotees that thateven tlUltoen thateven
even the golfing enthusiast must take takehis takehis takehlsping
his hlsping pingpong pIngp pnng ng to flu iinks links with him himOur hImOur himOur
Our greatest demand for complete completesets completesets completesets
sets including the regulation tables tableshas tableshas tableshas
has of course come from the clubs clubssaid clubssnld clubssaid
said a dealer yesterday But the thewomen thcwomcn thewomen
women women and children hare got the thefever thetever thefever
fever as bad ba as their brothers and andfathers andtathers andfathers
fathers If youre writing about the thepingpong theplngl1011g theping
pingpong ping pong craze you cant make it t too toostrong oo oostrong oostrong
strong So far as I know we havent haventsold haventsold haventsold
sold a set to any old ladles la les home yet yetbut yetbut yetbut
but I dare are say the game will reach reachthem reachthem reachthem
them in time This craze beats any anything anything anything ¬
thing I ever heard of Our belief is isthat Isthat Isthat
that its only beginning Hot weather weathermay weathermay weathermay
may affect our sales somewhat but butwo butwe
wo look for an increased demand next nextfall nextfall nextfall
fall fallOur
Our indoor putting green In the theback theback theback
back of the th store has been occupied by bya bya
a pingpong ping poug table for several weeks weeksLfits weeksL weeksLets
Lets L ts of people who never saw the thegame thegame thegame
game come In here and watch a few fewsets fewsets fewsets
sets get fascinated by the play and nndcud riudend andend
end by buying racquets and balls anda and anda anda
a net to take home and set up on their theirdiningroom theIrdlnlngroom theirdining
diningroom dining room or billiard table Theres Theresa
a game going on here almost every everyhour ceryhOUl everyhour
hour of the day People cant seem to toget toget toget
get enough of IL ILThe It ItTho ItTho
Tho clubs have been and are still stilltlys stillt10 stilltl
tlys t10 tl > o stronghold of the craze although althoughthe nlthouhtho althoughthe
the newspapers have had more to say sayabout sayabout sayabout
about the play In brokers ofllces of lces and andon andon andon
on ocean steamers So sudden has been beenthe beenthe beenthe
the passion for the sport and so much muchroom muchroom muchrOonl
room does a regulation table take up upthat upthat upthat
that most of the clubs have had to togive togive togive
give up some other sport in whole or orIn 01In orin
In part for a time or else sacrifice sacrificepart sacrltleepart sacrificepart
part of their diningroom space No Nobody Nobody Nobody ¬
body seems to object however Even Eventho Erentho Eventhe
tho most sedate of club loungers al although nltbough although ¬
though he may begin by scoffing at atthe atthe atthe
the childs play ends in becoming becomingcither becomIngeither becomingeither
either an enthusiast entllUslastor or a disappointed disappointedbut lsappolnledbut
but persistent duffer dufferCollege dufferCollega dufferCollege
College clubs or other clubs fre frequented tree treequented frequented ¬
quented by younger men are the worst worstsufferers worstsufferers worstsufferers
sufferers from the pingpong ping pong malady maladyTho maladylo maladyI1he
I1he Tho lo Harvard 1 alvald Club early In Inthcwlutol Inthcwlutolput the winter winterput winterput
put up the little nets on its billiard billiardtables bllliardtables billiardtables
tables and billiards have scarcely
been played there since Members Memberspay Memberspay Iemberlpay
pay the same amount per hour for forplaying forplayIng forplaying
playing pingpong ping pong that they formerly formerlywere 1ormerl 1ormerlwero formerlywere
were cbnrgdtl for fortbe the use of the bit billiard bllliard bitHard ¬
liard tables The club has since set up upIn upIn upin
In addition a veal ping pingpong pong board boardThe boardThe boardThe
The Yale Club has four tables in one oneof oneot oneof
of the class diningrooms on the ninth ninthfloor ninthfioor ninthfloor
floor The Cornell University Club Clubgives Clubgives Clubgives
gives up half Its diningroom to the thopastime thepastime thepastime
pastime and the House UouseOommlttee UouseOommltteenow Committee Committeenow Committeenow
now talks of letting the whole apart apartment apattment apartment ¬
ment bo used for It so many of the themembers themembers themembers
members want to play and pingpong pingpongtables plngpongtables ping pong pongtables
tables can be used ns dining lnlnl tables if ifit ItIt ifit
it takes too long to make the change changeIn changeIn changeIn
In n Brooklyn Droold n athletic club the ping plugpongcrs pingpongers pingpongers
pongers have Invaded the the handball handballcourt handballcourt handballcourt
court Most of these resorts Ies rts have had hador hador hador
or are having pingpong ping pong tdurnamentsand tdurnaments tournamentsnnd
nnd clever players bare Jave been dowel developed deeloped doweloped ¬
oped in the course of a few weeks weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses weeksBoardinghouses
Boardinghouses In all parts of town townhave townhave townhave
have been hard hit by the craze The Thelong ihelong Thelong
long table ta ble in the back parlor l > llor makes a agood agood agood
good pingpong pl ping gllong pong board and a till the young youngman youngman youngman
man In the hall bedroom two flights flightsup filghtsup flightsup
up takes delight In making the star starboarder starboatder starboarder
boarder look like thirty cents The Thelandladies Thelandladies rholandladIes
landladies are arc rc not enthusiastic overthe over overthe 001the
the game because when played In the theevening theevening theevening
evening it has a n tendency to develop developa developrobust
a robust appetite for late suppersThe suppers suppersThe suppersThe
The vernacular of tbo sport has not notyet notyet notyet
yet reached a l high degree of development develop development oelop11ent ¬
ment For the present as Is the case casewith casewltbany casewith
wltbany with any new game players make free freewith treewltb freewith
with words nnd phrases plll ses proper to toother toother toother
other branches of sport Expressions Expressionslike Expressionslike
like You dealt cm the last time timeThis timeThis timeThis
This cue Is rotten Off side are areheard areIleard areheard
heard around the board Picturesque Picturesquelanguage Plctulesquelanguage Picturesquelanguage
language of n different character is isalso Isnlso isalso
also common The elusive celluloid celluloidsphere celluloidsphere celluloidsphere
sphere is as conducive to profanity as nsthe asthe asthe
the guttn guttnpercha percha A well known lawn lawntennis lawntennis lawntennis
tennis player has n novelty in the way wayof wayof wayof
of pingpong ping pong profanity When he hemakes hemakes hemakes
makes a fault he shouts Fudge I or orGoodness 01Goollness oreGoodness
Goodness gracious He explains that thatho thatbo thatlie
ho learned the game by playing with wltl1his withbis withhis
his sisters and it Isnt worth cussln cusslnabout cusslnabout cussinabout
about anyway anywaNew New York Sun</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016353/1902-05-11/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Making a PingJong PingJongget On g nay t tI
I get et at HOllie HOllieOt Ho HoOf a e
1 1Of
Of all the Indoor games that the wrl wrlr wrlcr wrier
cr r bas tried trIedand and bo has tackled about aboutill aboutn aboutill
ill n of them themnont none has proved such Jolly follyIQod Jollyood jollyfCod
fCod ood fun as table tennis or as the Engish Eng EngIsh
Ish call It pingpong pingpongA plngpongfirstclass ping pong pongA
I A firstclass pingpong plug pong outfit with wilhtwo withtwo withtwo
two rackets racl ets that are perfect little ten tenits ten11s tenis
its is rackets on a small scale will cost costibout costbout costibout
ibout 4 1 at the shop When it comes comeso corpes
o a n very cheap set you can probably probablypake probablypate probablypnke
pate at home just as good an outfit outfitFirst outfitIDd outfittntl
IDd tntl maybe btlter btlterF1rst bejteri
F1rst i First irstas as Si to the tb r rackets clictS In England Englandlie England1te
lie kind most favored have centres of oflarchment ofnrchment oflarchment
larchment like a drumhead from fromVhlch fromvhlch fromwhich
Vhlch the ball rebounds with that bum bumfling humnlng humg
fling pingpong ping pong sound which gives the thefame therame thelame
fame Its name nameThe nampThe nameThe
The writer prefers the string racket racketPieces Jacketrleces racket4leeos
Pieces of rattan soaked sOI1I Ctl a while In Inrteamlng inrteamlng inrteaming
rteamlng hot water WI1 tar to make them very verytupplo verytupple verytupelo
tupelo make good racket frames A Arooden Aooden Awoden
rooden handle hollowed out at the end endvlth endrith endvltb
vlth grooves for the rattan frame to toIt toIt toIt
It In Is simply constructed us shown shownn
n the thedlagram diagram above In stringing the thertrlng thertrlng theitring
rtrlng used on a banjo would be about about1ght aboutofght aboutfight
fight Two strings for each racket racketJiould racketJlOuld rackethould
Jiould b bt > enough enoughThese enougllhese enoughThese
These hese strings should shoul bo thoroughly thoroughlylooked thoroughlyoOaked thoroughlycaked
looked and then used while still wet wetDo weto
Do 0 not string too tight for If you do dovhen dorhen dovllen
vhen the strings dry and shrink they theyvlll theym theyvlll
vlll m pull the frame all allout out of shape shapeString shflpeHdng shapetring
String first across and andAlen toen en up and andlown andlawn andtown
lawn exactly as In a regulfClon regul on racket racketn
n making n support for your net a aouple aDuple aduple
Duple of yards of heavy hen telegraph wire wirevlll wirem wirevlll
vlll m answer Take each length and andlouble alldIiouble andlouble
louble and bend into shape shown In Inhe Inbe inbe
be diagram This of Itself may not be belulte beluite beluite
luite stanch enough to hold the net netaut netlut netnut
nut but by running a cord from the thex theop theop
x op > p of one wire support down and un unler unler unler
ler the tab table I to the top of the other otherlupport otherIUpport othersupport
support you OU should be able to obtain obtainlie obtainhe obtainhe
he necessary amount of rigidity The Thelet Thelet Thelet
let itself should be about sis Inches InchesUgh Inches11gh inchessigh
Ugh from the table and should clear clearhe clealhe clearhe
he table by enough to allow the ball ballo ballto
o pass easily asllr under it Any material materialvlll materialIVJIl materialgrill
vlll do for the net though a gauze or orlotting orlotting ortotting
lotting of some kind bound at the top topvlth toppith
pith Ith an Inch or two of white tape isLest Is Isest iscst
Lest est As to the table Itself It should
be e simply a smooth and flat surface surfaceibout surfacelbout surfaceibout
ibout five by ten feet or say four by bysight byIght byIght
Ight fret fretThe ftetThe feetThe
The game Is played exactly as tenass ten tensis tenIlls
sis is played except e cept that there is but butne butme butlne
me ne court on either efth el side of the net If Ifthe Ifhe Ifthe
the he ball strikes the very edge e ge of the thetable thel1ble theable
table and 10 o bounces off at In such suel1l1 a way waythat wayat waythat
that at a return la Impossoble call it an anedger anedger anedger
edger and serve over again againThe a Ialn IalnTIle aln alnThe
The method oC scoring is the same lameHil sameis
18 in tennis One rule of the old game gamevhlch gamejhlch gamewhich
which IB barred because of the narrow narrowbounds narrowoundl narrowbounds
bounds ic volleying A ball can never neverie neerJe neverbe
ie returned except on the bounce bouncePickups bouncePlckuPI bouncePickups
Pickups however loWerer are allowable An Another Anther An9ther ¬
other ther strict ruling of pingpong ping pong is that thatQO thatno
QO overhand strokes are allowed the thehand thehand theband
hand must never be raised above the theheight theheIght theheight
height of th tlll elbow Also the serve servemutt 5118I servemust
mutt be delivered from a a point beyond beyondthe beyondthe beyondthe
I the end of the table tableThe tableThe tableThe
The tennis experts and allround nll ronnd ath athletes dhbave athletes ¬
letes have devised It new sort of racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
that makes of tills parlor game nme a rath rathir ratbar rathar
ar strenuous and exciting affair affairThe affairThe affairThe
The racket is simply a l wooden pad paddle pRal11e padale ¬
ale of about the same outside dimen dimensions dim dimenslona en en3lonl ¬
sions as a the pingpong plag pong strung racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
that is about six inches In diameter diameterroughly dlameterroughly diameterroughly
roughly speaking IIpealtingthe the handle being of ofany oflny ofany
any desired length lengthThe lengUIThe lengthThe
The paddle part IB not of one piece piecewith piecewith piecewith
with the handle hl1n le as it would break or orsplit 01split orsplit
split too easily The handle Is spliced splicedon
on The paddle padaJeon on one side or both bothaccording botIllccordlng bothaccording
according to bow you play is covered coveredwith coveredwith coveredwith
with emery cloth or paper guled on oncarefully oncarefullJ oncarefully
carefully With this thl rough surface surfaceyou lurfacerou surfaceyou
you can cut the ball or give the Law Lawford L LfortI Lawford
ford stroke In splendid fashion fashionAs rub fashionAs Ion IonAs
As to balls the best art those made madeof madeof madeof
of celluloid which can be e bought at atany atn atany
any n sporting or toy store for a few fewcents reweents fewcents
cents apiece apieceThis apleCeTIIIIIJ apieceThis
This pingpong ping pong is I really a great game gameand gameand gameand
and the writer thinks thInk it has 1111 come to tostnyDetroit totarDetrolt tostayDetroit
stnyDetroit Free litre Press PressTli Prfl PrflTIle PressThe</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1902-05-18/ed-1/seq-46/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SUMMER DELIGHTS OF
B1 LJ
ti
I
F. L. VA3IDEVEER &SV HARRY BLO(
Two well-known young attorneys, who are experts at the
Written for the Sunday Republic.
I ping We tear our clothes.
Thou pongst You raise the deuce, if
He pongs They fall In a faint.
Verb, Irreg. Origin, Japan. Inf,
s to ping-pong.
St. Xiouls is ping-pong maa. Everybody
plays It; and so enthusiastic are the de
votees of the game that It is now assured
that the game will run through the sum
mer. But it Is a winter game, declares some
one. We will make It a summer jjame, fben,
is the ifsponse.
PING PONG.
E.ETT,
game of Ping-Pong.
In Its Indigenous clime it is a game for
all the year. Summer and winter alike, it
is a game, not only for men, but also for
women and children.
Tor more than three centuries how much
more no one knows ping-pong has been a
game of great Importance.
Of course, the name is inane, but there is
I
KICKED BY A MULE
TUMBLED INTO A MINE.
if m v C
i ii -- 1 1 in i iu -w.!&r .1 im mkiii i ,
wssLMmm
mmmSMlrmb
Monai '
VM. G. LLOYD.
Special Correspondence of The Republic
Now York, May 16 There seems to be pi
most no limit to the. number of breaks and
bruises a man may suffer and still live to
tell the tale. As long as no -vital organ la
actually destrojed, there seems to be al
most no end to tho Injuries a. man may re
ceive without their proving mortal.
Two workmen in New Jersej have reccntly
been all but broken to pieces, but still live.
One of them, a miner, fell down a 200-foot
shaft near Morrlstown, sustaining injuries
which will keep the doctors busy for sev
eral months. The other received an ener
getic kicking from a mule, and will so
about for the rest of his life with a con
siderable part of his anatomy composed of
silver plates, rubber and falsa skin.
It Is difficult to say which of the eraser is
the mora rem" Me. William C Lloid of
Trenton, N. discharged from the
hospital onlj i days ago, after three
months of tr&, .t. Ills injuries were in
flicted by a mug In tho fraction of a sec
ond. The animal kicked off large sections
of his skin, fractured his skull, removed
his eyebrows and practically all of his
teeth, besides giving him a general shaking
up. To-day, however, he is practically as
good as now, and e-tpecte. soon to return to
his work. Meanwhile, his head will re
main, as long as he lives, a veritable mu
seum of artificial appliances.
Llojd was employed in the stables of the
Rocbllng Company, and was know n to be a
daring and expert horseman. The com
pany owned a very unruly mule, which had
long resisted all the attempts made to tamo
him. and tho perilous work was finally In
trusted to Lloyd. Unfortunately, tho at
tempt was made without any witnesses
present. There is, therefore, no authentic
record of what happened.
Tho unfortunate mule tamer was deprived
of all consciousness very early in the en
gagement. He remembers being kicked
twice. Judging from his appearance after
tho engagement, it appeared that tho mule
had ppent tho greater part of tha day kick
ing him.
Tho blows wero delivered fairly In the
face. Tho force of their delivery may bo
Imagined from the fact that several of the
heaviest bones of the tkull were actually
splintered by the impact. Llojd is pos
sessed of Immense energy, or ho could not
hav o lived an hour. As a matter of fact, the
real extent of the Injuries was not dUcov
ered for some time.
Lloyd was first treated in Trenton, but
when the extent of his injuries became
knowr it was found necessary to take him
to "jpeciilists In Philadelphia. Tho work ot
rebuilding his skull and remaking his face
a lot to tho game besides tho name; and
you may call it with perfect propriety, "ta
ble tennis." That will save your feelings.
Tor tho game is nothing moro or less
than a diminutive gamo of tennis It is
counted exactly like tennis; requires as
many players; furnishes as much exercise,
and offers as great an opportunity for tho
practice of subtle heart-charms.
Who plays ping-pong? The answer is
easy: Kverybody. The popularity- of tho
gamo has increased so much in tho last
few months that it has become necessary
to manufacture the racquets and balls in
St. Louis; tho foreign markets are unablo
to furnish even half of what Is required
It is not only a fad, but has undoubtedly
como to stay as much as tennis did years
ago
Tennis is still a popular game. We have
champions; national and local. So It will
bo with ping-pong before another year has
rolled around. Already In St Louis me
have tournaments, championships and
prizes at ping-pong parties. There is great
rivalry between clubs and between mem
bers of clubs. One cannot go to dine now
adays without having to tako part in a
gamo of ping-pong after the dinner. It Is
everywhere and all-absorbing.
Not only men of leisure and ladies of
quality aro indulging In it, hut business
men and college stoudents and women
mho have to busy themselves about a hun
dred and one things during the day. Hv-
erybody has the fever. A ping-pong parlor
on Locust street is crowded every day for
several hours with players and there Is no
sign of any loss of Interest In the game.
Bankers and brokers find that the gamo
gives them moro and better exercise in a
short time that they have been able to get
in any other way. Among the devotees of
the game are Allen West, Dwight Davis,
Harold Kauffman, Hunt Turner and Jim
Drummond. They frequently find tlmo to
meet during the day for a game. Usually
it Is for but a short time, but occaslonaily
they become so Interested that tfcey finish
the afternoon at the table.
But the season for ping-pong Is after
dinner. Then at private residences and at
the clubs there is Invariably a game In
progress. Special rooms have been fitted up
in houses large enough to accommodate
them, and In the clubhouses where the par
ticularly ardent worshippers at tho shrine
of the celluloid ball and the racquet may
commune with their own kind.
Stuart Stlckney, he of golf fame, is a
"fiend" at ping-pong. He says himself that
he has to struggle to keep away from a table
during tho day In order that he may devote
himself to business. But at night and on
Saturdays he gives may to th desire and
Instead of playing golf he stands at a ping
pong table until he is about ready to drop.
The exercise In the game will be ac
knowledged when It Is known that a tennis
and a golf champion have almost forsaken
their favorite game for the enticing ping
pong. Dwight Davis does not play tennis
as much as he used to; and Stuart Stlckney
is rarely seen with his clubs Yet. both ex
celled in their special branches of athletic.
But ping-pong is a winter game, said one
who was only half converted. Needless to
say he could play only fairly. A host rose
to contradict him. Already many lawns are
being prepared for a table during the um
mer. All that is necesasry 1 an even place I
for the table and light enough so that the'
balls may be seen In the evening. In Japan 1
and in England the game Is played the year
'round. Why not In St. Louis?
Evening ping-pong parties during the
summer are already assured. It Is not dis
f
r "
l (fat K? A MXJLESKim
ID TO YtM-M.lUO2!
was gone about s-.iemiticallv. The frac
tured part of his skull wis removed and
replarcu t a "ilvir plate This was not
merely i imttcr of sllveraUtlng an in
jured part The bone was ctuallv cut
avay and the tilvtr plate rtatly litted ill
its place The tkin was, then carefully
drawn over the plate and stvved. In timu
it is believed even the seir will disappear.
He will carry the silvtr plate to his grave.
The roof of Ilia mom! was alio broken,
past repair and a similar courtehad to to
tmploytd In rebuilding it An artificial tow
ering of rubber, was midc to tit in the in
jured portion. Despite hia artificial mouth
he is able to speak and at with pirfett
comfort. The artltlc al roof of his mouth.
Is adjustable and can lx- rtmoved at will.
Tho lost teeth were repl icpd by a full new
double set. Meanwhile a number of small
fractures of bones of the head were set and
held in position until they had knitted in
the ordinary manner
The most remarkable part of the opera
tion of repairing the damages inll'cted by
th mule was the operation of si-in grafting.
Friends volunteered to supply him with a
small part o the'r own cuticle to rep'aco
that which had been removed by the mule.
Tho operation is rather delicate and is pain
ful for both parties, c.
The contributors presented themselves at
the hospital, to be prepared for the opera
tion. The skin was taken from the upper
rart of the forearm. The skin was first
carefullv shaved and next washed very
thoroughly with a strong antiseptic. Kvcry
precaution was of course taken to prevent
any contagion All tho instruments used
were steriljied.
The other case was that of a miner named
Peter Henshaw of Hibernia, N. J. Hen
sham's Injuries were not so nany or pic
turesque as Lloyd's, though the accident
itself w as cv en more remarkable. Hensham
was working the other day near the top of
a W-foot telegraph pole when he lost hla
hold, and plunged downward. He was near
ly 00 feet from the ground when he lost
hold, and the fall, to thoe who chanced
to sec him, appeared to mean certain death.
As he dropped, however, he reached -6ut
mildly, and by a lucky chance his arm
struck a set of telegraph wires beneath
him, and to one side These served to part- ,
ly check his fall, but at the same time
swung his body outward. Ho fell from tho
pole with an awful force.
AH this v as bad enough, but morse await,
ed him. The wires, bysinging him to
ono side, dropped him at tho foot of a
mining shaft. Tho mountains thereabouts
are honey -combed with these shafts, which.
pierce the earth at a variety of angles. The
shaft near which Henshaw fell runs into
a mountain at a steep angle. Had it been i
a perpendicular shaft he would have fallen i
to cc-tain death.
As it mas, he mas so badly stunned at
the Instant he struck tho ground that h
could not save himself, and slipped Into
the hole. His body continued to slip, slida
nrd fall by turns until it reached the bot.
torn of the shaft, 100 feet below. By a
miracle of good luck. Henshaw only hroke
one leg and two ribs In the descent.
tinctly a rich man's or woman's game, ai
has often been sapposed. but almost every
one may havo a set Tha sets aro cheap
even as compired with tennis sets. Wher
ever there is room for a dining table therfj
is room for ping-pong, and tho fascination
that the gamo nor. holds, especially amon
tho smart set. cannot bo downed by warn;
m cather.
Among tho particularly pood plng-ponr;
rooms in bt, Louis, asldo from tho clubs,
are those at tho Drummond's. Mis Wtck
him's and at tho McKittrick's. Cvery evo
ning ping-pong holda sway. It is proper
nowadays for young ladies to take soma
form of physical exercise, and ping-ponB
combines all the pleasure that they- may
find in any exercise and affords all tha
sport of play. j
Ralph and Walter McKittrlck, Arthua
Shepley and Dan KIrby- are among the best
and most enthusiastic players In the city.
The Country Club and tho Florissant Club
are utterly crazed over tho game. At pres
ent It holds the trumps over all other
games, and from Indications it will be tha
popular game of the summer at both clubs.
Of course, this does not mean that tenn!
and golf and polo will not havo their de
votees, but ping-pong will bo tho most frequently-
played gamo of tho season.
The women of the city are us enthusias
tic .as the men-possibly more so. and they
havo their claims upon the attention of tho
men and their sports. Ping-pong looks and
sounds llko a game that does not requira
as much cndtiranco and strength as other11
spons anu tint is sid to bo tho reuson
that the women have taken It up. As t,
matter ot fact. It is as violent as nlmnst
any gamo th it Is popular with many peo
ple, but It seems so playful that tho weaker
be. have seized upon It.
It is a fact that one business man of this
c ty a man or more than usual corpulence-
has reduced his weight by forty pounds
playing ping-pong. And If the truth mi.ro
known, it is probably true tint several
women have been enabled to become mora
sylph-like through the medium of the game.
But that Is .v matter concerning which
women will not talk.
Women who are onenlv .anient nl.-ners
of
ny
ping-pong are rot the ones of whom any
one can say they play to reduce thel
weight. They- are modern women In every
may, and have taken up tho game not only
because it Is tho fad, but also because it
Is a g ime that enables them to keep In
good physical condition It is proper no
longer for momtn to be weak and requiring
the attention of maids and menr but they
mut be able to cope with the strongest.
Accordingly, they tako as much exercise,
comparatively, as men And ping-pong of
fers them something in the way of a gam
that has not been offered by any thins
else.
Among the more prominent women play
ers of ping-pong are Mrs. James Drurr
mond, Mrs. William' Gregg, Mri. Laurence
J. Mornn MIs ickham. Mis Mitchell.
Mrs. E O. Stanard, Mrs. W. II. Walker
and Mrs. Goodman King. Each of theso
has an elaborate ping-pong room fitted up
nt her house, and parties are frequent. It
is not at nit unusual for them to meet in
the morning and play arduously befora
luncheon. It serves as an excellent appe
tizer. The game was hroiight 'to St. Louis by
two people at about the same time. Mrs.
E. H. Semple ot Westminster place be
came enamored of the game while abroad
last summer, and when she returned she
set up a table at once. Sirs. Sidney Walker
appeared on the scene at about the sama
time, an enthusiastic player of the game.
That mas its start In thi3 city. It did not
take long to bring the sport to its present
position, but these two St. Louisans havo
been instrumental In making it a fad.
One of the best players among the women
is Mrs. Lewis Haywood She has for sev
eral months been a devotee, and lias ac
quired remarkable 'kill in handling tho
racquet. Mrs. John Fowler Is another ex
cellent player, and Mrc Dan Taylor, Mrs,
Campbell Smith and Mrs. Frank HammeS
are also in the first class. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1902-05-25/ed-1/seq-21/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DAFT ON PING-PONG
Washington Entranced With
Game, Which Is Played
in Many Homes
'fcOOM OF TIGHT CORSET
f(Xew Diversion Has Phenotncnal
Hold on All Sort* and Condi-
tion*. From 9teM Senators
tv DudtliiiK Debutantes.
Special to The Globe.
■ WASHINGTON, D. C. May 21.—Mover
j lias the national capital been so com-
T-letely enslaved by the fascinations of a
game, indoor or outdoor, as it has fallen
; (under the seductive influence of the won
jdc-rful new game, which, having set , all
J l^ngland crazy, has come with- a power
' to] stride across the Atlantic to exercise
its potent influence upon our social life.
i As a prominent leader of Washington
I society remarked the other day, "Wash
ington has fairly gone ping-pong mad."
. Conversation in capital society has now
i foe-come impregnated with the peculiar
I terms of the new pastime. Where for
merly one would hear "social precedence"
' and "rising man," one now hears "clever
i (half volleyer" and "invincible striker
I out." '
"Love" and "advantage" as topics of
; social conversation have now a ping-pong
significance entirely foreign to their for
xtx-r meaning among the capital gossips.
The ping-pong party has entirely sup
planted the whist party arid the bridge
circle.
The peculiar ping-pong of the celluloid
; balls as they are beaten to and fro (from
■which the game derives its name) is now
to be heard j in every Washington home
from the palatial mansion of the fam
-1 ily of the men who shape the nation's.
I destiny on Pennsylvania avenue to the
• humble residence of the congressional
I bootblack in the eastern section of the
i city. Years are a matter of no consid
; ©ration among the devotees of the sport.
■ The mature matron whose nod or frown
I Oias settled one way or the other the so
cial aspirations of mar.v- a newcomer
.at the capital is as frequently to be seen
i exerting herself in a manner wonderful
to behold, to keep the little swiftly pass- j
ing celluloid ball from dropping on her
I side of the net, as is the beautiful bud
| ding debutante who, with flushed face,
eyes sparkling with enthusiasm- and ex
. citement. and bared arms wildly but
Withal skillfully circling the air, is a
cSaily testimonial to the aethestic features
of the game.
Strike* nil Classes.
. . Nor are the enthusiasts of the new
gam" to be found only among the fairer
sex, - Washington masculinity has given
itself to ping-pong with an abandon
,Nor ar^ the enthusiasts .of the now
which would furnish a profitable study to
the seeker- of pysehologieal phenomena.
Staid congressmen, dignified senators.
Learned members of the bench and bar
When they meet together nowadays dis
cuss not, the political significance of the
lim.s. but the latest-make of ping-pong
racquet.
This -may be regarded as gross exagger
ation. It is a potent fact, however, that
ping p has attained a surprising vogue
■among Washington's public men.
All the leading hotels and cafes are
hastening to open up ping-pong parlors
on their premises, so that their distin
guished patrons may indulge .to their
heart's content in the game. . •
Senator Maur.a. when asked the other'
■day whether he favored the. erection of aj
ping-pong parlor in the national capital,
l>uckercd up.his brow* and gave the mat
tor a few minutes' serious consideration
before discussing the idea with a smile.
Congressman Sulzer, when asked to ex
plain the tremendous hold that ping-pong
has taken upon members of the-house,
said that it is a wonderful game for~ex
erclse. and gives one a good hand to
sustain the handshaking proclivities of
the vast army of well meaning citizens
| who swoop down upon unwilling repre
sentatives of the people with all the re
lentless energy of the notorious New
Jersey musquito upon its helpless victim.
As may be supposed, the stores have
not been slow to take advantage of the
commercial possibilities of the craze. In
* -addition to the fact that some of the
larger dry goods emporiums are opening
up ping-pong saloons for the accommo
dation of their patrons, the new game
has an important bearing upon the latest
styles. The ping-pong waist is prom
inently- displayed in the shop windows,
find is a phenomenal seller; while the
new forms of neckwear for women and
men bear handsomely embroidered figure.*
■of ping-pong racquets and balls upon
their silken folds.
Doom of the Tight Corset.
One important reform the game prom,
ises to effect, which may render rational,
the development which has been lavished'
upon it by England and America and im
mortalize the new game as one of the
most valuable and beneficent reform fac
tors of the century.
Ping-pong may abolish the tight laced
■corset.
Ping-pong is essentially an informal
game to be played at the spur of the
moment, as the whim seizes. It is a
game to be introduced by the smiling
hostess after the last vestige of the din
"■ner has been cleared away and ti;o
white table cloth is removed to make
way for the ping-pong net. Consequently
as the rapid movement and freedom of
body S necessary to me ping-pong player
renders the corset impossible, the charm
ing diner out has either to leave off her
corsets when she dresses to attend a
modern dim party or run the risk of
having to stand against the wall in ail
the-prim symmetry of a corseted waist
and, watch the merry movements of her
more fortunate sisters who, with grace
fully swing forms, keep the merry cellu
loid ball ping-ponging across the table
at a lively pace to the intense admira
tion of the man with the racquet on th^
other side of the table and .every other
man In the room. v
This good may ping-pong do; bu other
„ wise what peculiar qualities has the same
to '-rive it phenomenal popularity? Strict
ly speaking it is nothing more or less
then a table adaptation of lawn tennis
and tennis, while possessing to an equal
and even greater degree the same physi
cal benefits and sporting fascinations of
its replica has never attained the vogue
which has been vouchsafed to ping-pong.
Played on Dining Table.
Ping-pong is played on an ordinary din-
Ing table and its only accessories are
posts tp hold the net, the net itself
vellum string or wood-racquets and cellu- ■
loid balls: The game is for two people
one standing on one end of the table,
the other opposite. The player who first
delivers the ball is called the server ■ The
Other the striker out. i The service is
strictly underhand and is delivered from
beyond the end of the table.
£ The: ball served must drop on the table
beyond the net and is then in piav. if
it dops into the net or off the table it
counts to the striker out
The server wins a stroke if the striker
out fails to return the service or ball in
play of the table.
The striker out wins a stroke If the
server fails to return the ball in play or
makes a foul in service.
On either player winning his first stroke
the score la 15. The second stroke brings
the score to 30; the third stroke is called
•40 and the fourth stroke wins a game
The player who wins the first six games
' -wins a set.- -
This is all there really is to the game
of ping-pong. Certainly it Is a skill de
manding and skill acquiring game. It
lias simplicity and cheapness to recom
mend it. It is far better from a hygenie
standpoint than a majority of parlor
prames and is an extremely socialble and
interesting pastime. It is. for these rea
. sons and its similarity to tennis, a game
calculated to prove attractive to the"
. younger members of both sexes. .
: But why It has set the people of two
' countries almost crazy: why old as well
as young-have taken up ping-pong when
they would not as much as look at an-
other form of sport; why the game
acquired such a vogue on the other side
that one serious British magazine writer
has accused; English society of being
more interested in the records of ping- j
pong champion than in the fortune of
the British troops in South Africa and
has prophetically croaked of Nero fid
dling, while Rome is burning— are
phenomena that: it would puzzle the
average human being to account for; and
the answer is certainly not forthcoming
from the devotees of the game. : .
9 — -—Bertram Lebhar.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1902-06-01/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Prin-
would be better if it were gray, but ex.- i
pcrience has taught that white is the best
adapted for the use of the expert player.
'•There can be no doubt," said an ex
pert the other day, "that the constant
watching- of the ball which is required in
the game tends to aggravate a^eakneaw
of the eyes. The moving of the muscUf
which control the eye3 wearies them after
an ordinary game. The control of. the
eyes is really the most essential part, for
the game calis into requisition compara
tively few muscles.
"I have heard much of the ping-pong
ankle, but as the ankle is used compara
tively little in playing I do not think that
the maiaUy is one.v/hich the player need
count. Some players find that the dorsal
muscles arc easily tired, and the man
who stoops a great deal in his effort to
find the balls which have been knocked to
the carpet is lijtcly to suffer from sore
ness and inflammation of the muscles
alrout the pftins. There is in my opinion
j. ping-pong eye, although I deny that
there is si ping-pong face.
"It has been said that the muscles of
the legs and arms are often wearied By
the game. This .is true in a. sense, but I
think that the eye and the brain -will be
exhausted :n ping-pong long before the
muscles used in sending and returning
balls can be affected to any appreciable
extent."
•— -\ ISEASES with strange names have
Dloliowtd in the wake of ping-pong,
J.ut the real pang is not a fanciful
une. for the watching of the cellu
loid* sphere really strains the eyes.
Let London surgeons talk as they will
about tei.dosyr.ovitis "and p^ig-ponS an
kles: all these are as nothing compared
to tho'strair.ed muscles of the eye of the
Ail ping-pong devotees, even experts,
suffer from the ping-pong eye more or
Jess. Other muscles employed to playing
th* game are ""speedily co-ordinated. To
develop a proper technique is^ing-pong
is no easy matter, and in the endeavor
the eye suffers the most.
There is a ping-pong wrist, of course,
and a ping-pong back, but the player who
can return a ball a hundred times or so
suffers comparatively little from these.
The tyro who bends often to pick up the
balls -which bound upon the carpet is the
one who is most likely to complain of
In time he learns, however, to make the
optical nerves save the exertions of the
muscles. Then he requires a ping-pony
i ji^jlimii
Not much strength # is required in tho
game. A little more vigorous than bil
liards and not quite bo arduous as tennis.
of which it is a cousin german, pins-
THE S U^J)AY CALL. .
pcng appeals to those who have the quick
eye. -/ .
The skillful player can keep his body
almost rigid, and standing In front of the
table send the ball backward and forward
with scarcely a movement of a muscle
except those of the wrists. Many or the
players are able- to sit In • one of the
chairs such as are used by spectators in
billiard games, and still keep the ball go
ing rapidly.
Physicians say that many ping-pong
players suffer from an inflammation of
the eye. and champion players add their
Testimony. The constant watching of the
ball is liable to cause heaoaclies, or, 'in
other words, to cause irritation to spread
from the overworked optical mu.-des.
The pir.g-ro"g eye is often bloodshot.
The only way to cure it is to stop play
ing and to give the overworked eye a
chance to rest. Th!s the ping-pong devo
te*- objects to doing. When ho becomes
absorbed in the game he persists in play
ing it in season and out of season.
There are many . ping-pong table's which
served originally in dining-rooms. The
man who plays upon them is prone fo
contract the ping-pong eye. The ideal
table should be dark green^This color is
easy on the eye. A retired billiard or
poo! • table is well adapted to the game,
as far*"as the effect upon the eye is con
cerned. The ball is dazzling white. It
THE PING PONG
STRAIN ON THE EYE
MUSCLES</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1902-07-13/ed-1/seq-39/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>umination,
Mrs. Duncan's ptcg-pocg set win he the
i principals of the tennis games to be played
, at sight tn Cabasne, With so much to en
tertain the younger society element, it Is
doubtful if many more will Join the earlier
exodus during the month of August. Mrs,
Mae Wiggs has decided to remain at home
to keep house for her father, the genial Pat              ##### FIX THIS ###########
Short, who has rent his wife and grand
son away, hut prefer for himself the
comforts of his charmingly appointed
home. Mrs. Wiggs. who calls her father
"son," looks after the cooking herself, an!
leaves even the fascinating ping-pong, at
which she is a adept, to return home n
THE WOMAN WHO WAS "DONE.
WlU'l'lJS; TOTt TUB STJNDAT RETtTBUCL
"It's only a bad attack of parasitus; m
bo ail right soon," raid the bachelor ctrl
weakly from her pillow-propped position on
the divan, as she motioned her sympathis
ing caller to aa easy chair.
"Oh. parasltusr said the friend, trying to
look as if she knew all about it. "That must
be bad for you I didn't know you were 111</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1902-09-21/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The cut Is much the same. The object
of the cut is to make the ball go over the
net with that | peculiar < little ' rotary mo
tion which causes it to bounce In an en
tirely opposite "direction from .the way
that would naturally, be expected. This
is where the_rule of waiting for the ball
to bounce comes in so handy. " >v^7--
As nearly as I can describe them, so
of the court. "Care must be taken, how
ever, not to drive it outside the scoring
line, or your opponent-will score against
you on your own error, as in ping pong.
In both games, as you know, the scoring
is the same.'. .'.-_. ¦ . . . : r'-v^ "¦V? ;'¦'¦
. The volley is used when your opponent
is close to the , net. To execute it you
strike the ball .with ;a swinging . upward
motion, which - drives it high above the
head and far out of his reach in the rear
. The smash is always used when you are
close to the net. It is executed with a
swift short-arm stroke to drive the ball
straight down., A good smash ball prop
erly executed la practically r unreturnable,
for the 'ball can be delivered with incred
ible speed and accuracy.
.Until you get accustomed to the game
use the lightest racquet obtainable.' This
will relieve much of the soreness that in
variably follows the first two~or.thre«
games. -¦;. •..•¦•'
But : to 'return to the explanation of
technical points.
sity of thp muscles of -the shoulders and
back and removes all danger of spraining
them. •; .;¦ V
the greatest precision in driving, Just as
the full free arm stroke relieves the ten-
Always Jiold the racquet as near the "
extreme eifd of the handle as possible:
This gives you greater reach, as well as *
¦*» . ¦ ¦ .'¦-.¦'¦¦
Let your opponent do all ths smashing
until you , have mastered the first rudi
ment of the sport
Nearly all beginners have this fault :n
common. They don't seem to realize that
they are ruining all their chances of suc
cess by flagrant violation of this very sim- \
pie little rule. And it is ofttlmes difficult \
to make It clear to them that in" giving the
ball a good chance to bounce well, the
leisurely player not only Insures himself
greater precision In returning it over the.;
net, but is enabled thereby to play a moro
masterly, game, besides . saving strength •
and ' energy. I - • . ¦ . • ¦ .
to* follow at all times. Always let the ball
bounce If you ar^' playing in the back
court, and take y/ir time in returning it.
Don't be in a hurry to hit it quick.: Wait!
There is lots of time. The ball will conie^.
rlgh-t up to you if you will only let \.\..*$r~
For comfort wear extra heavy stock
ings. If you don't, your feet are apt to
Of course, you will get hot and flushed
and tired and more or less ruffled, and be
draggled generally, but the chief thing In
tennis Is to get the ball back ove~r the
net as fast as your opponent can drive or
place it on your own side. You will quick
ly discover very ,early In the game
if you are a beginner that It takes all of
your beet thought and energy to accom
plish this result without worrying over
little matters of dress.
Don't worry about your personal appear
ance. Tou can't play good tennis if your
mind is actively concentrated on an un
ruly curl that will persist, despite your
best efforts to control It, in playing tag
with the wind.
Don't wear high heel shoes, or a skirt
bo long that you have to keep one hand
constantly engaged In holding it up to
keep from stumbling over it.
This does not mean that you should not
look trim and r.eat and well dressed, but
your shirt waist must be so loose that
when you reach for a high volley the
action will not necessarily start the seams
at the sleeves or make an ugly gap at the
belt.
Don't wear tight clothesf
And. girls, let me Impress upon you at
the very outset that freedom of move
ment, absolutely unrestrained In every
muscle, is the first essential to success in
tennis. Indeed, the question of appropriate
costume must be your first consideration.
There Is scarcely an hour of any day
when they are not crowded with players
cf all ages— but, oh, such playing as most
of the beginners do indulge in! They play
all over the court, driving the ball hap
hazard everywhere but within the lines
prescribed by the rules of the gam*. I
think this fault with girls lies in the fact
that they do not dress properly. They
hamper themselves with their clothes, and
then expect to become experts.
It Is the reactionary influence of ping
pong on tennis Itself that Is «o surpris
ing, for In a greater degree — a far greater
degree— than Is generally supposed ping
pong is responsible for the sudden and
growing popularity of tennis In the courts
at Golden Gate Park.
solely of the possibilities for dainty
rowEic* which it afforded, nor of the
.hitherto unsuspected opportunities for
'flirtations that resulted seriously. There
would be no need to epeak of those things
here. Every girl learned them for herself
very early in the ping-pong craze, and
made the most of the game.
PING-PONG, childish Imitation of
tennis though It is. has done won
ders for our sex. Every girl ought
to be'* very clad that she learned
It, though I'm not thinking now
Then there is the underhand drive,
wherein you bring the racquet round and
up, knocking the ball high above the net
for a volley serve. In executing the
underhand drive, take lots of time and
don't strike the ball until It Is falling close
to the ground.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99066033/1902-06-14/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW POOR LO HAS THE PING PONG CRAZE
Somebody has taught the Indians of Buffalo Bill's Wild West show how to play ping pong, and the noble
Keds have become as greatly enslaved by the fascination of the game as are their brethren, the pale faces. The
above Is an authentic snapshot of a scene in Buffalo Bill's camp. It shows Black Fox in the midst of an exciting
game. The popular chief Is a passionate devotee of the game and has attained great proficiency in its many intricacies.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99066033/1902-04-19/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A GAME OF PING PONG IN LONDON SOCIETY.
Is America going to have the Ping Pong craze which at present affects England? Present indications seem
to point to an affirmative reply to this question. The game has already taken a phenomenal hold In this country
and Ping Pong tables are now properly installed in thousands of homes throughout the country. As yet the
game (which Is a table adaptation of tennis) is being adopted here within the bounds of sanity. Not so In Eng
land, where society seems to have given itself heart and soul to the fad. One famous British magazine writer
has upbraidingly declared that Ping Pong is at present of more moment to the average Englishman than the prog
ress of the. war in South Africa. -</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99066033/1902-08-02/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Piag Pong Girl
(Philadelphia Times.)
The ping pong craze promises to out
rival the golf fad of previous seasons
In the multitude of things brought out
in the shops which owe their existence
to the fashionable game imported from
London.
Ping pong shirtwaist-sets In silver
consist of a brooch formed of two bats
crossed inside of a horseshoe, and three
pins for the front of the waist made
of two bats crossed.
Ping pong stick-pins have a single
bat mounted on the end of the pin.
The end of a ping pong hatpin is orna
mented with two bats crossed. The de
votee of the ultra-fashionable amuse
ment can proclaim her allegiance by
draping her chapeau with a veil of
white chiffon profusely embroidered In
black with small crossed bats sur
rounded with tiny balls, or the same
design comes embroidered In white on
black chiffon.
Among the special neckwear designed
for the "Ping Pong Girl" is the ping
pong cravat This consists of a stock,
shaped to fit the neck, of heavy corded
white pique finished with long ends,
smartly ornamented on the edge with
lows of stitching, which widen gradu
ally and terminate In a fancy pointed
effect: the ends are double, the one on
top being of pique, beneath which Is
another detached of soft fine mull In
contrasting color, this being slightly
larger, so that when the ends are
crossed and fastened with a scarf pin
the effect Is of a border of color ex
tending beyond the white pique.
The same Idea is carried out In the
ping pong cravat, which comes with
ends already tied in a double knot In
front This Is extremely smart In the
now very fashionable black moire or in
barathea silk ornamented- wlth tows
of stitching, and also In butcher's linen.
These cravats are shown In the various
summer colors.
Another ping pong cravat Is of white
cheviot made with a stock three inches
high and tie graduating Into very wide
ends and embroidered with a design of
crossed bats and balls In black-and-white
or in color. The cravat Is usu
ally worn with ends folded over once
and fastened with a pin.
A ping pong stock of fine, striped,
imported madras has ping pong em
blems embroidered in black, pink, blue
and golf green.
A washable ping pong belt with stock
to match comes in a peculiar fancy
open mesh called Kro-mesh. The
edges are bound with narrow lawn. All
colors are represented, but particular
ly pretty are the all-white mesh belts
and those In different combinations of
blue and white pale blue with white
border, white with pale blue border, a
light blue and white plaid mesh with
white border. A white mesh delicately
barred in green with white binding is
smart as are the black-and-white ef
fects. The gay plaids are quite the
thing for golf. The stock to match Is
of lawn-bound mesh, the ends being
brought around from the back and
tying in a small bow in front
Of course there Is a ping pong shirt
waist It is made In various stuffs,
but the smartest models seen thus far
are of pongee and of butcher's linen.
One of pongee Is in the popular Gib
son style except that it opens down the
front and has a cluster of three one
half inch vertical pleats on each side
of the centre band. The stock and
cravat are of pongee, but what gives
the waist its ping pongy touch Is the
design of crossed bats and balls em
broidered in scarlet on the cravat ends
and on the deep turned-back cuffs. The
symbolical designs embroidered In
black and white on a Gibson model of
green butcher's linen convert it into a
ping pong shirtwaist
Shops are showing ping pong suits,
and If you want to be strictly up-to-date
don't say "polka dot" say "ping
pong dot"
The ping pong craze has even Invad-
PURE
1 vC .
OUR ARTIFICIAL ICE IS
Absolutely Pure
Telephone Orders to 2125
LINCOLN ICE CO., 1040 0 St. I
Ganoungs
Pharmacy
1400 O Street . . . Open all Night
Lowbcj's and Allcgrctti's Gbocolates
HOT SODAS IN SEASON
Farmers & Merchants Bank
m
15th and O Streats.
LINCOLN, NEBRASKA.
Gao. W. Moktookxsy, Preat L. P. Fdnkhouskz, Cashier.
Capital Paid in, $60,000 OO
Accounts of Individuals, Firms, Corporations, Banks, and
Bankers Solicited. Correspondence invited. FOREIGN
EXCHANGE aad LETTERS OF CREDIT on all
the principal cities of Europe. Interest
paid on tine deposits.
COME IN AND GET A HOME SAVINGS BANK
Lincoln
) . . If you Want First Class Service Call on Us .
TV - -f ,7 WE DO WE 8ELL WE CARRY
X idilOiCi ( Piano and Fur- all grades of a fine line of Car-
niton Moving Coal
riages & Baggies
Co.
OFFICE, TENTH AND Q STS.
PHONE 176.
latest 15ooks
Hearts Courageous, by Hallie M. Rives, . . . . $1.20
The Story of Mary MacLane, 1.20
The Virginians, by Owen Wister, 1.20
Stephen Holton, by Charles Felton Pedgin 1.20
Tom Beauiing, by Governeur Morris 1.05
Red Anvil, by Sherlock 1.20
Graustark, by George Barr McCutcheon, 85
THE LINCOLN BOOK STORE, 1 126 O Street.
ed the furniture departments. There
are ping pong tables that can be con
verted Into dining or library tables at
a moment's notice of weathered, Flem
ish or polished golden oak In mission
style; folding tables are of hardwood
for ping pong, the legs and frame of
hardwood with painted and scored tops
made of board that will not warp from
dampness, and there are painted and
scored tops to place over any ordinary
table made of compo board, and ping
pong table covers of green oilcloth,
scored.
For ping pong parties and luncheons
are special table decorations In the way
of souvenirs, favors and other decora
tions which range frombon bon recep
tacles of cardboard In the form of the
bat with a small rubber ball fastened
to the Ud to a tiny box for sweets, the
cover of which when lifted forms a
table covered with green paper to rep
resent the field and ornamented with a
net and ball and racquet the full
fledged table represented in miniature.
Then there is a ping pong thirst
which goes with the game, and a new
punch called ping pong has sprung in
to popularity.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn97070123/1902-05-17/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>I'ln&T-ronc Id Chicago.
The ping pong craze has taken hold
of Chicago and the game Is drawing
Its devotees from all classes, especial
ly tho golf and tennis players. Of the
latter Kvarts Wrcnn Is the most con
spicuous character. Mr. Wrcnn Is a
champion at tennis, and yet he admits
that the parlor gamo has attractions
not surpassed by the older sport, and
that It requires Just as much science
and more accuracy. Ping pong Is slm-
ply Indoor tennis, with tho necessary i
modifications. It can bo played on the
dining room table and Is the gentlest
sort of exercise, requiring chiefly dex
terity and suppleness ot wrist.

The Craze for Ping Pong
Ping pong continues the craze in
England. Recently a big tournament
'.fas htAd in the town hall at Leeds
for tho benefit of the local war relief
fund. Twelve tables for the game wero
gathered In the largo room, which
was densely packed with spectators.
The fever, too, rages among the offi
cers ot the ' navy and the game' Is
played regularly in tho evenings after
dinner. The Junior midshipmen act
as caddies, and. with the pitching of
the ships the young men have lots ot
fun retrieving balls that bound from
the tablos.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88053046/1902-04-10/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE PING-PONG CRAZE.
Baltimore Heai'ld.
Ping-pong, tho latest and most
absorbing a
great deal of interest among tho smart
set, in Baltimore, in nearly every large
club or fashionable residence tho game
of ping-pong rules the hour formerly
occupied by the banquet and the ball.
Neither the first night of a great
actress nor the opera excites one-half
as much interest as a ping-çong match.
Ping-pong, which is simply lawn
tennis adapted to a table, is sometimes
called whiff-whaff. It was played by
the Japanese years ago and is still be
ing played by tht
ping-pong was ni
and w
noise made by tho ball striking tho
vellum racket. It has been played in
rly every country. Tho United
States seems to be one of tho last to
no affected by tho ping-pong craze.
Home time ago the g
pong was manufactured by Kamley
Bros., High llolborn, London, Eng.,
and in a short while all England was
Every club and private
London lmd a game and, in
who could not play ping
looked at askance. Last
tas taken up
the Uni tea
fashionable game, i
?m. In fact, the name
rat started i
•easioned by the peculiar
Jap
of ping
house ii
fact, a per
pong
it
by the finest
States,
society i
nearly all of the smart set,
tho gi
Ping-pong has also found its way
into hundreds of less pretentious homes.
It may be well just here thoroughly to
descriho the game for the benefit of
those who do
playing
it know exactly what
Ping pong i
game for young and
old people. It has proved tho most
successful indoor game ever gotten out,
because it gives
of physical exertion and is free from
; the irksomeness of some of the other
social games that compel one to eit
agreeable amount
still all the time.
The game is played just as lawn tenis
table, and it requires a
great deal of skill. Tho usual meusurc
9 feet by 5 feet
is, «inly on
ments of tho table t
and W foot by 4 feet, but just
fur. may ho had
table,
inchei
lion
smaller
larger
The height of the net is o%
. The remainder of the game
consists of posts to hold tho net when
stretched across the table : vellum,
string or wood rackets, and celluloid
balls. Ping-pong rules are the same as
lawn tennis, with the few following
except'
In ping-pong only
serving, whereas in tennis two balls
are used. The ball must be hit upon
the first bound in ping-pong, and may
not be hit upon the alternative of a
tennis, upon the second
fly, as in tennis.
Ping-pong is for two players, but
able to play.
the rules of the game,
which everybody should know thor
oughly before attempting to play a
match :
1. —The game is for t.
They shall s'and one at
the table. Tho player who first de
livers the ball shall tie called tho
server, and the other the striker out.
2. At the end of tho first game tho
striker-out shall become tho server,
and the server shall become the striker
out, and
3. The service shall be strictly un
derhand and delivered from beyond the
end of the table.
4. Th«* ball
where
and is then i
the net
striker-out. There i
bnll is used i
fly. as
bounce
a largo table four
Here
vo players,
each end of
alternately.
•rved must, drop any
the table top beyond tho net,
play. If it drops into
off the table it counts to the
soond service.
in lawn tennis.
5. In se
touch tho
(5. If tho ball i
object abo
it bounces
fing, it is a let if the ball
passing over.
play strikes any
around tho table before
tho table top itself (not
post excepted) it counts against tho
player.
7. Tho server
stroke if the
striker-out fails to return tho service,
return the service
off the table.
8. Tho striker-out wins a stroke if
fault, or fails to
turn the ball in play,
ball in play s
table.
ball in play
the
return tho
that it falls off the
9. No
lleying is allowed ; but as
long as the ball touches tho table top
it is in play, and can be taken at half
volley.
10. On either player winning his first
stroke the score is called 15 for that
either player winning his
•cond stroke the score is called 30
either player win
ning his third stroke tho score is called
40 for that player, and the f«»urth
strok
for that player;
i»y
it her player is Rcored
for that player except
11. If both pi aye
strokes (40 i
deuce, and the
either p
that plAyer.
the next stroke he wins the game; if
he loses the next stroke the score i
called dette;», and
below,
have won three
is called
ga:
all i the hi'*
ext stroke w
-layer is scored advantage to
play
by
, until
either player wins tho two strokes im
mediately following the score of deuces,
when the game is scored for that player,
12. The player who first wi
games wins a s«*t.
13. The g.
points, 20 up.
case, change
five points scor
There i
ay also lie scored by
». Tho players, in this
the service after every
•d.likn overs at cricket,
great deal of science about
Xpert player of the
place n ball within
aimed at.
d ;
ping-pong,
inch
Ho can knock
8«
of tho pi;
the ball sideways at any degree,
that it will bo out of his opponent's
reach. In fa-t, he can • hat with the
racket with as much precision and
much certainty as if he simply placed
the ball then» with his hands.
Among the expert players will be
found ping-pong tables covered with
green felt and marked like a tennis
court, but this is not at all necessary,
— ordinary dining table will answer
. On«* thing well to re
member is always to see that tho table
a little to the side of the
that it will not c<
under the chandelier.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86086481/1902-03-12/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING-PONG CRAZE
AMONG LYCEUM MEN
The members of St. Paul’s Lyceum
-ave the ping-pong craze, and two
teams selected from what are known
as the dav and night gangs have been
matched to plav a series of games for
the suppers. The two teams will ba
nicked from the following: Day gang,
Capt. Butler. Dolan. Carroll, Lapham
and Jennings: Night gang. Cant. Ry
an. McCourty, Fitzpatrick, Mulvey and
Mullaney. Henry M. Shaughnessy haa
presented to the society a loving cup
to be contested for by the individual
embers in ping-pong games.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026355/1902-06-12/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84022060/1902-05-22/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1903-02-15/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE SUNDAY CALL.
Copyright. 19C2. by D. T. Pierce.
_ - T/THOTTftK of late
"TSo33c-{!3cl wf have heard very
t££)v VV^S little of ping-pong-.
wtfS it must not b" sup
' posed that the game
c* £?*Pt» *^ * s ca^ : naturally.
>-5?5*^?£^rJg during the summer
mmm^ t^ m^^ _ month?, its place
*7 has been largely
taken by cricket, lawn tennis and other
essentially outdoor sports— at the same
time we could speak of numerous spots
where ping-pong has been the means of
passing enjoyably many an otherwise
weary hour during wet summer days. V.'e
have seen many a game played on the.
awjilnged upper decks of up-river house
boats, and no doubt a large number of
seaside boarding-houses and hotels could
testify to its usefulness in engaging the
attentions of otherwise discontented visit
ors. It is now quite an exception to en
ter a hotel or boarding-house that has
not got its ping-pong room and table, and
vis-its to Continental cities disclose the
fact that the game has considerably*
"caught on" on the Continent. We our
selves saw a full-sized match ping-pong
table in the Kurhaus at Homburg; in
Stockholm the game is much played by
the Swedish aristocracy and good so-'
clely; and in Paris and other parts of the
Continent .some most successful tourna
ments have been held.
A short account of the wonderful way
in which ping-pong and table tennis have
caught on to the public taste may not be
out of place here. The game appears to
have originated in about 1890, but with
book covers In place of racquets, and a
cork ball in place of the celluloid article
now in use; the writer has had the pleas
ure of talking with one of the gentlemen
who played the game under these condi
tions. Improvements .were 6f course very
soon made, but the great difficulty was to
get a ball light enough (rubber balls were
most used), and, with wooden racquets,
a sort of progenitor of the present game
was installed. R. S. Jones, an old Cam
bridge blue, and captain of St. John's
College, Cambridge, and Leslie Jones
were among the'first to play the game at
all seriously, but It became quite lost
Bight of until 1900. Then the Nondescript
cricket team 'on tour experienced a con
tinuously wet season, and in order to
pass the time one of the team introduced
some battledores, a net was rigged up
across the table, a ball of some light de
scription obtained and the game found
such favor among the players as an in
door pastime that on returning to town
a club was formed "to play it. This was
the nucleus of the Cavendish Table Ten
nis Club, which may be looked upon as
the forerunner of the table tennis clubs
now so popular all over the country.
Their headquarters Were at Armfield's
Hotel, In Finsbury.' Following their In
corporation several other goud clubs were
?.istituted and club matches arranged.
The more the game was prayed, so did
It increase in popularity by leaps and
bounds. The next Important incident was
a public tournament held at Chlswlck,
which attracted a large number of play
ers and still more spectators, anxious to
see what the new game was. Following
this the first really well-known tourna
ment took place in the galleries of the
Royal Aquarium, and the excitement it
created and the enormous crowds who
vislted.it are facts- too well known now to
need recapitulation.
Ping pong in England is now far more
cosmopolitan than it was some months
ago. but such a result Is to be advocated,
not deplored. A^ter a record season of
popularity such as the game has enjoyed
a calm must be expected,. but there are
not wanting signs to show that it will be
played more than ever in the forthcoming
winter. Ping pong 'will be more popular
than ever for one reason, because a rec
ognized set of rules has now been formu
lated by the Table Tennis and Ping Pong
Associations, these associations being
composed to a great extent of some of the
best players, and tho>e who have been
conversant with the game from Its con
ception. We have heard some people say
that so soon as hard and fast rules are
made for such a game as ping pong then
its attractiveness and fun for the family
circle at once diminishes and consequent
ly Its days are numbered— but such a line
of reasoning is not justified. . A game, to
adds very much to the Interest of the
game from the onlooker's point of view,
and as the game progresses it is probable
that further innovations will take place.
We shall hope to see volleying Introduced
very shortly and there are other varia
tions on the tapis. We have seen one
ping pong table fitted with a sort of arti
ficial bunker, this being invented with
the Idea of stopping the interminable ral
lies: should the ball bounce on the bunker
it would generally count to the maker of
the stroke, the ball usually bouncing off
right at a tangent: to get the ball on the
bunker, however, would, of course, ne
cessitate a good shot. Another idea is
that of fixing up a sort of wall round op
posite sides of the table, and making it
into a kind of miniature real tennis court.
It is probable that these suggestions will
not be acted on to any great extent, but
they serve to show that the game is
quite capable of developments in othi-r
ways besides strokes. A considerable
amount of amusement may be caused by
experimenting in different directions
when the orthodox game becomes a little
tiresome.
In conclusion, there will be so many
public ping pong tournaments this forth
coming season that all classes In all parts
will have an opportunity of competing for
prizes. The experience gained by the
original promoters of ping pong tourna
ments has been handed down, and com
petitors cah generally be certain that
everything conducive to good play ami
sportsmanship will be catered for. There
is probably nothing that helps the game
along and makes It more popular than a
well conducted tournament, so we shall
be glad to see plenty of them all over
England.
ponehts on ediual terms, for strength of
arm and body are of small account in
ping pong. We are not all of us great
athletes, sighing for" cricket, tennis and
football fields to conquer, and ping pong
seems to give us Just the right amount
of exercise to be beneficial— that is to say
when the game is not played too ener
getically. For those who want something
severe let them play the best of three
sets at ping pong against a really good
player and they will get probably all the
severity they want. One frequently sees
at ping pong tournaments the competitors
in flannels, and even then sweating from
every pore, and after a long and severe
match there is no doubt the game be
comes somewhat of a strain on wrist and
eye. It is a fact that shortly after the
ping pong craze took its hold on the pub
lic the players got into a rut of safety
play, most of the best exponents making
safety their aim without any brilliancy In
strokes. This was made a great point of
by detractors, who Averred that such
monotony in the play would kill it— it was
In fact not uncommon for "stonewaliera"
to have rallies of several hundred con
secutive strokes.
Ping pong enthusiasts may congratulate
themselves that the style of play has now
altogether altered. At the conclusion of
last season the best players were putting
on an amount of spin and varying their
strokes to an extent that would have
be,en considered almost Impossible earlier
in the history of the game; probably the
introducatlon of corrugated rubber bats
has had a good deal to do with this, but
there is little doubt that the brilliancy of
the strokes as now played by the cracks
become popular and remain so. must offer
(unlimited scope for the exercise of skill
so that the tyro, by assiduously practic
ing, may continually better himself, and
thus hope to arrive eventually at cham
pionship form. Now it must be admitted
that ping pong is a seductive game which
grows on one the more it Is played, and in
which undoubtedly practice begets skill;
although productive of a tremendous
amount of fun and vigor In the drawing
room after dinner when not played too
seriously, no sooner docs the player begin
to appreciate the possibilities of the game
that It becomes his ambition to Improve.
The establishment of a set of rules to
be universally observed both In tourna
ment and practice play j is an" important
factor in the increased devotion of the
players* time and energy to the game.
j Ping pong in its readvent under these
favorable circumstances will present at
tractions not possessed by any other In
door game, billiards not excepted. In the
first place the Implements are now to be
obtained anywhere In England, and at
prices to suit every purchaser; tables,
bats, balls and nets are now made in
regulation sizes and great Improvements
have been effected m the manufacture of
'all the articles; also installing and play
ing the game is effected with little altera
tion of existing arrangements, and no spe
cial room is required as^t billiards. The
game is played as well by ga3 or lamp
light, and to crown all it is a game In
which ladles can meet gentlemen ?p-</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064676/1902-05-19/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>In the past few days persons walk
ing through the quiet up-town streets
have remarked about the number of:
houses through whose open windows,
came the staccato "ping! pong!" of the
xylonite "table tennis" bal. ' Accord
ing to the stories which are told by
dealers in sporting goods, thousands'
of sets of this game have been sold to
families in the city, and the demand
appears to be increasing. One fac
tory at Chicopee Falls alone is turn
ing out 1000 sets daily, and is far be
hind its orders. Ping-pong outfits are
going in numbers now to suburban
golf clubs. It shows what a hold the
sport has taken on its devotees that
even the golfing enthusiast must take
his ping-pong to the links with him.
"Our greatest demand for complete
sets, including the regulation tables,
has, of course, come from the clubs,"
said a dealer yesterday. "But the
women and children have got the
fever as bad as their brothers and
fathers. If you're writing about the
ping-pong craze you can't make it too
strong. So far as I know we haven't
sold a set to any old ladies' home yet,
but I dare say the game will reach
them in time. This craze beats any
thing I ever heard of. Our belief is
that it's only beginning. Hot weather
may affect our sales -somewhat but
we look for an increased demand next
fail.
"Our indoor putting green in the
back of the store has been occupied by
a ping-pong table for several weeks.
Lots of people who never saw the
game come in here and watch a few
sets, get fascinated by the play and
end by buying racquets and balls and
a net to take home and set up on their
dining-room or billiard table. There's
a game going on here almost every
hour of the day. People can't seem to
get enough of it."
The clubs have been and are still
the stronghold of the craze, although
the newspapers have had more to say
about the play in brokers' offices and
on ocean steamers. So sudden has been
the passion for the sport, and so much
room does a regulation table take up
that most of the clubs have had to
give up some other sport, in whole or
in part, for a time, or else sacrifice
part of their dining-room space. No
body seems to object, however. Even
the most sedate of club loungers, al
though he may begin by scoffing at
the "child's play," ends in becoming
either an enthusiast or a disappointed
but persistent "duffer."
College clubs or other clubs fre
quented by younger men are the worst
sufferers from the ping-pong malady.
The Harvard Club, early in the winter.
put up the little nets on its billiard
tables, and billiards have scarcely
been played there since. Members
pay the same amount per hour for
playing ping-pong that they formerly
were charged for the use of the bil
liard tables. The club has since set up,
In addition, a real ping-pong board.
The Yale Club has four tables in one
of the class dining-rooms on the ninth
floor. The Cornell University Club
gives up half its dining-room to the
pastime, and the House Committee
now talks of letting the whole apart
ment be used for it, so many of the
members want to play; and ping-pong
tables can be used as dining tables, if
it takes too long to make the change.
In a Brooklyn athletic club the ping
pongers have invaded the handball
court. Most of these resorts have had
or are having ping-poug tournaments.
and clever players have been devel
oped in the course of a few weeks.
Boarding-houses in all parts of town
have been hard hit by the craze. The
long table in the back parlor makes a
good ping-pong board, and the young
man in the hall bed-room two flights
up takes delight in making the star
Iloarder look like thirty cents. The
landladies are( noi enthusiastic o\ver
the game. ih'[eeue vl'when played in the
evelling it litas :1 tLnuden-y to develop
a rolust i appe ,titel for int' suppers.
Th' ver naular of the splort has not
yet reached a high 'degree of develop
llelu. For tilthe present'I , as is thle ctse
with lally inew\ llnel. lallyers i]akee free
w\it'h woldtilis Ia I hI'tIll ise llroleor to
ither b)rt ch(; ot" 4orl. lxprtssion.s
"''hiii cl'11 is ititntll." "O') side" are
heard aroundl th lit iltard. Piecturestlue
Itlniguage ot" a dliflren'ollI il'lrt'cter' is
also coulon.I. 'ITh'te elusive ctelluloid
spiliere is aIs (Olldu(l(i'-ti 1o I)profaniity as
the gutta perlha. A well known lawn
tennis player has a noveclty ill the way
of ping-pong profanity. When he
makes a fault he shouts "Fudge!" or
"Goodness gracious!" He explains that
he learned. the game by playing with
his sisters, and it Isn't worth cussin'
about anyway.-New York Sun.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016014/1902-07-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING PONG CRAZE.
The Came Is Now in Full Blast in
Topeka.
Ping pong has reached that stage in
Topeka that people are following the
hints of the funny papers and are eat
ing off pianos and anything else so as
not to disturb the dining room tables.
One family has the dining room table
extended for ping pong, the net in
place constantly and so as not to dis
turb the table they eat off the kitchen
table. Another family has a little bet
ter scheme and uses one end of the
long table without having to take down
the net. Other families have the ping
pong tables on the porches. One man is
mad because he found a ping pong ball
in the pudding and still another is fur
ious because he can not read. His eyes
are out of true because he tried to
watch the antics of a ping pong ball.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
